
import { Quiz, Question } from '../types';

const processQuestions = (questions: any[]): Question[] => {
  return questions.map(q => {
    const newQ: Question = { ...q };
    // If flags are already explicitly set, respect them and continue
    if (newQ.isMatching === true || newQ.isMultipleChoice === true) {
        return newQ;
    }

    // Otherwise, infer from the answer type
    if (Array.isArray(newQ.answer)) {
      newQ.isMultipleChoice = true;
    } else if (typeof newQ.answer === 'object' && newQ.answer !== null && !Array.isArray(newQ.answer)) {
      if(Object.keys(newQ.answer).length > 0) {
        newQ.isMatching = true;
      }
    }
    return newQ;
  });
};

const mock1Data = [
    { "question": "M1Q1 A company is implementing agile methods. After a few sprints, communication problems develop. Some project team members are not getting along with others and this has led to the project being delayed by more than three weeks? What would have caused this issue?", "options": ["The PM plan is outdated", "Daily standup meeting is not being held", "The project sprint backlog has not been updated", "The project performance reports are not being created"], "answer": "Daily standup meeting is not being held", "explanation": "Daily standup meetings will ensure all team members are aligned and understand the purpose of the project. It will also allow them to communicate any issues they face on a day-to-day basis." },
    { "question": "M1Q2 A Project Manager realizes a major stakeholder's expectations are NOT being met, specifically regarding the project's budget. This may also cause a delay to the project. To resolve this issue, what should the project manager do?", "options": ["Update the risk register.", "Update the communications management plan.", "Update the scope baseline.", "Update the stakeholder engagement plan."], "answer": "Update the risk register.", "explanation": "The risk register will contain risks that may affect the project. The best resolution here would be to add this risk to the risk register with the corresponding response." },
    { "question": "M1Q3 A team is working on a hybrid software development project. Stakeholder's understandings of the project requirements are not aligned to the expectations from the team. What steps should the project manager have taken to prevent this?", "options": ["Have the team meet with the customers to help develop the scope statement", "Alter the project scope to meet the requirements", "Have the team conduct a sprint review meeting with the customers", "Update the scope statement"], "answer": "Have the team conduct a sprint review meeting with the customers", "explanation": "By allowing the team and customers to conduct a sprint review meeting, it will allow the customers to give feedback on the development of the deliverable." },
    { "question": "M1Q4 A senior manager would like to add a few new features to the project deliverables. Before a project team member starts working on these new features, what should be done first?", "options": ["Gain approval from the Project Manager.", "Ensure the change control board (CCB) approves.", "Gain approval from the senior manager.", "Ensure key subject matter experts (SMEs) approve."], "answer": "Ensure the change control board (CCB) approves.", "explanation": "The Change control board is responsible for reviewing, evaluating, approving, or rejecting changes to the project." },
    { "question": "M1Q5 The project team is starting a new phase of a project. Based on the previous phase, they have compiled a list of issues that were solved. What should the project manager do with this list in the new phase?", "options": ["Have the team add the appropriate reserves to the new project plan", "Add all the issues as a risk in this phase", "Update the risk management plan with the list of issues", "Update the organization process assets"], "answer": "Update the organization process assets", "explanation": "Once a phase or project is done, the PM should update the OPA's with the organization so it can be used by other projects or phases in that project." },
    { "question": "M1Q6 A project is at the planning stage of the project. The Project Manager realizes that producing complex CRM software is not feasible with the current number of resources and hire more resources for code development. The Project Manager identifies and contracts temporary resources. Which risk response strategy does this scenario demonstrate?", "options": ["Mitigate", "Transfer", "Accept", "Avoid"], "answer": "Avoid", "explanation": "The risk to the project was posed by insufficient resources. The risk was Avoided by hiring additional resources." },
    { "question": "M1Q7 An agile team with members from different countries is having difficulties resolving issues. This has led to the project falling behind schedule. What should the project manager do to resolve this?", "options": ["Meet with the product owner and inform him of these issues and slow down", "Implement new methods to ensure the team has better communication methods and technologies.", "Remove the members who are causing the issues", "Speak with the HR department about what can be done with this issue"], "answer": "Implement new methods to ensure the team has better communication methods and technologies.", "explanation": "The action to take here would be to ensure that all team members have the technology to ensure communications are being done correctly. Poor communications generally lead to conflict." },
    { "question": "M1Q8 Project Manager has completed the following steps: -Finished a major software project. -Confirmed with the release manager that all the software works. -Confirmed that functionality has been verified by the quality assurance team. -Gained formal acceptance from the sponsor. What is the next step the Project Manager should take?", "options": ["Update the risk register.", "Conduct the lessons learned with the team.", "Ensure that the procurement management plan is complete.", "Review the closing management plan."], "answer": "Conduct the lessons learned with the team.", "explanation": "During project close out, lessons learned should be done with the team." },
    { "question": "M1Q9 A project manager is reviewing a deliverable that is 80% completed and has presented it to a key stakeholder. The stakeholder is not happy with the way the project manager is showing the deliverable and says he really doesn't understand it's purpose. What tool or technique should the project manager use?", "options": ["Bottom-up estimating", "Prototyping", "Decision making", "Expert judgment"], "answer": "Prototyping", "explanation": "One of the best ways to show stakeholders a product is to use a prototype. This will allow for more interaction with the stakeholder and gain feedback." },
    { "question": "M1Q10 A project manager and a new agile team have started a new project. The PM notices members are not doing agile meetings. Team members often don't hold standup meetings or sprint review meetings. How should the project manager handle this situation?", "options": ["Conduct the standup meeting yourself on a daily basis", "Inform the team it is okay to hold meetings as necessary", "Meet with the product owner to remove team members who don't value agile methods", "Work with the team and explain the benefits of these meetings"], "answer": "Work with the team and explain the benefits of these meetings", "explanation": "On a project, it is important for the project manager to educate the team on the benefits of using agile processes. The more the team understands the benefits, the more likely they will follow the processes." },
    { "question": "M1Q11 After realizing that there are insufficient resources for a hybrid project, the PMO outsources some development tasks to keep the project on schedule. What should the Project Manager do first in this situation?", "options": ["Review the RACI chart.", "Review the Communication management plan.", "Revise the procurement management plan.", "Meet with the project sponsor."], "answer": "Revise the procurement management plan.", "explanation": "The Procurement Management Plan is the project procurement decisions, specifying the approach and identifying potential sellers is captured." },
    { "question": "M1Q12 The project manager is hesitant to work with a new customer on a hybrid project. Previously the project manager had a very difficult time getting sign-offs and approvals from this particular customer. The sponsor has initiated the project and the customer is ready to start planning the project. How should the project manager handle the situation?", "options": ["Ask the client if they have a dedicated resource to complete sign-offs", "Meet with the client and review the project ground rules", "Add a risk to the risk management plan about potential delays", "Inform the client, it is not acceptable to delay sign-offs"], "answer": "Meet with the client and review the project ground rules", "explanation": "In this situation, it would be best to meet with the client and informed them of the project ground rules and how you would like documents to be signed off." },
    { "question": "M1Q13 A project has the following need: -300 resource hours must be outsourced. -All sellers must be given the same information about the requirements. Which should the Project Manager do to ensure to meet these requirements?", "options": ["Send the procurement management plan to each provider.", "Conduct a bidder conference.", "Add the provider to the stakeholder register.", "Meet and negotiate with each provider."], "answer": "Conduct a bidder conference.", "explanation": "A bidder conference is a meeting between the buyer and sellers. It is used when you want to give out similar information to all sellers. This way, no seller has more info than another." },
    { "question": "M1Q14 Team members are having a major issue with the method to develop a software module on a hybrid project. One member claims method A is better than method B. This issue could delay the project by over two weeks. What should the project manager do to resolve this issue?", "options": ["Ask a third team member to select one of the methods", "Tell the two members to resolve the issue right away and move on", "Select one method for them to resolve the issue immediately", "Have team members meet in a face-to-face meeting and facilitate which method would be best."], "answer": "Have team members meet in a face-to-face meeting and facilitate which method would be best.", "explanation": "In this scenario, it would be best to have the two team members meet in a face-to-face meeting and for you to facilitate this meeting to come up with a consensus." },
    { "question": "M1Q15 A company has a goal of releasing a new product to increase market share within five months. A project is initiated to meet this goal. The Project Manager needs to understand how customers will use the product once it is made available to the public. What should the Project Manager utilize to accomplish this?", "options": ["Focus groups", "Affinity diagram", "Benchmarking", "Facilitation"], "answer": "Focus groups", "explanation": "Focus Groups should be used to gather feedback from actual customers. This ensures that any decisions are made off of real data rather than assumptions." },
    { "question": "M1Q16 After the project management plan had been approved, a major stakeholder informed the project manager that the project management plan would not be sufficient for the completion of the project deliverables. The stakeholder is not willing to cooperate and meet with the project manager. What should a project manager do first?", "options": ["Meet with the project sponsor and ask for guidance", "Proceed with the project as planned since the stakeholder is not willing to meet with you.", "Review the project management plan", "Meet with the project management office and ask them to speak with the stakeholder"], "answer": "Review the project management plan", "explanation": "Since this is a conflict on the project, the project manager should review the communications management and stakeholder engagement plan to see how to resolve stakeholder issues on a project." },
    { "question": "M1Q17 A new product is released. When a customer identifies performance issues with this product, the Project Manager realizes the wrong tool was used to collect the customer requirements. Which tool should the Project Manager have used?", "options": ["Benchmarks.", "Cost-benefit analysis.", "Appraisal costs.", "Cost of quality."], "answer": "Benchmarks.", "explanation": "Benchmarks are used to assess a product against industry standards." },
    { "question": "M1Q18 Team members working on a software development project are questioning whether they could meet the deadlines for the project. Their concern is that the project will not be able to complete on time. The team members feel that their concerns are not being taken seriously on the project. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Inform them that deadlines are to be taken seriously and they must be met", "Inform them to submit their concerns to the project sponsor", "Meet with the project management office to understand why the team members would feel this way", "Meet with the project team and listen to their concerns and assure them that they will be taken seriously"], "answer": "Meet with the project team and listen to their concerns and assure them that they will be taken seriously", "explanation": "In this scenario, it would be best to meet with the team and assure them that their concerns will be heard and taken seriously." },
    { "question": "M1Q19 A Project Manager is doing the following: -conducting a cost analysis based on a high-level scope -using expert judgment to make a document. What is the Project Manager doing, based on the description above?", "options": ["Create a project management plan", "Developing a scope statement", "Create a risk management plan", "Create a project charter"], "answer": "Create a project charter", "explanation": "The project charter is a high-level document with a high-level scope and budget." },
    { "question": "M1Q20 A recently executed project has team members that are growing frustrated with each other. This is due to the lack of expectations between team members. This is beginning to affect the entire team and may cause delays to the project. What document should the project manager review to address this issue?", "options": ["Communications management plan", "Team charter", "Stakeholder Engagement plan", "Project charter"], "answer": "Team charter", "explanation": "The best course of action here would be to review the team charter. The team charter will outline expected behaviors and project expectations." },
    { "question": "M1Q21 A project has been executed with an approved plan. A team member says the project might fail to meet the requirement. Correcting the issue may cause an increase in scope and costs. What should the Project Manager do?", "options": ["Contact the customer and negotiate for risk acceptance.", "Resolve the issue to satisfy the customer.", "Implement a change request.", "Conduct a risk analysis."], "answer": "Conduct a risk analysis.", "explanation": "The Risk Register is there for the project team to understand potential problems with the project. It is necessary to first perform a full risk analysis and update the project sponsor before making any decisions." },
    { "question": "M1Q22 The project manager is working with the sponsor to gain acceptance of the project scope. During this process, the project manager realizes that some of the project work was not included in the original project scope. This work will be essential to getting the project accepted by the sponsor. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Implement a change requests to include the additional work to the scope", "Update the risk register with these new potential risks", "Complete the scope validation and inform operations about the issue", "Inform the project sponsor of the issue and ask for guidance"], "answer": "Implement a change requests to include the additional work to the scope", "explanation": "The best course of action would be to implement the change requests to add the additional work. This will ensure that the scope is accepted when the project is done." },
    { "question": "M1Q23 A Project Manager decides to utilize a stakeholder engagement assessment matrix. The matrix identifies an influential stakeholder who is resistant to the project. The Project Manager needs to have this person be active on the project. What should the Project Manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Create the stakeholder engagement plan.", "Ensure that the stakeholder register is completely updated.", "Meet with the sponsor.", "Create the communications management plan."], "answer": "Create the stakeholder engagement plan.", "explanation": "Plan Stakeholder Engagement is the process of creating an approach to involve project stakeholders based on their needs. It is a plan to interact effectively with stakeholders." },
    { "question": "M1Q24 A key stakeholder on an agile project wants the functionality of the product to be delivered immediately within the next three months as one iteration. The project team has informed the project manager that it will take five iterations for a total of seven months. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Meet with the key stakeholder to understand why he wants it done in three months and educate him on the benefits of incremental delivery", "Speak with the product owner about this issue", "Schedule a meeting with the stakeholder and inform him this cannot be done", "Meet with the project team informed to inform them they will need to complete the work as one iteration and three months"], "answer": "Meet with the key stakeholder to understand why he wants it done in three months and educate him on the benefits of incremental delivery", "explanation": "In this situation it would be best to meet with key stakeholders to understand why he wants this and didn't educate them on the benefits of incremental delivery." },
    { "question": "M1Q25 An organization is creating a new product. However, the company has never made a product like this before. The Project Manager needs to collect requirements. Which two tools or techniques should the Project Manager use? (Choose 2)", "options": ["Decomposition", "Prototypes.", "Expert judgment.", "Product analysis.", "Create requirements traceability matrix."], "answer": ["Prototypes.", "Expert judgment."], "explanation": "Experts and Prototypes are tools used in collect requirements.", "isMultipleChoice": true },
    { "question": "M1Q26 During an iteration, a team member informs the project manager that the consultant has left the project and does not want to return. The team is having a difficult time negotiating with this consultant to return. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Meet with the consultant and negotiate with him yourself", "Work with the team to negotiate with the consultant", "Determine how this risk can affect the entire project", "Request that the team find a new consultant"], "answer": "Work with the team to negotiate with the consultant", "explanation": "It would be best to work with the team to negotiate with the consultant than to do-it-yourself. You should have an input in the negotiations with the consultant." },
    { "question": "M1Q27 A Project Manager working on a hybrid virtual project is dealing with a scheduling priority conflict among team members. He schedules a video conference call to resolve it. Which statement is true about this scenario?", "options": ["It is an example of Force/Direct conflict resolution technique.", "It is an example of Compromise/Reconcile conflict resolution technique.", "It is an example of Smooth/Accommodate conflict resolution technique.", "It is an example of the Collaborate/Problem Solve conflict resolution technique."], "answer": "It is an example of the Collaborate/Problem Solve conflict resolution technique.", "explanation": "Collaborate/problem solving requires a supportive attitude and open dialogue that typically leads to agreement and assurance. This method can result in a win-win situation." },
    { "question": "M1Q28 The project manager has just learned that a stakeholder is very upset that he was not included as one of the original stakeholders on the project. He has given the project manager a few requirements that he wants to be added to the scope. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Review the scope management plan", "Update the stakeholder engagement plan", "Implement a change request to add additional changes", "Arrange to meet with the stakeholder to understand his requirements for the project"], "answer": "Arrange to meet with the stakeholder to understand his requirements for the project", "explanation": "It is always best to meet with stakeholders individually to understand what your issues are the best ways to go around fixing them. This should be the first thing that should be done." },
    { "question": "M1Q29 A functional manager in an organization would like to use a senior team member for a new project. Which should the Project Manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Contact the portfolio manager to resolve the issue.", "Deny the request", "Meet with the functional manager to understand how this issue can be resolved or escalated.", "Request that the functional manager replace your resource."], "answer": "Meet with the functional manager to understand how this issue can be resolved or escalated.", "explanation": "The PM should first understand how this can be resolve. If getting to an agreement is not possible, the issue needs to be escalated for resolution." },
    { "question": "M1Q30 The project manager has begun working on a software development project. The team has met a few of the customers and has decided to revise the way they will develop the software. They have decided this after the project management plan has been approved and the project is about to be executed. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Implement the new methods immediately", "Implement a change request", "Inform the sponsor of this problem and implement the changes", "Inform the team, they might be wrong and execute the project as planned"], "answer": "Implement a change request", "explanation": "Any changes to the project management plan require change requests to be approved by the change control Board. The next step here would be to have the project manager implemented change requests." },
    { "question": "M1Q31 A new hybrid project has been executed. The Project Manager notices a stakeholder believes the project's deliverables are not achievable. Which should the Project Manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Assess the project charter thoroughly with this stakeholder on a conference call.", "Ensure that the stakeholder understands the risk management plan.", "Assess the project scope while analyzing the stakeholder's needs and expectations.", "Perform a risk analysis."], "answer": "Assess the project scope while analyzing the stakeholder's needs and expectations.", "explanation": "It is important to understand the needs of stakeholders and why they feel this way. Then take actions to ensure requirements are met." },
    { "question": "M1Q32 A project manager working on an agile project has just been informed by a vendor that a few components to the project will be shipped late. This is due to flooding in their factories. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Implement a change request to extend the project schedule", "Call for meeting with the project sponsor to inform him of this development", "Replace the vendor with a new vendor", "Add this to the issue log and meet with the project team to brainstorm solutions"], "answer": "Add this to the issue log and meet with the project team to brainstorm solutions", "explanation": "In this situation, the project manager should meet with the team to determine if there are any other solutions to this problem. He should also add this to the issue log as this will affect the project." },
    { "question": "M1Q33 A customer asks the Project Manager for a new product feature during a meeting. What document should the Project Manager refer to find out who has the authority to approve this request?", "options": ["Change log.", "Scope management plan.", "Change request.", "Change management plan"], "answer": "Change management plan", "explanation": "The change management plan describes the process for submitting, evaluating and implementing changes to the project." },
    { "question": "M1Q34 A project team member has modified the project scope without any approval. This could lead to a delay on the project. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Remove the team member from the project", "Update the project management plan", "Remove the change right away", "Evaluate the impact of the change on the entire project"], "answer": "Evaluate the impact of the change on the entire project", "explanation": "Once a scope change is made, the project manager should immediately assess how this will affect other parts of the project." },
    { "question": "M1Q35 Review the following steps: 1. The Project Manager has obtained stakeholder acceptance. 2. Complete the lesson learned. 3. What is Step 3?", "options": ["The Project Manager should release the project team.", "The Project Manager should reallocate the unused funds.", "The Project Manager should file the project report.", "The Project Manager should conduct quality assurance."], "answer": "The Project Manager should release the project team.", "explanation": "Once the stakeholder's acceptance is done and the lesson learned is finished, it is time to release or reassign the team." },
    { "question": "M1Q36 A project manager has just been assign to a new project and the PMO has given him a list of all the stakeholders on the project along with their potential roles, their level of interest and their expectations on the project. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Risk analysis", "Stakeholder matrix", "Stakeholder register", "Stakeholder analysis"], "answer": "Stakeholder analysis", "explanation": "Once this information is given to the project manager, he should then conduct a full stakeholder analysis that will then produce the stakeholder register." },
    { "question": "M1Q37 Review the following project characteristics: -The project is executed. -Due to recent regulation, the project gets terminated. -The Project Manager must close the project. What is the first action the Project Manager should take?", "options": ["Follow communications management plan to properly inform all stakeholders.", "Close all project procurement processes.", "Assess how this will impact the team.", "Follow the organization's project closure guidelines."], "answer": "Follow the organization's project closure guidelines.", "explanation": "Project closure guidelines or requirements will contain the organization's procedures to follow." },
    { "question": "M1Q38 A project manager has just been assigned to a new project. Due to a significant natural disaster, this has caused a major schedule issue and has delayed the project. This might affect the budget and scope. What should the project manager do? (choose 2)", "options": ["Calculate the SPI and SV on the schedule", "Implement a crashing method on the schedule", "Increase the schedule due to a natural disaster", "Use a schedule compression technique to shorten the schedule", "Review the budget with the PMO and ask for guidance", "Implement a Fast-tracking method on the schedule"], "answer": ["Use a schedule compression technique to shorten the schedule", "Implement a Fast-tracking method on the schedule"], "explanation": "This question is asking about the schedule. This means the PM should try to reduce the schedule by using schedule compression techniques such as fast-tracking.", "isMultipleChoice": true },
    { "question": "M1Q39 A project has a new stakeholder who is not attending meetings during initiating. The stakeholder will have a large impact on the overall project in the future. The Project Manager needs to engage this new stakeholder. What should the Project Manager do?", "options": ["Ask the new stakeholder to meet with a more experienced stakeholder to learn their responsibilities.", "Examine the project charter with the new stakeholder and assess their level of engagement.", "Review the project schedule with the new stakeholder.", "Request that the sponsor speaks with this new stakeholder and ask that they send them to all meetings."], "answer": "Examine the project charter with the new stakeholder and assess their level of engagement.", "explanation": "The best option here would be to meet with the stakeholder and assess their interest and what their level of engagement should be." },
    { "question": "M1Q40 A new hybrid project has started. The project sponsor asks the project manager how deliverables will be verified for accuracy. In which project document is this information found?", "options": ["Requirements management plan.", "Risk Management plan.", "Quality management plan.", "Scope Statement."], "answer": "Quality management plan.", "explanation": "The quality management plan identifies the quality requirements and/or standards for the project and its deliverables and documents how the project will demonstrate compliance with quality requirements and or standards." },
    { "question": "M1Q41 A vendor has missed a major component of a deliverable. After having a one-on-one meeting with the vendor, the project manager understands the issue. This has caused the critical path to increase by more than two weeks. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Update the lesson learn register with this new lesson", "Implement a change request to extend the project schedule", "Review the risk register and implement the risk response", "Terminate the vendor from the project"], "answer": "Review the risk register and implement the risk response", "explanation": "Since this risk has materialized, the next step would be to implement the response." },
    { "question": "M1Q42 A project is being planned in an area with limited access to vehicles. The Project Manager proposes that the company deliver equipment themselves. The Project Manager will take full responsibility if vehicles cannot get to the project site. What risk response is the Project Manager using?", "options": ["Transfer", "Mitigate", "Accept", "Avoid"], "answer": "Accept", "explanation": "Risk acceptance is a risk response strategy whereby the project team decides to acknowledge this low risk and not take any action unless the risk occurs." },
    { "question": "M1Q43 The agile team has completed two sprints so far. The team is about to conduct the sprint planning meeting for the 3rd sprint. What should the project manager bring?", "options": ["Agile charter", "Burndown chart", "Sprint goal", "Burnup Chart"], "answer": "Sprint goal", "explanation": "Sprint goals are clear objectives set before the beginning of a sprint. They are set by the product owner and delivery team collaboratively." },
    { "question": "M1Q44 A project manager begins to make the project management plan after the project charter. There is currently no historical information from the project management office (PMO). What is the next step the Project Manager should take in this situation?", "options": ["Use expert judgment", "Meet with the sponsor to seek advice", "Inform the PMO and have them plan it.", "Stop planning the project"], "answer": "Use expert judgment", "explanation": "If no historical information is available, then the use of expert judgment is needed to plan the project." },
    { "question": "M1Q45 During a network implementation project, a key stakeholder has requested for the project to be completed four weeks early. The vendor doing the work has requested a cost increase on the contract. What should the project manager do first?", "options": ["Update the project management with the new shorter end date", "Review how this shorter duration would impact other parts of the project", "Meet with the sponsor and request a budget", "Submit a change request to the change control board"], "answer": "Review how this shorter duration would impact other parts of the project", "explanation": "Before a change can be made to a project, the PM should assess how this would impact all aspects of the project." },
    { "question": "M1Q46 A development team is creating a new website. The team needs to identify what are the visual requirement for the site. What is an appropriate tool or technique to use for this situation?", "options": ["Value Analysis", "Decomposition", "Benchmarking", "Focus groups"], "answer": "Focus groups", "explanation": "Focus groups organize stakeholders and subject matter experts to learn about their expectations and attitudes about a product." },
    { "question": "M1Q47 An organization is moving from traditional to agile methods. The team is having difficulties assigning work to the members. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Review the resource management plan", "Assign work to each member based on their skill set", "Educate the team on agile methods and have then assign work to each other", "Hire an outside consultant to assign work to each member"], "answer": "Educate the team on agile methods and have then assign work to each other", "explanation": "One of the core concepts of agile is a self-organizing team. It would be best to have the project guide the team and have determined how work is assigned to team members." },
    { "question": "M1Q48 A client brings a project manager onto a project during the project's execution stage. The project manager reviews the project scope for cost estimating purposes and notices that some deliverables were missed in the work breakdown structure (WBS). Which step should the project manager take next?", "options": ["Ask that the project management office (PMO) approve additional funds for this work.", "Include the work in the WBS and recalculate the total project cost.", "Verify with the stakeholders to see if these missed deliverables should be added.", "Determine whether these deliverables are necessary by verifying with experts in the field."], "answer": "Include the work in the WBS and recalculate the total project cost.", "explanation": "The WBS has all the work necessary to complete the deliverables. If work is missing, you would not be able to complete the deliverables." },
    { "question": "M1Q49 A Project Manager is working with a group of stakeholders to ensure their vision of the project is aligned. The Project Manager needs to obtain approval of the project management plan. What should the Project Manager do?", "options": ["Request that the project sponsor meets with the group to resolve this issue.", "Invite the stakeholders to meet with the team.", "Use facilitation to ensure the stakeholders are in agreement.", "Conduct stakeholder analysis."], "answer": "Use facilitation to ensure the stakeholders are in agreement.", "explanation": "To facilitate decision making project manager should use his facilitation skills to help the stakeholders agree on a shared vision." },
    { "question": "M1Q50 An organization has just moved to agile methods. The HR department has hired team members with a few members having agile experience in different agile methods. As a new project manager, what should you do in this situation?", "options": ["Have one member teach the entire team one method", "Select a method you feel is best and teach that method", "Teach the overall concept and principle of agile", "Have each team member teach their method"], "answer": "Teach the overall concept and principle of agile", "explanation": "It would be best if the entire team have a solid understanding of the core concepts of agile." },
    { "question": "M1Q51 The Project Manager invites team members to a meeting to create a document that will guide the team in defining the main project objectives. What will be the final output of this meeting?", "options": ["Activity list.", "Work breakdown structure (WBS)", "Scope management plan.", "Activity management plan."], "answer": "Scope management plan.", "explanation": "The scope management plan is a component of the project management plan that describes how the scope will be defined, developed, monitored, controlled, and validated." },
    { "question": "M1Q52 A network implementation project has just been executed. The plan is approved and the work has started. Quality is the most important part of this project. What should the project manager do to ensure the project meets its quality requirements?", "options": ["Review the work being done on a regular basis", "Create and implement quality metrics", "Create a Quality management plan", "Conduct inspections on the completed deliverables"], "answer": "Review the work being done on a regular basis", "explanation": "The best answer here would be to review the work on a regular basis, this would ensure work is getting done according to plan." },
    { "question": "M1Q53 A hybrid team is now working on deliverables for the project. The compliance department informs the team that one of the project deliverables has not met a new law. What is the first document the project manager should update?", "options": ["Issue log", "Scope statement", "Business case", "Risk register"], "answer": "Issue log", "explanation": "After a new issue is raised, the issue log should be reviewed and updated, as needed, prior to taking action." },
    { "question": "M1Q54 During an agile project, the customers have been requesting a lot of additions to the product backlog and also sending detailed emails to the project team about errors in the software. This may cause a delay in the project as the team is usually late with a response. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Tell the customers to attend the retrospective meetings to give their feedback", "Inform the team to respond to the customers right away", "Inform the customers it is correct to send it to the team", "Have the customer send you the additions and errors"], "answer": "Have the customer send you the additions and errors", "explanation": "By agile principles, it would be best for the customers to send you the errors and additions. The job of the servant leader is to shield the team from things that might distract them from completing the sprint goal." },
    { "question": "M1Q55 A project is almost done when a senior project team member requests a few weeks off due to health issues. What should the Project Manager do first?", "options": ["Assess how the leave will impact the project.", "Discuss the issue with the sponsor and request a replacement.", "Review the resource management plan.", "Ask the team member to see if the leave can be postponed."], "answer": "Assess how the leave will impact the project.", "explanation": "The first thing the Project Manager needs to do is to understand what impact (if any) this may have on the project." },
    { "question": "M1Q56 An agile project is about to start the first sprint when the project manager learns that the finance department will not finance the project due to concerns about how much value the project will return to the organization. What should the project manager do first after finding out about this issue?", "options": ["Schedule a meeting with the finance department and the product owner to learn more about this issue", "Continue the project until completion", "Speak with the product owner and ask for advice on the situation", "Terminate the project immediately"], "answer": "Schedule a meeting with the finance department and the product owner to learn more about this issue", "explanation": "A project manager should always learn more about an issue before taking action against the issue. In this scenario, it would be best to meet with the finance department to learn why the project will not be financed before taking any action." },
    { "question": "M1Q57 A Project Manager is preparing to develop a new product for a company. The new product will require a potential law change in order to be sold. The law is pending approval. To initiate this project, what should the Project Manager do?", "options": ["Document the risk in the project charter.", "Develop the scope statement.", "Develop a competitor analysis.", "Focus on quality control."], "answer": "Document the risk in the project charter.", "explanation": "The risk should be listed in the project charter, so its impact can be analyzed before project initiation." },
    { "question": "M1Q58 A new software development project follows traditional project management methods and hires a new team member. This team member is encouraging other members to follow agile methods. The other members are rejecting this and it is beginning to cause issues on the project. What should the project manager do to resolve this issue?", "options": ["Inform the new team member to stop encouraging agile methods to the team", "Schedule a meeting with the team and the new member to discuss the issue and brainstorm a solution", "Meet with the project team to implement agile methods", "Remove the team member from the project"], "answer": "Schedule a meeting with the team and the new member to discuss the issue and brainstorm a solution", "explanation": "In this scenario, it would be best to meet with the team in the new member to discuss this issue and have the team and the new member solve it." },
    { "question": "M1Q59 Match the risk response with its description.", "options": ["Don't believe a system would fail, so no response is needed", "Purchase a service contract for a project component", "Training team members on the correct usage of a software"], "answer": { "Don't believe a system would fail, so no response is needed": "Accept", "Purchase a service contract for a project component": "Transfer", "Training team members on the correct usage of a software": "Mitigate" }, "explanation": "Don't believe a system would fail, so no response is needed - Accept, Purchase a service contract for a project component ? Transfer, Training team members on the correct usage of a software ? Mitigate", "isMatching": true },
    { "question": "M1Q60 MBTI Match", "options": ["Like to be in a fast-paced environment", "Focus on the reality of how things are", "Could be described as reserved, private"], "answer": { "Like to be in a fast-paced environment": "Extraversion", "Focus on the reality of how things are": "Sensing", "Could be described as reserved, private": "Introversion" }, "explanation": "Like to be in a fast-paced environment ? Extraversion, Focus on the reality of how things are ? Sensing, Could be described as reserved, private ? Introversion", "isMatching": true }
];
const mock2Data = [
  { "question": "M2Q1: A Project Manager wants to estimate the duration of an activity. He asks a few team members. One member says it can be done in 5 days. The other member in 15 days. The third member says in 35 days. Using the triangular estimating technique, what is the duration of the activity?", "options": ["A: 13 days", "B: 18 days", "C: 21 days", "D: 15 days"], "answer": "B: 18 days", "explanation": "Using the Triangular formula: [Pessimistic estimate + Most likely estimate + Optimistic estimate]/3 = Therefore, [5+15+35]/3 = 18." },
  { "question": "M2Q2: An organization has moved from traditional to agile methods and is now conducting its first agile project. The newly appointed product owner would like the team to prioritize the features as soon as possible so they can start the sprints immediately. What should the project manager do in this scenario?", "options": ["A: Educate the product owner on the benefits of having him prioritize the features", "B: Inform the product owner that prioritizing the feature is not needed", "C: Work with the team to prioritize the features and store them in the product backlog", "D: Inform the team to prioritize the features and store them in the product backlog"], "answer": "A: Educate the product owner on the benefits of having him prioritize the features", "explanation": "On an agile project, it is important for the product owner to prioritize the features and store them in the product backlog. If the product owner refuses, then the project manager should educate them on the benefits of doing this." },
  { "question": "M2Q3: A smartphone company reports that customers are complaining that a new phone is very slow to boot, while others are saying it boots times are okay. A Project Manager needs to determine if something needs to be changed during the production of the smartphone. Which tool or technique can the Project Manager use for this?", "options": ["A: Affinity diagram", "B: Cost of Quality", "C: Histogram", "D: Control chart"], "answer": "D: Control chart", "explanation": "Control charts are used to determine whether or not a process is stable or has predictable performance." },
  { "question": "M2Q4: A product deliverable has failed acceptance testing. The sponsor says the deliverable was not created as per the original scope. What should the project manager do to avoid this in the future?", "options": ["A: Have the team demo the finished product.", "B: Review the change management plan.", "C: Have the team create the scope statement.", "D: Ensure a scope management plan is created"], "answer": "D: Ensure a scope management plan is created", "explanation": "A scope management plan documents how the project and product scope will be defined, validated and controlled." },
  { "question": "M2Q5: A customer is unwilling to accept the deliverable since it was not functioning the way they expected it. A Project Manager is evaluating what could have been done differently to avoid this. What should the Project Manager have done?", "options": ["A: Review the requirements documentation.", "B: Assess and evaluate the scope management plan.", "C: Ensure that the quality metrics are defined.", "D: Create the work breakdown structure (WBS) dictionary."], "answer": "C: Ensure that the quality metrics are defined.", "explanation": "Quality metrics are a description of a project or product attribute and how to measure it." },
  { "question": "M2Q6: A team working on a hybrid project is frustrated with the customers due to the constant changing of the project scope. When the team completes a release, the customers will then ask for the work to be redone. This has led to major delays in the project schedule. What can the project manager do to prevent this from happening while the project is progressing?", "options": ["A: Ensure customers are invited to the sprint review meeting to give feedback", "B: Inform the customers that changes should not be made after the work has been completed", "C: Have the team invite the customers to the daily standup meetings and take feedback from them", "D: Inform the project sponsor about this issue"], "answer": "A: Ensure customers are invited to the sprint review meeting to give feedback", "explanation": "If their constant changes to a deliverable, it would be best to invite the customers or have them participate more in the Sprint review meetings to give more feedback as it is being built." },
  { "question": "M2Q7: The project manager created a charter for a new software project. A senior stakeholder feels this project will have a negative impact on her employees. What should the project manager do first?", "options": ["A: Have the stakeholder meet with the team for a better explanation of the project.", "B: Document as a risk in the risk register.", "C: Have a meeting with the stakeholder to review the project objectives.", "D: Request for the project sponsor to speak with this stakeholder."], "answer": "C: Have a meeting with the stakeholder to review the project objectives.", "explanation": "The first thing the PM needs to do is to make sure the project objectives are well understood before taking any action." },
  { "question": "M2Q8: A project manager has been assigned to an ongoing project in the planning phase. The WBS has already been decomposed, but the project manager feels that more information will be needed in order to complete the project. What will the project manager use to further decomposed the work?", "options": ["A: Scope statement", "B: WBS dictionary", "C: Requirements documentation", "D: Requirements management plan"], "answer": "B: WBS dictionary", "explanation": "The best document for the user would be to WBS dictionary since it has detailed information about some of the work. After reviewing the WBS, the project manager can then determine what additional detailed meeting is needed." },
  { "question": "M2Q9: A company is creating a new technology product. The project manager has verified that the component work packages have been well-defined. Which estimating technique should the project manager use to obtain an accurate cost estimate of the deliverables?", "options": ["A: Analogous", "B: Three-point", "C: Parametric", "D: Bottom-up"], "answer": "D: Bottom-up", "explanation": "Bottom-up estimating is a method of estimating project duration or cost by aggregating the estimates of the lower-level components of the WBS." },
  { "question": "M2Q10: A key stakeholder is giving the team a hard time and is always arguing with team members. The stakeholder feels like no one understands him and knows how to communicate. If the issue is not resolved immediately, it could lead to the termination of the project. What should the project manager do in this situation in regards to the team?", "options": ["A: Inform the team to try to communicate with the stakeholder as the project is nearing completion", "B: Have the stakeholder communicate with them through email only", "C: Inform them not to communicate with the stakeholder going forward", "D: Train the team on emotional intelligence"], "answer": "D: Train the team on emotional intelligence", "explanation": "This solution would be to train the team on emotional intelligence so they can better communicate with the stakeholder and hopefully resolve this issue." },
  { "question": "M2Q11: A project is completing the deliverable and a key stakeholder will be unavailable for a few weeks during the project. This stakeholder will be the person to approve the deliverable. What should the project manager do first?", "options": ["A: Finish the project and have another stakeholder approve the deliverable", "B: Setup a meeting with the sponsor to evaluate the situation", "C: Ensure that the issue log is updated", "D: Request a replacement during the stakeholder's absence"], "answer": "C: Ensure that the issue log is updated", "explanation": "The first thing the PM needs to do is to update the issue log and communicate this to the other stakeholders." },
  { "question": "M2Q12: A small team is working virtually on a hybrid project and is having a difficult time being committed to the project. This has led to work being incomplete and defects in completed work. What should the project manager do first in this situation?", "options": ["A: Remove the team members that are having issues and replace them with more motivated members", "B: Meet with the team as a whole and inform them of this issue and have them resolve it immediately", "C: Meet with the project sponsor and inform him of this issue", "D: Speak with each team member individually to determine the root cause of this issue"], "answer": "D: Speak with each team member individually to determine the root cause of this issue", "explanation": "The best solution would be to meet with each member individually since it is a small team to better understand what is causing this. Then work with the team to find a resolution." },
  { "question": "M2Q13: A hybrid project has been executed and a new regulatory law has been passed that mandates immediate compliance. This law will increase the project's scope and cost schedule. What should the project manager do first?", "options": ["A: Update the risk register", "B: Escalate this to the senior company management.", "C: Ensure the project management plan is up to date.", "D: Implement a change request."], "answer": "D: Implement a change request.", "explanation": "Since compliance is mandatory and it impacts the scope, and cost, a change request needs to be submitted." },
  { "question": "M2Q14: A deliverable on the project's critical path is behind schedule. The cost performance index (CPI) is 1.3. The project manager wants it back on schedule. What is the most likely outcome for this deliverable?", "options": ["A: There will be rework.", "B: There will be activities performed in parallel.", "C: There will be a revised scope.", "D: There will be an increase in costs and risks."], "answer": "D: There will be an increase in costs and risks.", "explanation": "The Cost Performance Index (CPI) is above 1. Therefore the project is spending money at a rate lower than planned. It would be best to crash this deliverable to complete it sooner. This will generally increase cost and risk." },
  { "question": "M2Q15: A scrum team is having a difficult time staying on schedule. The PMO is concerned that this delay can cause the project to lose value. The project manager realizes that this is caused by team members not having the correct skills. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Find the correct training for the team members that needs it", "B: Meet with the team and inform them of the deadlines they have to meet", "C: Inform the PMO this is normal on a project", "D: Increase the project schedule to account for the delays"], "answer": "A: Find the correct training for the team members that needs it", "explanation": "The project manager should ensure the team members are adequately trained while working on a project." },
  { "question": "M2Q16: The project manager discovers that a senior stakeholder is asking a team member for project information. This is causing an issue with the team completing their work. Which should the project manager do first?", "options": ["A: Review the stakeholder register.", "B: Review the communications management plan.", "C: Refer to the project management information system (PMIS).", "D: Send the stakeholder the information yourself."], "answer": "B: Review the communications management plan.", "explanation": "A communications management plan is established to ensure that the appropriate messages are communicated to stakeholders in various formats and various means as defined by the communication strategy." },
  { "question": "M2Q17: The agile project team has complained that the product owner has prioritized the product backlog with everything as being critical. The team is not sure what to work on next. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Have the team reprioritize the entire product backlog", "B: Have the team choose what is the most important to start with first", "C: Meet with the product owner and educated him on why the product backlog should be reprioritize based on value", "D: Have the team prioritize the work based on what can be finished the fastest"], "answer": "C: Meet with the product owner and educated him on why the product backlog should be reprioritize based on value", "explanation": "Prioritization of the product backlog should be done by the product owner, not the product team. It would be best for the project manager to educate the product owner on the values of doing this." },
  { "question": "M2Q18: An organization has signed a fixed price contract with the vendor to upgrade its current network. The project manager thinks that due to certain network components, the project might be delayed by more than two months. The vendor has stated this will not happen. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Implement a change request to extend the project schedule by two months", "B: Update the risk register and risk responses", "C: Hire a new vendor on standby in case the vendor delays the project", "D: Update the procurement management plan with this potential issue"], "answer": "B: Update the risk register and risk responses", "explanation": "Since this is a risk that can affect the project schedule, the project manager should add the risk to the risk register with a corresponding response." },
  { "question": "M2Q19: A project manager is working with a customer who submitted over 10 new scope changes for an existing software development project. The project manager feels this is unnecessary due to the type of software being made. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["A: Analyze the scope management plan.", "B: Hold a meeting with the customer to request that the number of new requests is reduced.", "C: Organize a meeting with the team to set expectations.", "D: Define the number of changes with the sponsor."], "answer": "A: Analyze the scope management plan.", "explanation": "The scope management plan documents how the project and product scope will be defined, developed, monitored, controlled and validated. The document provides guidance and direction on how the scope will be managed throughout the project." },
  { "question": "M2Q20: A project manager is working on a large project for a global corporation. After conducting a stakeholder analysis, the project manager decides the best way to communicate would be through virtual meetings. The sponsor would prefer emails since it is what the organization uses the most. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Ask the PMO what would be best for this project", "B: Meet with the project sponsor and educate him on the benefits of virtual meetings over emails", "C: Inform the team they should use emails going forward", "D: Change the communication management plan to reflect emails"], "answer": "B: Meet with the project sponsor and educate him on the benefits of virtual meetings over emails", "explanation": "The project manager should always be willing to educate stakeholders on the benefits of using communication methods that are better suited to the project." },
  { "question": "M2Q21: A project is 9 months into execution. The Project Manager computes that the schedule performance index (SPI) is .60. The SPI was .9 in month 1, .8 in month 4 and .7 in month 8. What should the project do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Utilize the management reserve.", "B: Hire new team members to complete the work faster.", "C: Crash the project schedule.", "D: Issue a change request."], "answer": "D: Issue a change request.", "explanation": "Since the project is behind schedule and the trend analysis shows that this will continue, the best course of action is to update the project management plan with a new realistic schedule." },
  { "question": "M2Q22: As a project is being implemented. A key stakeholder communicates to the project manager that the requirements of the project may have changed. These changes may significantly impact the project scope. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Compute the current earned value management (EVM).", "B: Redo the scope statement.", "C: Update the risk register and identify risk responses.", "D: Use the contingency reserve and update the risk mitigation plan."], "answer": "C: Update the risk register and identify risk responses.", "explanation": "These new requirements may pose additional risks. These risks need to be documented and appropriate responses need to be identified." },
  { "question": "M2Q23: The agile project has just released a minimum viable product (MVP) to the customers and the company. A few of the customers have complained that it is lacking a large number of features and is not very useful. What should the project manager do first in this scenario?", "options": ["A: Inform the team to add the required features immediately", "B: Ask the product owner to meet with the customers to discuss this issue", "C: Educate the customers on the value of an MVP", "D: Pullback the release until it has the right amount of features"], "answer": "C: Educate the customers on the value of an MVP", "explanation": "The best-case scenario would be to educate the customers on the usage and value of an MVP and why it lacks certain features." },
  { "question": "M2Q24: A project has the following characteristics: -US$5 million budget -Planned value of US$635,000 -Actual cost of US$655,000 -Earned value of US$545,000. Which statement is true about the current status of the project?", "options": ["A: The project is behind schedule and under budget.", "B: The project is ahead of schedule and over budget.", "C: The project is behind schedule and over budget.", "D: The project is ahead of schedule and under budget."], "answer": "C: The project is behind schedule and over budget.", "explanation": "CV = EV - AC: $545-655=-110. SV = EV - PV: 545 - 635 = -90. Negative cost variance means the project is over budget, Negative schedule variance means the project is behind schedule." },
  { "question": "M2Q25: A recent change to safety regulations will be implemented soon across the entire country. After analyzing the project management plan, the project manager realizes the project will not be in compliance. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["A: Update the project management plan and continue working", "B: Meet with the legal department and seek guidance", "C: Add safety regulations as a risk to the risk register", "D: Meet with the legal department and implement a change request to update the project plan"], "answer": "D: Meet with the legal department and implement a change request to update the project plan", "explanation": "Since this is a regulation, the project manager should meet with the legal department and determine how to implement this across the project and then implement the change request." },
  { "question": "M2Q26: A project has been executed. The project must be completed fast. The project manager needs to quickly assign resources to meet project requirements. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["A: Conduct workshops.", "B: Acquire and train a team.", "C: Create the resource management plan.", "D: Host a webinar."], "answer": "B: Acquire and train a team.", "explanation": "Once the project team is established, the project manager can then start developing them." },
  { "question": "M2Q27: A new project manager is assigned to a new hybrid project and wants to start guiding the team toward project success. This project has been ongoing for the last three months. What should the new project manager do first?", "options": ["A: Review the project schedule to determine if extra time is required.", "B: Stop the project until he understands all the project objectives.", "C: Review the lesson learned register by the former project manager.", "D: Review the project charter to understand the goals and deliverables."], "answer": "D: Review the project charter to understand the goals and deliverables.", "explanation": "The Project Charter defines many aspects of the project which are critical to the new project manager's understanding of the project strategy, as well as the tactical execution." },
  { "question": "M2Q28: The project manager working on an agile project has received many emails from team members complaining that other members are interrupting them and causing them to delay their work. This is happening on a daily basis and may affect the project schedule. What can the project manager do to resolve this?", "options": ["A: Meet with all team members and find out the root cause of this issue and work with the team for a solution", "B: Coach the team on the benefits of solving problems on their own", "C: Have the team conduct the daily standup meeting more than once per day", "D: Meet with each member individually and inform them not to interrupt each other"], "answer": "A: Meet with all team members and find out the root cause of this issue and work with the team for a solution", "explanation": "Once there is an issue on a project with team members, it is best for the project manager to meet with the team and facilitate them to find the main cause of an issue and to resolve that issue." },
  { "question": "M2Q29: A Project Manager receives a list of assumptions, a few restrictions from the PMO and a preliminary scope from the sponsor. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["A: Review or create the business case", "B: Build the project team", "C: Build the project schedule", "D: Ensure project charter approval"], "answer": "A: Review or create the business case", "explanation": "The business case should be done before a charter can be written." },
  { "question": "M2Q30: A project manager wants to estimate the duration for the creation of a complex function. A subject matter expert says the function can be done as early as 20 days, as late as 70 days and will most likely take 30 days. What is the estimated development duration for this function?", "options": ["A: 35 Days", "B: 20 Days", "C: 30 Days", "D: 70 Days"], "answer": "A: 35 Days", "explanation": "Using 3 point estimating: Beta Estimate = (Optimistic + (4 x Most Likely) + Pessimistic)/6 = (20 + (4*30) + 70)/6 = 35 days." },
  { "question": "M2Q31: A project manager joins a project with a worldwide distributed virtual team and a budget that is fixed and a scope that is driven by certain regulations. What should the Project Manager do to avoid any scope creep?", "options": ["A: Have teams do weekly meetings", "B: Don't allow stakeholders to directly interact with the members", "C: Ask that all team members report all work to the project manager only", "D: Put any changes to scope through a formal approval process"], "answer": "D: Put any changes to scope through a formal approval process", "explanation": "Scope creep can be avoided by adherence to the agreed upon change management process." },
  { "question": "M2Q32: The project manager and the team are currently reviewing the risk register and the corresponding responses. They have determined that most of the severe risks are no longer a threat to the project. What should the project manager and the team do with the other less severe risks?", "options": ["A: Inform the project sponsor of this accomplishment", "B: Remove contingency reserves from the project plan", "C: Remove them from the risk register since they will not have much impact", "D: Reevaluate the risks and reprioritize the risk register."], "answer": "D: Reevaluate the risks and reprioritize the risk register.", "explanation": "The best course of action would be to reevaluate the risk and then reprioritize the risk register. Risk consistently changes on a daily basis and reevaluation should be done consistently throughout the project." },
  { "question": "M2Q33: A project manager has updated the work performance information of a hybrid project with an SPI of 1.2 and CPI of .78. What should the project manager review on this project?", "options": ["A: Review the budget since the project is over budget and ahead of schedule.", "B: Informed the sponsor the project is progressing as planned.", "C: Review the schedule since the project is behind schedule and under budget", "D: Review both the budget and schedule since both are not as planned"], "answer": "A: Review the budget since the project is over budget and ahead of schedule.", "explanation": "CPI and SPI should both be 1 and over. Any value under 1 would indicate the project is over budget or behind schedule." },
  { "question": "M2Q34: A project is behind schedule by 20% due to an issue with a stakeholder giving wrong requirements. The project manager issued a change request, but the stakeholder claims he didn't know about this change request. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["A: Update the communications management plan.", "B: Review the communications management and stakeholder engagement plans.", "C: Meet with the project sponsor to better understand stakeholders communication needs.", "D: Approve the change request"], "answer": "B: Review the communications management and stakeholder engagement plans.", "explanation": "There is a communication issue on this project. The PM should first review the communication management plan and the engagement plan." },
  { "question": "M2Q35: A project sponsor requests the Project Manager to change a component to increase the customer likeability of the product. What should the project manager do first?", "options": ["A: Follow the perform integrated change control process.", "B: Stop the project and enact the change.", "C: Reject the change since it is outside the scope.", "D: Immediately implement the change."], "answer": "A: Follow the perform integrated change control process.", "explanation": "The perform integrated change control process is done to analyze a change and get it approved." },
  { "question": "M2Q36: A project manager has been managing an agile project for several months when an unexpected component of the project fails. The team thinks they can fix this without any impact on the project. If the team cannot fix it, it may delay the project significantly. What should the project manager do?", "options": ["A: Delay the project by a few weeks to have the team address the issue", "B: Meet with the team to discuss how they will fix it and agree on a solution", "C: Have the team work on the issue and hope to finish it on time", "D: Immediately inform the sponsor of this issue"], "answer": "B: Meet with the team to discuss how they will fix it and agree on a solution", "explanation": "The best course of action would be to meet with the team and determine how the conflict is said that if it's possible." },
  { "question": "M2Q37: A key stakeholder on the project is very upset that they have not been included in the regular project communications. This has led to the stakeholder missing vital reports on the project performance. What should the project manager do first to resolve this communications issue?", "options": ["A: Meet with the team to understand why the stakeholder was not updated", "B: Implement a change request to fix the communications management plan", "C: Review the project management plan", "D: Meet with the stakeholder to understand why he wants the report"], "answer": "C: Review the project management plan", "explanation": "The best course of action would be to first review the project management plan which will include the communication and stakeholder engagement plan to better understand what communications should have taken place before trying to resolve this issue." },
  { "question": "M2Q38: One of the sprints on an agile project has become very complex. The product owner would like the work to be completed within four weeks, but the project manager thinks this may take longer. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Hire an outside consultant to help the team", "B: Have the agile team work together to complete the work as fast as possible", "C: Inform the product owner that it will take a few more weeks to complete", "D: Facilitate the team and push them to complete the work within four weeks"], "answer": "B: Have the agile team work together to complete the work as fast as possible", "explanation": "It would be best to let this self-organized and cross-functional team work on the sprint as fast as they could while facilitating and coaching them to complete the work." },
  { "question": "M2Q39: A team is having a difficult time determining how long it should take to finish a particular feature. One senior programmer says the feature can be done in as little as 7 days but could take as long as 32 days. The other programmer said it would most likely take 14 days to complete. What is the estimated development duration for the new product using the Beta estimation technique?", "options": ["A: 16 Days", "B: 32 Days", "C: 7 Days", "D: 18 Days"], "answer": "A: 16 Days", "explanation": "Using the Beta Estimate = (Optimistic + (4 X Most Likely) + Pessimistic)/6 = (7 + (4*14) + 32)/6 = 96/6 = 16 days." },
  { "question": "M2Q40: A project was just executed when the team noticed they would need to implement changes to the scope statement. The team cannot come to an agreement on how to implement these changes. What should the Project Manager do first?", "options": ["A: Organize a meeting with team members and sponsor to review the impact of this change.", "B: Hold a meeting with the project sponsor to address the issue.", "C: Ensure all team members understand the change management plan.", "D: Ensure all requested changes are applied to the project."], "answer": "C: Ensure all team members understand the change management plan.", "explanation": "The team and Project Manager must follow the agreed upon change management processes." },
  { "question": "M2Q41: After the project work is finished, the project team members are still being asked to do the following: -Make minor modifications -Solve technical and non-technical issues. The project manager wants to ensure the product now has operational support. What should the Project Manager do?", "options": ["A: Formally release the project team.", "B: Fulfill the requests.", "C: Examine the acceptance criteria.", "D: Complete the delivery of the project."], "answer": "D: Complete the delivery of the project.", "explanation": "Project closure happens once the project is complete. The PM should formally close the project and deliver the final product, service, or result." },
  { "question": "M2Q42: An organization has moved from traditional project management methods to agile methods. This was done so the project can output deliverables faster. What two things should the project manager implement to ensure faster delivery on an agile project? (Choose 2)", "options": ["A: Have the team delegate work to each other based on their skill set", "B: Delegate work to the project team based on their skill set to accomplish the work faster", "C: Speak with the product owner to determine who should be delegating the work to the team", "D: Have the team work with the customers to prioritize the product backlog", "E: Work with the product owner and educate him about prioritizing the product backlog"], "answer": "A: Have the team delegate work to each other based on their skill set, E: Work with the product owner and educate him about prioritizing the product backlog", "explanation": "On an agile project, is important to have a product owner prioritize the product backlog. The team should be a self-organizing self-directed team. This means they will determine what work to do and who does the work." },
  { "question": "M2Q43: A draft of a project management plan is completed and needs to be sent to sponsors around the world. There is limited time and needs to get approved fast. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Send the plan for the sponsors for review, and then meet with them all individually.", "B: Have each sponsor review the plan individually, adding any recommendation, and then hold a virtual meeting.", "C: Organize individual meetings with only a few sponsors to walk them through the plan.", "D: Ask select sponsors to review particular sections of the plan."], "answer": "B: Have each sponsor review the plan individually, adding any recommendation, and then hold a virtual meeting.", "explanation": "By sending the project management plan to the sponsors in advance, the PM can ensure that the virtual meeting is most productive." },
  { "question": "M2Q44: A project team on an agile project is having a difficult time getting along with each other. The constant conflict has led to the project being severely delayed. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Meet with each team member individually and give them solutions on the issues", "B: Organize meetings in different face-to-face activities with the team to resolve these conflicts", "C: Meet with the project sponsor to discuss changing team members", "D: Meet with the team and demonstrate how the conflict is affecting the project"], "answer": "B: Organize meetings in different face-to-face activities with the team to resolve these conflicts", "explanation": "The best way to resolve team conflicts would be to have the team discuss these conflicts in a face-to-face session." },
  { "question": "M2Q45: A new agile virtual team is having difficulty communicating due to the complexities of the technology being used. They complain that the technology is very difficult to use and it leads to delays in communication. What should the project manager do first in this situation?", "options": ["A: Replace technology with a simpler technology", "B: Request from the product owner additional funding for the team to work in the same environment", "C: Inform the team to use the self-help feature in the software to learn", "D: Review the training requirements for the technology and ensure the project team is trained"], "answer": "D: Review the training requirements for the technology and ensure the project team is trained", "explanation": "It is up to the project manager to ensure the team is well trained in the development of the deliverables and the usage of technology on the project." },
  { "question": "M2Q46: An organization has transitioned from traditional project methods to agile methods. Many team members feel that the daily standup meetings are a waste of time. What should the project manager do to handle this situation?", "options": ["A: Inform them that the standup is optional", "B: Inform them it is okay to have the standup just once a week", "C: Inform the product owner of the noncompliance by the team", "D: Educate them on the benefits of the daily standup"], "answer": "D: Educate them on the benefits of the daily standup", "explanation": "When an organization moves from one method to the next, it is important for a project manager to educate the team on the benefits and processes within that method." },
  { "question": "M2Q47: An organization has been authorized to conduct a hybrid project that includes toxic materials. If the team is not trained on how to handle the materials, it will be a safety risk. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Update the risk register and risk management", "B: Include mandatory training for the team in the project budget when planning the project.", "C: Alert the sponsor and product owner of this risk", "D: Build the team with only resources who know how to handle the materials"], "answer": "B: Include mandatory training for the team in the project budget when planning the project.", "explanation": "Since this is a safety risk and will happen if there are not trained, the best action would be to ensure the team is trained to handle the materials." },
  { "question": "M2Q48: A Project Manager is working on an agile team. The Project Manager realized that two members are having a very serious disagreement about an approach to fix a technical issue. They are not allowing each other to speak and raising their voices at each other. In what phase of development is the team now?", "options": ["A: Confronting", "B: Storming", "C: Attacking", "D: Performing"], "answer": "B: Storming", "explanation": "Storming is when the team is having issues and conflicts about getting the work done." },
  { "question": "M2Q49: An organization is looking to appoint a new project manager to an ongoing hybrid project. The PMO has selected a few candidates and would like to submit your information to senior management for a decision. What should they submit in order for senior management to make a decision?", "options": ["A: A set of projects each potential manager has managed before and their detailed outcomes", "B: Project management plans and documents that each manager has created before", "C: A resume with certifications and business experience for each potential manager", "D: A set of projects each manager has managed and the performance of each project"], "answer": "D: A set of projects each manager has managed and the performance of each project", "explanation": "When it comes to working with senior management is important to give them the least amount of information for them to make an educated decision. Anything else would have been too much information for senior management to review." },
  { "question": "M2Q50: An organization was able to complete an agile project on a budget of $85,000. A few months later, they decided to do a project that was almost the same as the previous project. But this time, the budget came out to be $125,000. What could the project manager have done to prevent this increase in costs?", "options": ["A: Work with the same resources as the previous project", "B: Conduct an analysis of resource costs before planning the project", "C: Set a flat budget from the start of planning", "D: Reduce some of the work in the project scope"], "answer": "B: Conduct an analysis of resource costs before planning the project", "explanation": "The best answer here would have been to conduct an analysis of the cost before planning the project. This way, they would have an expected budget before actually going to the detailed planning." },
  { "question": "M2Q51: The project manager has worked with the current customers on a previous traditional project. The customers have informed the project manager that this new agile project is delivering products that are not meeting the requirements. What should the project manager do in this scenario?", "options": ["A: Tell the customers changes can be done once the product goes to operations", "B: Inform the customers to attend the iteration review meetings", "C: Have the customers review and prioritize the product backlog", "D: Stop the project to review the requirements"], "answer": "B: Inform the customers to attend the iteration review meetings", "explanation": "The best course of action would be to inform the customers to attend iteration review meetings so they can give feedback as the product is being built." },
  { "question": "M2Q52: A customer on a traditional project has requested a major change to the scope of the project. The project manager has informed the sponsor of this change. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["A: Stop the project until the change has been approved or disapproved", "B: Submit a change request to the change control board for approval", "C: Inform the customer the change cannot be done due to its impact", "D: Review how this change may affect other aspects of the project"], "answer": "D: Review how this change may affect other aspects of the project", "explanation": "What a change has been requested, the next step would be to assess how this change can impact all aspects of the project." },
  { "question": "M2Q53: A task in an iteration doesn't get completed due to a team member's personal issue that appeared two days before the iteration was finished but did not get resolved. What should the project manager do to prevent this from happening again?", "options": ["A: During the next iteration planning meeting, discuss the issue.", "B: In the next daily standup meeting, inspect the issue.", "C: In the iteration review, address the issue.", "D: During the retrospective, inspect the issue."], "answer": "D: During the retrospective, inspect the issue.", "explanation": "A retrospective is where the team will talk about what went right, what went wrong, lessons learned and what to improve for next time." },
  { "question": "M2Q54: A project manager working on an agile project and has noticed that some team members are experts and others are not. This has led to some tasks taking longer than expected, while some are completed soon. The Project Manager needs to enhance team performance. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Implement the necessary training for all team members.", "B: Train the others yourself to ensure the team has equal skills.", "C: Request that the senior level resources train others.", "D: Manage the expert resources and remove the others."], "answer": "A: Implement the necessary training for all team members.", "explanation": "The PM must Implement training were necessary for all team members." },
  { "question": "M2Q55: You have been recently assigned a job as a project manager on an ongoing project. The customer has just requested a change to reduce the budget by 20%. What should you do first?", "options": ["A: Meet with the team to discuss how this change may impact the project", "B: Review the change management plan", "C: Look for ways to reduce the schedule and scope to decrease the budget by 20%", "D: Submit the change to the change control board"], "answer": "B: Review the change management plan", "explanation": "On a project, the first action a project manager should do is review the project documentations such as the change management plan, before taking any actions." },
  { "question": "M2Q56: While working on an agile project, a few team members are having an issue determining the best method to develop a feature in the software. What should the project manager do to resolve this issue?", "options": ["A: Conduct your own research and determine what method is best", "B: Meet with the team in an open setting and have a discussion on the different methods", "C: Stop the project until the team has decided which method would be best", "D: Tell the team to select one method and continue to work"], "answer": "B: Meet with the team in an open setting and have a discussion on the different methods", "explanation": "Anytime there is an issue between team members on a project, it's best for the project manager to facilitate discussion in order to solve the problem." },
  { "question": "M2Q57: A project manager has been alerted by a key stakeholder on a recently approved project that the project management method is not sufficient for the project. What should the project manager do next to resolve this issue?", "options": ["A: Implement the change request to change the project management method", "B: Update the issue log with this issue", "C: Meet with the project sponsor to alert them of this concern", "D: Schedule a one-on-one discussion with this key stakeholder to understand their concern"], "answer": "D: Schedule a one-on-one discussion with this key stakeholder to understand their concern", "explanation": "Before taking any actions, the project manager should meet with the stakeholder to better understand what the concerns are about the methods." },
  { "question": "M2Q58: A project manager working on a construction project has received notification from the local safety authority that the working conditions for the workers may result in injuries. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Immediately inform the sponsor about this situation", "B: Meet with the workers and inform them of the situation", "C: Call the safety authority and inform them you have fixed the issue", "D: Immediately stop the project until the situation has been fixed"], "answer": "D: Immediately stop the project until the situation has been fixed", "explanation": "Since this is a safety issue and may result in injuries, the best course of action would be to stop the project until the situation can be resolved. All other choices allow the project to continue operating." },
  { "question": "M2Q59: Match the Terms. 1. Limits the work in progress 2. Will be decomposed into the WBS 3. Organized by the product owner.", "options": ["A: Kanban", "B: Scope Statement", "C: Product Backlog"], "answer": "N/A", "explanation": "The correct answer is: Limits the work in progress → Kanban, Will be decomposed into the WBS → Scope Statement, Organized by the product owner → Product Backlog" },
  { "question": "M2Q60: Match the motivation description to the theory. 1. Herzberg's Theory of Motivation 2. Theory X 3. Theory Y.", "options": ["A: Hygiene agents", "B: Micromanager", "C: Employees like working"], "answer": "N/A", "explanation": "The correct answer is: Herzberg's Theory of Motivation → Hygiene agents, Theory X → Micromanager, Theory Y → Employees like working" }
];
const mock3Data = [
    {"question":"M3Q1 A team member has unexpectedly been out for more than one week due to reasons that no one knows about. This length of absence has caused the critical path to increase by two weeks. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Ask the functional manager to contact the team member to discuss the situation.","Call the team member to discuss the situation and identify solutions to the issue.","Have other team members work overtime to complete the unfinished work.","Immediately contact the PMO and hire a new team member."],"answer":"Call the team member to discuss the situation and identify solutions to the issue.","explanation":"The most appropriate response would be to first contact the team member to see if there is a major personal issue and then, if possible, to come up with solutions to these issues to get the team member back to work."},
    {"question":"M3Q2 New members are added to an ongoing agile project. The original team members received basic training on business processes and new members do not have the same training. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Train all members together using a self-pace web portal.","Inform new team members that they should ask the original members for help.","Inform the new members they will learn the processes over time","Ask the original team members to provide support and training for new team members."],"answer":"Ask the original team members to provide support and training for new team members.","explanation":"It is the PM's responsibility to make sure that the new members are adequately trained. This approach provides that training."},
    {"question":"M3Q3 A Project Manager is leading a project that has a diverse global agile team. What should the Project Manager do to develop cultural sensitivity?","options":["Discover each team member's culture in-depth for several weeks.","Seek help from PMO to obtain formal training in this area.","Travel to each team member's geographic location to meet face-to-face.","Be aware of local customs and remain flexible when working with team members"],"answer":"Be aware of local customs and remain flexible when working with team members","explanation":"The Project Manager needs to be proactive and learn what he can while also keeping flexible."},
    {"question":"M3Q4 A project team has completed a few deliverables and would like to get approval on them. After meeting with a few of the stakeholders the project manager realizes that disagreements among them could lead to none of the deliverables being accepted. What should the project manager do next?","options":["Meet with the team and inform them to update the deliverables immediately","Update the project management plan with the new requirements to get the deliverables accepted","Implement a change request to modify the scope of the project","Have a meeting with the stakeholders to understand the root cause of the disagreements"],"answer":"Have a meeting with the stakeholders to understand the root cause of the disagreements","explanation":"The best course of action would be to meet with the stakeholders and find out what is causing the disagreement and then come up with a solution based on the main cause."},
    {"question":"M3Q5 A project's sponsor has been replaced by a large PMO due to the nature of the project and the effect on the organization. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Modify the communications management plan to the PMO","Follow the original communications management plan","Guarantee that the PMO members receive the project's current status report.","Schedule a meeting with the PMO and the team, but continue to follow the original communications management plan."],"answer":"Modify the communications management plan to the PMO","explanation":"The Project Manager needs to be proactive and respond to this change. The same communication that was planned for a sponsor will not necessarily work for this PMO."},
    {"question":"M3Q6 A Project Manager identifies two new risks. These risks could impact a few key components. The Project Manager wants to reference additional information before presenting this new risk information. To which sources should the Project Manager refer to check if these are new risks?","options":["Risk register and risk report.","Risk register and Risk management plan.","Risk management plan and risk report.","Issue log and risk report."],"answer":"Risk register and risk report.","explanation":"The Project Manager must check the risk register and risk report to see if this is indeed a new risk and to see if there was action already planned around it."},
    {"question":"M3Q7 An organization was following traditional methods has recently moved to agile methods. A senior member of the IT department is not knowledgeable on any agile methods. Since most of the projects will be IT-based projects, how should the project manager approach this situation?","options":["Ask the team members to educate the senior member on the best practices of agile","Manage the projects using agile and hybrid methods yourself","Coach the senior member on agile processes and values","Ask the senior member to attend agile classes"],"answer":"Coach the senior member on agile processes and values","explanation":"It would be best for the project manager to coach the senior member and to teach the values of agile and the corresponding processes. This would ensure the project gets more support and acceptance."},
    {"question":"M3Q8 An organization has recently implemented agile methods to bring products to the market faster. Senior management would like to see rollouts being done within six months versus the traditional 18-month rollouts. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Hire expert team members that specialize in particular skills","Prioritize the product backlog based on what can be done the quickest on a project","Implement a strict change management process to keep scope changes at a minimum","Develop an approach using minimum viable products (MVP)"],"answer":"Develop an approach using minimum viable products (MVP)","explanation":"By utilizing MVP's the organization will be able to release products quicker to the market with minimal features. This will allow them to gain more feedback and develop the product more time."},
    {"question":"M3Q9 A Project Manager working on a hybrid project meets with a key project stakeholder to understand how complex the project deliverables are. The stakeholder expresses fear and worries regarding the deliverables. What should the Project Manager do to ensure that the deliverables are accurate?","options":["Inform the stakeholder the team will fix all issues and add them to the issue log.","Perform a feasibility study.","Have the sponsor meet with the stakeholder to resolve this issue.","Conduct a risk assessment and present the result to the stakeholder."],"answer":"Perform a feasibility study.","explanation":"To ensure that the deliverable is realistic, the Project Manager needs to conduct a feasibility study and then evaluate the results."},
    {"question":"M3Q10 A customer has agreed to accept the deliverable after it was built by the team. A few weeks later, the customer changes their mind and will not accept it. What should the Project Manager do?","options":["Review the quality management plan.","Review the project charter.","Review the requirements documentation.","Review the acceptance criteria."],"answer":"Review the acceptance criteria.","explanation":"The acceptance criteria are what needs to be met for the customer to accepted the deliverable."},
    {"question":"M3Q11 A project manager working on a hybrid project has informed the team that they will need to identify the best communication methods for the project and any corresponding risk from these methods. The team will also help to identify the responses. What type of leadership is a project manager using here?","options":["Charismatic","Laissez-faire","Servant","Transformational"],"answer":"Laissez-faire","explanation":"Laissez-faire is when the project manager is hands-off and allows the team to make their own decisions."},
    {"question":"M3Q12 An organization has just adopted a hybrid approach to all internal projects. They have conducted hybrid training for all of the internal project managers. After a few of the projects have started, the PMO has noticed the team members are having major issues conducting the project work due to team members working slow or have issues with each other. What could've gone wrong in the training for the project managers?","options":["Training didn't teach how project managers should assign work to the team","Training didn't teach about backlog prioritization","The training didn't teach the principles of servant leadership","The training did not include team members"],"answer":"The training didn't teach the principles of servant leadership","explanation":"One of the core concepts of agile project management is to keep the team motivated is to support them, coach them and give them the tools they need to succeed. This is all done using servant leadership."},
    {"question":"M3Q13 The project team is working on a traditional project and has encountered a risk that could drastically impact the schedule. What should the project manager do first?","options":["Meet with the team to determine the correct response","Review the risk management plan","Update the issues log with this new risk","Meet with the project sponsor to alert them of the new risk"],"answer":"Review the risk management plan","explanation":"The first action the project manager should take would be to review the risk management plan to determine what steps should be taken when the risk is identified."},
    {"question":"M3Q14 A project team is having many communication issues on the project. This includes using inappropriate language towards each other. What should the project manager suggest in order to solve this problem?","options":["Resource management plan","Team charter","A penalty system for disorderly members","The performance assessment"],"answer":"Team charter","explanation":"Team charters are used on a project to set the ground rules for the team. This includes the use of inappropriate language and other personnel management tactics."},
    {"question":"M3Q15 While working on an office relocation project, a team member has informed the project manager that the communication management plan is not needed for the project since everyone knows everyone. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Meet with the sponsor to understand if the communication management plan is really needed.","Request the team member be removed from the project","Removed the communication plan from the project","Keep the communication Management in the project"],"answer":"Keep the communication Management in the project","explanation":"The communication management plan is vital for the success of any project. Removing would likely cause misunderstanding and issues on the project."},
    {"question":"M3Q16 The project team over the last few iterations has not been performing up to plan. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Stop the project work until the team has resolved all issues, then proceed","Replace team members that are causing issues on the project","Meet with the team and conduct coaching sessions","Conduct assessments on individuals to identify who needs to be replaced on the team"],"answer":"Meet with the team and conduct coaching sessions","explanation":"Your best strength here will be to work with the team directly to address any performance issues."},
    {"question":"M3Q17 A team is currently working on a hybrid project and many of the project requirements are not being met. Many senior stakeholders are unhappy with the progress so far. What should a project manager do to handle the situation?","options":["Assess the team performance","Remove the team members that are causing issues on the project","Schedule frequent meetings with the stakeholders to better understand the requirements","Meet with the team and review the requirements document."],"answer":"Schedule frequent meetings with the stakeholders to better understand the requirements","explanation":"It would be best to have the team meet with the stakeholders periodically throughout the project so they can gain feedback on what was done."},
    {"question":"M3Q18 The sponsor and project team have agreed that the hybrid project has a suitable budget and accurate schedule. The Project Manager fears that unexpected events could threaten the project's success. What should the Project Manager do first?","options":["Ask the sponsor for additional funding to cover the unexpected events.","Schedule a meeting with the sponsor to address the potential impact of unexpected risks.","Execute the project since the budget and schedule are approved by the team.","Identify project risks, then assess those risks."],"answer":"Identify project risks, then assess those risks.","explanation":"The Project Manager needs to familiarize himself with risks and their mitigation strategies."},
    {"question":"M3Q19 A mid-size project with about 100 stakeholders is close to completion, so the Project Manager must prepare to officially close the project. How should the Project Manager obtain signoff on the acceptance of project deliverables?","options":["Ask the project sponsor to sign off.","Ask functional managers to sign off.","Ask the team to sign off.","Ask the steering committee to sign off."],"answer":"Ask the project sponsor to sign off.","explanation":"The sponsor provided the resources for the project and it is, therefore, his responsibility to officially sign off on the project deliverables."},
    {"question":"M3Q20 An agile team is developing a new HR management software using hybrid methods. A couple of the iterations will be done by an outside consulting company. After the second iteration with the consulting company, the project manager learns that the component will be delayed by over three weeks. What should the project manager do first?","options":["Replace the consulting company","Ask the vendors if an increase in their fees will help to keep the project on schedule","Review the procurement management plan","Modify the project schedule to include the additional three weeks"],"answer":"Review the procurement management plan","explanation":"The first step the project manager should take would be to review how the project will handle conflicts with their external sellers. This would be documented in the procurement management plan."},
    {"question":"M3Q21 An organization has decided to upgrade one of its key products. The decision is to use an agile approach. One of the key stakeholders is concerned that the upgrade may not meet user expectations. What should the project manager do to ensure the project is successful?","options":["Ensure customers attend the iteration review meetings","Hire team members that are experts in a particular skill","Hire outside consultants when necessary to ensure customer acceptance","Have the customers involved in selecting team members"],"answer":"Ensure customers attend the iteration review meetings","explanation":"One of the best ways to ensure the project is successful in the to meet the customer's requirements is to ensure that the customers are participating in giving feedback as the product is being developed. This would ensure that, in the end, the product will have met the requirements."},
    {"question":"M3Q22 A hybrid project with a quality management plan states that project deliverables must be reviewed every other week. The last two deliverables have missed this requirement. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Modify the quality management plan to check the deliverables later.","Inform the sponsor of this issue.","Use a cause-and-effect diagram for root cause analysis.","Have the team check the deliverable weekly."],"answer":"Use a cause-and-effect diagram for root cause analysis.","explanation":"By understanding the root cause of the issue, the Project Manager may avoid this type of problem later on in this and other projects."},
    {"question":"M3Q23 A company wants to reduce costs by insulating its office building. The local government provides most of the cost due to the energy saving of the project. After the project start, the Project Manager learns that the project will not qualify. What should the project manager do next?","options":["Add the risk to the risk register.","File a change request.","Make use of the contingency reserve.","Add the issue to the Issue Log."],"answer":"Add the issue to the Issue Log.","explanation":"Logging the issue first means that it can be analyzed and understood by the project team and all stakeholders."},
    {"question":"M3Q24 The project team has completed building the deliverables for the project. Upon inspection by the customers, they notice a few missing requirements. What should the project manager do to fix this issue?","options":["Implement a change request to add the additional feature","Implement a change request to remove the missing features","Inform the customers the feature is not needed","Add this to the issue log"],"answer":"Implement a change request to add the additional feature","explanation":"A project is supposed to be completed scope within a given time and budget. In this situation, it would be best to implement the change request to ensure all the features that were originally part of the scope to get completed."},
    {"question":"M3Q25 A key stakeholder on an agile project has requested that iterations deliver a product at the end and not over many increments. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Inform the product owner of this issue","Meet with the team to discuss how to resolve this issue","Inform the stakeholders of the benefits of incremental deliveries","Inform the team to only deliver the product at the end of the project"],"answer":"Inform the stakeholders of the benefits of incremental deliveries","explanation":"It is important that men following agile methods that the concept of incremental deliveries followed in order to maximize its benefits. The best course of action would be to train is key stakeholders on these benefits."},
    {"question":"M3Q26 During the daily standup meeting, a team member has informed the others that the IT department is having an issue with the server that is needed to complete the Sprint. What should the project manager do in the situation?","options":["Call the IT department to inform them this issue needs to resolve quickly","Ask the team member to speak to the IT department to resolve this issue quickly","Ask the project sponsor to discuss this issue with the IT department","After the meeting, analyze this issue and work with the IT department to resolve this issue"],"answer":"After the meeting, analyze this issue and work with the IT department to resolve this issue","explanation":"Part of working on an agile project is to be a servant leader remove any external issues that can affect the project team. These impairments can be things such as IT related issues."},
    {"question":"M3Q27 A hybrid project currently has eight deliverables that must get done for the project to be completed. A key stakeholder is concerned that one of the deliverables will not be done correctly. What should the project manager do to handle this situation? (Choose 2)","options":["Update the project sponsor about the concerns the stakeholder is having","Inform the stakeholder that all deliverables will be completed correctly","Review the scope statement and other project documents","Remove this deliverable from the project","Meet with the stakeholder to understand their concerns","Stop the project immediately until this dispute can be solved"],"answer":["Review the scope statement and other project documents","Meet with the stakeholder to understand their concerns"],"explanation":"The best action here would be to first review the scope statement and other project documents to understand the main requirements of the deliverables and then meet with the stakeholders to understand what their concerns are. This way, the project manager can find the root cause of the concerns and hopefully resolve them.","isMultipleChoice":true},
    {"question":"M3Q28 A project manager has just been assigned to work on a hybrid project at the client site. The client site includes a variety of functional managers and key stakeholders for the project. The organization's senior management is concerned that the project will not meet all of the different stakeholder's needs. What should the project manager do to address this concern?","options":["Meet with key stakeholders and prioritize their needs","Inform the project team that they must meet the needs of the senior management of the organization","Meet with the functional managers and prioritize their needs","Conduct stakeholder analysis and determine the needs of all stakeholders"],"answer":"Conduct stakeholder analysis and determine the needs of all stakeholders","explanation":"The best approach here would be to conduct stakeholder analysis for all stakeholders, not prioritize one group over another."},
    {"question":"M3Q29 The project has three team members working on three separate tasks at the same time. The project manager is worried that when these tasks come together, they may not function well. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Identify potential conflicts, and then arrange for a regular meeting with the members to review each other's work.","Continue to let all members work simultaneously, recognizing that conflicts can be addressed at a later date","Decide which members work should be prioritized","Document conflicts as they occur and take action to remedy any problems that arise."],"answer":"Identify potential conflicts, and then arrange for a regular meeting with the members to review each other's work.","explanation":"The PM should ensure consistent communication is done correctly throughout the development to identify risks or issue early."},
    {"question":"M3Q30 A Project manager has noticed that a hybrid project was behind schedule and has implemented new resources to speed up the work. This method did not work and the project is still behind schedule. The project manager has decided to escalate this issue. What should the Project Manager do first?","options":["Refer to the change management plan.","Review the stakeholder engagement plan.","Refer to the communications management plan.","Review the risk management plan."],"answer":"Refer to the communications management plan.","explanation":"The communications management plan will detail how the project communications will occur. This includes how to escalate issues."},
    {"question":"M3Q31 A recently completed agile project that spanned multiple countries over a period of two years has led to major dissatisfaction with the key stakeholders. They claim the project took too long and did not deliver on all promises. What actions should the project manager have taken to prevent this outcome? (Choose 2)","options":["Engage the stakeholders throughout the project by conducting Sprint review meetings","Allow customers to change the scope as needed as project was progressing","Implement change management process requiring a written change request","Ensure changes to the project scope could not have been done once the plan was approved","Ensure customers communicated with the project manager only and not the team"],"answer":["Engage the stakeholders throughout the project by conducting Sprint review meetings","Allow customers to change the scope as needed as project was progressing"],"explanation":"In agile practices, is best to ensure the stakeholders are engaged throughout the project and are allowed to change the scope that is needed.","isMultipleChoice":true},
    {"question":"M3Q32 An agile project has completed four iterations so far. One of the senior executives would like an update on the work that has been completed. What would be the best way to update the senior executive?","options":["Email the senior executive a list of the features that have been completed","Ask the senior executive to attend a one-on-one meeting with you to explain the project progress","Ask the project management office for guidance on the best method to update the senior executive","Make the project status document available on the company intranet so the senior executive can check it when he has free time"],"answer":"Ask the senior executive to attend a one-on-one meeting with you to explain the project progress","explanation":"The best way to communicate project information and resolve issues is usually face-to-face. This meeting with the to a better overall session where the executive will be able to get his questions answered and better understand what's happening on the project."},
    {"question":"M3Q33 A project manager working on a mission-critical product development hybrid project has noticed that the project sponsor has not been communicating or engage in the project. This may lead to schedule delays since deliverables acceptance may not occur when needed. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Inform the sponsor of this issue and what it could mean for the project schedule","Keep working on the project and hope that this sponsor engages later","Send the communications management plan to the sponsor for review","Meet with the sponsor to discuss the issue and to brainstorm solutions"],"answer":"Meet with the sponsor to discuss the issue and to brainstorm solutions","explanation":"The best option here would be to meet with the sponsor or to discuss this issue and then to come up with a resolution to it."},
    {"question":"M3Q34 A hybrid project deliverable is being built by the team. Based on the originally approved plan, 650 products were developed. The project team randomly chooses 50 products to evaluate against the quality plan. What is the project team undertaking?","options":["Quality assurance.","Statistical sampling.","Process audit.","Control procurement."],"answer":"Statistical sampling.","explanation":"Statistical sampling involves choosing part of a population of interest for inspection."},
    {"question":"M3Q35 A vendor has informed the project team that the product description was incorrect and the vendor will not fix any issues with the finished product. What should the project manager do first?","options":["Review the risk management plan and document lessons learned.","Check the service level agreement (SLA) with the vendor.","Review the procurement management plan and agreements.","Check the risk register."],"answer":"Review the procurement management plan and agreements.","explanation":"The first action should be to review the contract and the procurement management plan to understand what steps should be taken next."},
    {"question":"M3Q36 A project manager has noticed that the finance department is not sending the required funds to the project account in order to fund the work on the project. The finance department claim this project will not have any value to the organization. The project should stop immediately. What should the project manager do first in the situation?","options":["Reschedule the project work until the issue can be resolved","Report this issue to the sponsor and have the sponsor meet with the finance department","Immediately terminate the project and release the team","Schedule a meeting with the finance department to better understand what is the main issue"],"answer":"Schedule a meeting with the finance department to better understand what is the main issue","explanation":"Before taking any actions, the project manager should have a better understanding of what the issues are and how they can be fixed."},
    {"question":"M3Q37 A company starts implementing scrum. About halfway through the first sprint, communication issues develop. Some project team members are not in sync with other team members. What is the cause of this communications gap?","options":["Daily standup meetings were not held or enforced","The communications management plan has not been developed","The project status dashboard has not been updated","The project sprint board has not been updated"],"answer":"Daily standup meetings were not held or enforced","explanation":"The daily standup meeting is where team members are able to present their issues and say what they are working on during that day."},
    {"question":"M3Q38 A team is working on a hybrid project. Due to the different interpretations of the project requirements, the deliverables are not aligned with the expectations of the customers. They say the product at delivery is failing to perform correctly. What steps should the project manager have taken to prevent this?","options":["Update the project management plan in order to get back on track","Submit a change request to adjust the project scope","Ensure the team receives continuous feedback from customers","Ensure the team understands all additional project requirements"],"answer":"Ensure the team receives continuous feedback from customers","explanation":"The team should get continuous feedback from the customers to ensure there are building the correct product for the customer. Feedback should be given throughout the project."},
    {"question":"M3Q39 While reviewing the issues log, the Project Manager notices that tasks assigned to three team members have an SPI of .7. What should be done?","options":["Notify the members to complete the tasks quickly in order to avoid introducing extra project time.","Work with the team members to review the tasks and decide on strategies for solutions.","Ask the team members to explain why tasks were delayed and how they will get back on schedule.","Document the issue and escalate to the project sponsor."],"answer":"Work with the team members to review the tasks and decide on strategies for solutions.","explanation":"The Project Manager needs to review the activities with the team members and identify solutions."},
    {"question":"M3Q40 A project manager is working with a project team. The team has agreed on a solution to a major issue and is about to implement the solution. In what phase of development is the team in?","options":["Storming","Performing","Forming","Norming"],"answer":"Norming","explanation":"In the norming phase, the team has come to a solution on issues they had in the storming phase. They can then start the work next in the performing stage."},
    {"question":"M3Q41 A new software development project is having an issue where key stakeholders are given requirements that are opposites of each other. This has led to a delay in the planning of the project. The project manager has set up a meeting with the stakeholders to resolve this. What should the project manager do in this meeting?","options":["Inform the two stakeholders that this must be settled immediately or the project will be delayed","Work with the two stakeholders and select a requirement that is more cost-effective","Inform the two stakeholders that both requirements can be implemented","Work with the two stakeholders to understand the main issue and select a requirement that is best for the value the project will deliver"],"answer":"Work with the two stakeholders to understand the main issue and select a requirement that is best for the value the project will deliver","explanation":"The best option here would be to work with the stakeholders and find the requirement that best benefits all projects and not just something that is more cost-effective or satisfies one of them."},
    {"question":"M3Q42 A project team has fixed a software error on the company PMIS. This error may occur in other projects that may happen in the future. Which document should be updated to ensure this error is fixed going forward?","options":["Communication management plan.","The risk report.","The lessons learned register.","The issue log."],"answer":"The lessons learned register.","explanation":"The lessons learned register can be used for future projects to help avoid past project issues."},
    {"question":"M3Q43 A project manager overhears a conversation with two team members that a component will likely fail the customer's acceptance due to its performance. The project manager didn't think it could happen. What should the Project Manager do?","options":["Update the risk register with the new risk and assess its possibility","Have the members work with the customers and implement a solution before the component fails.","Inform the team members you overheard them and then explain to the sponsor why this may happen.","Have the other team members confront the members and resolve the issue."],"answer":"Update the risk register with the new risk and assess its possibility","explanation":"The Project Manager needs to proactively approach this. By updating the risk register and assessing the risk, the project will be able to handle the risk."},
    {"question":"M3Q44 A project manager has just gotten a job in an organization moving towards agile methods. The agile team claims that the organization's key stakeholders think agile methods are chaotic and will not work. This has led to less engagement by them. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Have the stakeholders prioritize the product backlog","Inform the stakeholders that agile methods produce more valuable deliverables than traditional","Train the stakeholders on the values of agile processes and artifacts","Inform the stakeholders that agile projects will allow deliverables to be delivered quicker"],"answer":"Train the stakeholders on the values of agile processes and artifacts","explanation":"The best option would be to train the stakeholders on the main value of agile practices. This will allow them to see if this is best for the organization."},
    {"question":"M3Q45 During a major company development project, a team member is having an issue conducting some of the work. The team member says working with the other member's team is difficult and the work is becoming more complex. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Inform the project sponsor of this issue in the potential delays","Reassign the team member to work that best suits his skills","Provide coaching and skill development to the team member as the project is progressing","Speak with the HR department to replace the team member with someone more suitable for the project"],"answer":"Provide coaching and skill development to the team member as the project is progressing","explanation":"One of the most important tasks of being a project manager is to ensure members have the right training to conduct the work on the project."},
    {"question":"M3Q46 An organization has starting to deliver projects using a hybrid approach. Some members are very knowledgeable about agile and some have never used it before. The inconsistent knowledge is leading the agile parts to fall behind. What should the manager do in this situation?","options":["Conduct the project using a traditional method only.","Allow team members that are not knowledgeable in agile to only work on the traditional parts of the project","Research and budget for agile and traditional methods to be taught to the entire team","Implement a schedule change to account for the delay."],"answer":"Research and budget for agile and traditional methods to be taught to the entire team","explanation":"It is important to have consistent implementation of project management methods. This can only be done if the team has the same knowledge about the different methods."},
    {"question":"M3Q47 An approved change request to fix a major component on a deliverable has failed. When the change request was implemented, it failed and caused a larger issue on the project. What plan should the project manager use to escalate this major issue?","options":["Stakeholder engagement plan.","Communications management plan.","Change management plan.","Issue management plan."],"answer":"Communications management plan.","explanation":"The communications management plan will detail how the project communications will occur. This includes how to escalate issues."},
    {"question":"M3Q48 There are concerns about the cost risk of adding a vendor to complete a major section of the project. The sponsor informs the project manager he will not approve any cost increase in the future. What type of contract should be used?","options":["A cost plus fixed fee contract.","A cost plus incentive fee contract.","A time and material contract.","A firm fixed price contract."],"answer":"A firm fixed price contract.","explanation":"A firm fixed price contract is a type of contract where the buyer pays the seller a set amount for all work performed. This contract has the lowest risk for the buyer."},
    {"question":"M3Q49 A major application redesign hybrid project has just been completed and the project manager is about to close the project. What should the project manager do during closing?","options":["Have the team conduct a final inspection of the product","Ensure all items on the product backlog is completed","Meet with the project sponsor to get acceptance of the deliverables","Ensure the product and knowledge is transferred to operation"],"answer":"Ensure the product and knowledge is transferred to operation","explanation":"During closing, you would transfer the knowledge and product. You would then release the team and transfer the project report."},
    {"question":"M3Q50 A project manager working on an agile project has notice one team member spending a few hours each day working on their personal tasks. The project manager informs the member to stop doing this and only work on the sprint. What problem solving method is this?","options":["Compromising","Collaborating","Smoothing","Forcing"],"answer":"Forcing","explanation":"This method is forcing since the PM is telling the team member what to do with no other options or input from the team member."},
    {"question":"M3Q51 A few new risks for a project are identified by two senior team members. These risks could affect the overall project schedule. What should the project manager do next with these risks?","options":["Review the risk report.","Refer to the schedule management plan and the risk report.","Review the organizational process assets and risk register.","Add risks to the risk register and then analyze how they will impact the project."],"answer":"Add risks to the risk register and then analyze how they will impact the project.","explanation":"The first step would be to update the risk register and then analyze the new risks."},
    {"question":"M3Q52 The Project Manager provided training for the entire team on the specifics of the company processes that the project supports. A few months later, new team members were added and lacked the needed training. This has caused conflict on the project. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Ask a senior member to conduct the training.","Provide a second round of training to all new members.","Inform the new members they will learn as the project is progressing from senior members","Have the new team members seek help from senior members."],"answer":"Provide a second round of training to all new members.","explanation":"It is the PM's responsibility to make sure that the new members are adequately trained. This method provides that training."},
    {"question":"M3Q53 The project manager is working on an agile project that requires complex software development. Two team members are having a hard time on the sprint with the work. They ask the project manager for help. What should the project manager do?","options":["Tell the two team members to ask senior team members to help them","Tell them to look up what training they need online and the project will cover the cost","Coach them on finding the best way for them to learn this information quickly and then follow-up","Inform them you will move those complex tasks to more knowledgeable members"],"answer":"Coach them on finding the best way for them to learn this information quickly and then follow-up","explanation":"The best solution here would be to coach the team member and get them the required knowledge as quickly as possible so as to minimize the effects on the project."},
    {"question":"M3Q54 At the start of project execution, the project manager finds out that a team member will be unavailable due to a medical emergency. This might cause a delay to the project schedule for one month. The project manager has requested a new temporary resource from the project management office. What should the project manager do?","options":["Stop the project until the team member returns","Extend the project schedule by one month","Ask the project sponsor for an additional team member to replace the absent member","Update the risk register"],"answer":"Update the risk register","explanation":"Since the team member being held might cause a delay to the project schedule, it would be best to add this as a risk to the risk register."},
    {"question":"M3Q55 An agile Project iteration just ended. A team member tells the project manager that a task was done during the iteration and was implemented incorrectly, causing the customer to reject the feature. The Project Manager wants to prevent this scenario in the future. When is an appropriate time to discuss this issue?","options":["During the next iteration planning meeting.","In the iteration review meeting.","In the next daily standup meeting.","During the retrospective."],"answer":"During the retrospective.","explanation":"The retrospective allows issues identified and discussed in a timely fashion along with ideas for improvement by the agile team."},
    {"question":"M5Q56 A senior sponsor is discussing the complexity of project deliverables with the Project Manager two weeks before the hybrid project is initiated. The sponsor feels the project will fail to produce the deliverable in an adequate time. The Project Manager wants to ensure that the deliverables are accurate. What should the project manager do next?","options":["Revise the project charter.","Conduct a feasibility study of the project deliverables","Documented in the issue log for later review.","Identify threats and document them in the risk register."],"answer":"Conduct a feasibility study of the project deliverables","explanation":"The feasibility study will support the business case to begin a new project."},
    {"question":"M5Q57 While working on a complicated project, team members are often having discussions with each other and customers. Some of these communications are being done offline without the knowledge of the project manager. This is leading to a major communication issue. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Allow the team to keep having off-line discussions","Host a meeting with the team to understand why these communications are happening and take the necessary actions to resolve this issue","Have the project sponsor speak with the customers and the team members","Inform the team to follow the communication management plan only"],"answer":"Host a meeting with the team to understand why these communications are happening and take the necessary actions to resolve this issue","explanation":"Since this is leading to a communication issue, the project manager should take action to solve this problem. The best option here would be to meet with the team and understand why this is happening, then implement the solution."},
    {"question":"M5Q58 An agile project has completed nine iterations with two releases. While some stakeholders are participating, others are not. Some of the stakeholders claim this new product may decrease the value that the company is offering to its customers and the company may lose market share. What should the project manager have done at the beginning of the project to ensure this doesn't happen again?","options":["Try to have all the stakeholders give inputs into the design of the new product","Meet with each individual stakeholder and explain the benefits of the project","Have the product owner speak with the stakeholders to explain the benefits of the new product","Create the project management plan before getting the project initiated"],"answer":"Try to have all the stakeholders give inputs into the design of the new product","explanation":"When a project is first initiated, it is important to have all stakeholders involved understand the main benefits of the project before the project work starts."},
    {"question":"M5Q59 Place Tuckman's Five Stages to a situation","options":["Members come to an agreement","Team is release","The team is learning each other names","One member doesn't agree with another member advice"],"answer":{"Members come to an agreement":"Norming","Team is release":"Adjourning","The team is learning each other names":"Forming","One member doesn't agree with another member advice":"Storming"},"explanation":"Members come to an agreement ? Norming, Team is release ? Adjourning, The team is learning each other names ? Forming, One member doesn't agree with another member advice ? Storming","isMatching":true},
    {"question":"M5Q60 Match the risk response with its description.","options":["Have the program management team, work on fixing the component","Removing a work package from the WBS","Informing other project managers of a new method to create a function"],"answer":{"Have the program management team, work on fixing the component":"Escalate","Removing a work package from the WBS":"Avoid","Informing other project managers of a new method to create a function":"Share"},"explanation":"Have the program management team, work on fixing the component ? Escalate, Removing a work package from the WBS ? Avoid, Informing other project managers of a new method to create a function ? Share","isMatching":true}
];
const mock4Data = [
    {"question":"M4Q1 A quality management plan states that the project deliverables must be reviewed for quality at least ten days before the customer can inspect for acceptance. Two deliverables have failed the quality requirement. What should the Project Manager do?","options":["Alert the project sponsor.","Conduct feasibility of an internal audit of the project.","Use a cause-and-effect diagram.","Update the quality management plan."],"answer":"Use a cause-and-effect diagram.","explanation":"Cause-and-effect diagrams break down the causes of the problem into groups. This will help to identify the main or root cause."},
    {"question":"M4Q2 A project manager is managing a team that has had issues and now has implemented a resolution. The team is currently working to complete the deliverables. In what phase of development is the team?","options":["Building","Performing","Norming","Working"],"answer":"Performing","explanation":"Once the team members start working on the actual work, they have moved to the performing phase."},
    {"question":"M4Q3 While working on a construction project, one of the vendors is having an issue delivering a major component of the project. The vendor wants to replace that component with a similar working component. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Use expert judgment and determine if this alternative component is acceptable","Replace the vendor with someone that could get the correct component","Tell the vendor it's okay to replace the component","Instruct the vendor to use the original component even if it delays the schedule"],"answer":"Use expert judgment and determine if this alternative component is acceptable","explanation":"This option here before taking action against the vendor would be to use an expert to determine if this component would be suitable for the project before rejecting it."},
    {"question":"M4Q4 While working on a software development agile project, a team member is having difficulty with some of the work. The project manager has done some research and has determined that this is due to the lack of knowledge by the team member. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Instruct the team member on how to fix the problem","Replace the team member with someone with the correct knowledge","Meet with the project team and have them come up with a solution to solve the issue","Reassign the team member to another part of the project"],"answer":"Meet with the project team and have them come up with a solution to solve the issue","explanation":"The best option here would be to meet with the team and bring the issue to their attention. The best solutions come from a self-organizing, self-directed team. The team should be a generalizing specialist that can help each other out when problems arise."},
    {"question":"M4Q5 The project sponsor has requested a major change to one of the deliverables. The team agrees the change should be implemented but disagrees on the method of implementation. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Meet with the change control Board and have them determine how to implement the change.","Inform the sponsor that the complex changes will require more time to implement.","Meet with the team members to brainstorm ideas on how to implement the change.","Submit the change to the change control Board for approval."],"answer":"Meet with the team members to brainstorm ideas on how to implement the change.","explanation":"If there is a disagreement on the team, the project manager should meet with the team to resolve the issues before moving on."},
    {"question":"M4Q6 A project team is inspecting over 500 products and has selected 50 products to evaluate against the quality metrics. What is the team doing?","options":["Performing inspections.","Utilizing statistical sampling.","Undertaking a manage quality measure.","Conducting audits."],"answer":"Utilizing statistical sampling.","explanation":"Statistical sampling involves choosing part of a population of interest for inspection."},
    {"question":"M4Q7 The project manager and the team is working on a hybrid network upgrade project and have completed the scope statement. A senior stakeholder has informed them that he wants the project to be completed 20% sooner than anticipated. What should the project manager do next?","options":["Collect requirements for the requirements documentation","Decompose the deliverables into work packages for the work breakdown structure (WBS)","Complete the project schedule and budget","Assign team members to work on the scope"],"answer":"Decompose the deliverables into work packages for the work breakdown structure (WBS)","explanation":"Once the scope statement is made, the next step would be to decompose those deliverables in the scope statement into work packages to create a work breakdown structure (WBS)."},
    {"question":"M4Q8 While working on a product development hybrid project, the team identified a major issue that could lead to the complete failure of the product. What should the project manager do to resolve this issue?","options":["Notify the project sponsor and ask for a solution","Modify the scope statement to resolve the issue","Work with the team to brainstorm a solution and implement the solution","Add this issue to the risk register"],"answer":"Work with the team to brainstorm a solution and implement the solution","explanation":"The main objective here would be to resolve the issue by working with the team to come up with practical solutions and then implement the solutions."},
    {"question":"M4Q9 A project manager is working on a hybrid software development project to create a new CRM. The team is currently working on the first sprint when a few team members want to spend time checking the codes instead of finishing the sprint to conduct a sprint review and this may delay the sprint. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Inform the team members that this is not the goal of the Sprint","Inform the product owner of what is happening on the project and why the Sprint will be delayed","Tell the few members not to do this and to complete the sprint","Have them finished checking the codes, then address this issue during the retrospective."],"answer":"Have them finished checking the codes, then address this issue during the retrospective.","explanation":"On an agile project is best to let the team be self-directed and self-organizing. If this leads to issues then it should be brought up in the next retrospectives to be dealt what."},
    {"question":"M4Q10 Due to severe weather, the project has been delayed by over two months. The project manager has requested a change to increase the project schedule but was denied by the change control board. The board claimed the project manager did not follow the right procedures. What should the project manager do next?","options":["Informed the team, they will need to work overtime to complete the project on time.","Review the project schedule to determine how else the project can get back on track.","Review the change management plan.","Inform the sponsor that the project will be delayed by two months."],"answer":"Review the change management plan.","explanation":"The project manager should first review the change management plan to understand what was the procedure that should have been followed when requesting a change. If any procedure was not followed correctly, the change could be resubmitted using the correct procedure."},
    {"question":"M4Q11 The project sponsor has found a website that claims some of the materials being used in the new product can lead to health risks for people using the product. The sponsor then requested a change to remove this material. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Implement the change by removing the hazardous material.","Stop the project until this can be resolved.","Review the change request and determine how it will impact the project.","Inform the sponsor the project cannot stop at this point due to its near completion."],"answer":"Review the change request and determine how it will impact the project.","explanation":"Even though this may seem like something that should be attended to right away, it is just a 'claim' on a website and you will need to assess it this claim is correct or not."},
    {"question":"M4Q12 While working on an agile project, a stakeholder has informed the project manager that the sprint review meeting was a waste of time and will not be attending the next meeting. Stakeholder feels their time is best spent on other tasks. How should the project manager handle this conflict?","options":["Tell the stakeholder it is mandatory to attend these meetings since he is a stakeholder","Review the benefits of the sprint review meeting with the stakeholder and show him the value","Ask the team to only invite the stakeholder if his input is needed","Tell the stakeholder it is okay not to attend the next sprint review meeting"],"answer":"Review the benefits of the sprint review meeting with the stakeholder and show him the value","explanation":"On an agile project, always try to be an agile advocate promoting the benefits of following the agile principles. This includes mentoring, coaching and teaching agile principles to all stakeholders."},
    {"question":"M4Q13 A project manager has noticed that the CPI of the project is .7 and the SPI is 1.0. What should the project manager do next in order to correct this project?","options":["Release a few team members to lower the project cost","Implement schedule crashing","Submit a change request to the change control board to increase the project budget","Submit a change request to the control board to increase the project schedule"],"answer":"Submit a change request to the change control board to increase the project budget","explanation":"Since this project is over budget by 30% (CPI of .7) it would be best to increase the cost baseline. Releasing team members can affect the schedule."},
    {"question":"M4Q14 A recently started project has just been notified of a new government regulation that requires a new permit to build a component of the project. The permit will take an additional month to get. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Have the team assess if the permit is actually needed","Update the risk register","Add an additional month to the project schedule","Implement a change request to update the schedule"],"answer":"Implement a change request to update the schedule","explanation":"The project manager should update the schedule by getting an approved change request. This will ensure the project has enough time to get the required permit."},
    {"question":"M4Q15 A project manager has worked with the sponsor to create preliminary scope, preliminary schedule, preliminary budget, and assumptions to complete the project charter. What should the project manager do next?","options":["Start planning the project","Recruit project team.","Get a budget sign-off","Get the charter approved"],"answer":"Get the charter approved","explanation":"After the charter is created, it will need to get approved before the project manager can start planning the project."},
    {"question":"M4Q16 A Project Manager is working on a hybrid project with team members around the world and a fixed budget and schedule. Managing Changes to the project scope will be important for the success of the project. What should the Project Manager do to achieve this goal?","options":["Confirm that customers do not directly interact with the development team leads.","Confirm that changes go through the formal approval process.","Confirm that daily stand-ups occur with all development teams.","Confirm that the development team leads generate detailed requirements."],"answer":"Confirm that changes go through the formal approval process.","explanation":"Following the formal change control process is the best way to control unnecessary project changes."},
    {"question":"M4Q17 The project manager has noticed on an agile project that team members are not engaging and seem to be discouraged. This may lead to delays later in the project. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Add an additional cost to the project budget to keep the team motivated.","Inform the team they should look at ways to keep themselves motivated","Remove team members that are not engaging on the project","Review the company methods to reward employees for work"],"answer":"Review the company methods to reward employees for work","explanation":"The best course of action would be to find ways to keep them motivated by finding a system of rewarding them."},
    {"question":"M4Q18 A new agile software development project is conducting its first sprint. During the daily stand-up meeting, a team member is very disrespectful to other team members. He claims if the work cannot get done his way, he will speak to the product owner himself. What actions should the project manager take to resolve this issue? (Choose 3)","options":["Replace the team member","Review the ground rules signed in the team charter","Have the team help the member resolve the issue","Coach the team to resolve issues themselves","Meet for a one-on-one discussion with the team member","Discuss these issues with the team member during the meeting with all members presented"],"answer":["Meet for a one-on-one discussion with the team member","Review the ground rules signed in the team charter","Coach the team to resolve issues themselves"],"explanation":"The best action would be to meet with the member one-on-one, review the ground rules with the team and coach the team to help resolve this issue.","isMultipleChoice":true},
    {"question":"M4Q19 A few key stakeholders are very upset that the performance reports for the project are outdated. This has led management to believe the project is behind schedule. What should the project manager do to ensure the performance reports are updated?","options":["Reassign a team member on the project to update the report","Update the performance report and send it to the company internal network","Implement a system to keep the report updated regularly and send them to the stakeholders","Implement a change request to extend the project schedule to add the time needed to update the report."],"answer":"Implement a system to keep the report updated regularly and send them to the stakeholders","explanation":"The project manager should update the report and implement a system to ensure it is done regularly."},
    {"question":"M4Q20 A hybrid project is about 50% complete with a CPI of 1.0, then after 55% the CPI.95, then after 60% the CPI is .90. What should the project manager do first about this?","options":["Have a meeting with the sponsor to inform him that the project is progressing well","Have a meeting with the team to determine why the trend is going over the budget","Implement a change request to get more funds to complete the project on budget","Calculate the EAC, then implement a change request"],"answer":"Have a meeting with the team to determine why the trend is going over the budget","explanation":"The PM should meet with the to understand why the project is trending over budget before implementing a change request."},
    {"question":"M4Q21 A Project Manager is working on a product redesign project. A few customers have been submitting changes to modify the project scope very often. The scope was already approved by the sponsor. What should the Project Manager do next?","options":["Give the scope changes to the project team for approval.","Review the scope management plan.","Meet with the customers and inform them scope is already approved.","Ask the project sponsor if the scope could be modified."],"answer":"Review the scope management plan.","explanation":"The first step the project manager should take should be to review the scope management plan to determine how the scope could be changed. The scope management plan will outline how to create, manage, and change the scope."},
    {"question":"M4Q22 A project manager has completed the work performance report. In the report, the SPI is 1.2 and the CPI is.6. Which of the following statements are true? (Choose 2)?","options":["Progressing well","Behind schedule.","Ahead of schedule.","Under budget","Over budget"],"answer":["Ahead of schedule.","Over budget"],"explanation":"CPI less than 1 = over budget, SPI over 1 = ahead of schedule.","isMultipleChoice":true},
    {"question":"M4Q23 After a company has started using agile methods from traditional, a few senior stakeholders have doubt that this new method will add any value to project delivery. The stakeholder claims early delivery will only slow down development time and make customers upset. What should the project manager do to resolve this?","options":["Inform all team members to use traditional methods going forward","Hire a consultant to coach the team and stakeholders on the agile value","Conduct a face-to-face session with the stakeholders and demonstrate how agile works and its values","Create and send an email to all senior stakeholders outlining the benefits of agile"],"answer":"Conduct a face-to-face session with the stakeholders and demonstrate how agile works and its values","explanation":"As part of being an agile project manager, it is important to ensure that you promote and coach stakeholders on the importance of agile principles and values."},
    {"question":"M4Q24 A project team has met up for the first time to create a team charter. After the charter is created, a member calls you to say he is unhappy with the charter and would like changes. If not, he will not work on the project. What should the project manager do first?","options":["Meet with the member and understand what is the issue and what went wrong during the meeting","Tell other members to speak with this member and resolve this issue","Meet with the other members to find out what happened and how to fix this issue","Remove this member from the project"],"answer":"Meet with the member and understand what is the issue and what went wrong during the meeting","explanation":"It would be best to ensure to meet with the team member to understand what exactly is the issue finding the root cause of it."},
    {"question":"M4Q25 Two team members have informed the project manager that a component on the project will not work as planned and will delay the project. The project manager was not expecting this issue. What should the project manager do?","options":["Implement the correct risk response from the risk register","Have a meeting with the team members and update the issue management plan","Have a meeting with the team members and update the issue log","Follow the communication management plan and update the risk register"],"answer":"Have a meeting with the team members and update the issue log","explanation":"The best action would be to meet with the member and then update the issue log."},
    {"question":"M4Q26 An organization has just appointed a new project manager to a company critical project. The project will redesign the organization's only product. If the project fails, the organization could suffer a large loss of market share. What should the project manager do to ensure the project is successful?","options":["Ensure plans are realistic, deliverables are reviewed, and the work is monitored","The project charter was done with a realistic budget and schedule","Ensure the budget is adequate for the project so that the project can be staff correctly","Hire the correct staff and ensure communication reports are done correctly"],"answer":"Ensure plans are realistic, deliverables are reviewed, and the work is monitored","explanation":"The main function of a project manager is to ensure plans are made correctly, the work is done on time and on budget and someone is monitoring the project."},
    {"question":"M4Q27 While managing a technical IT project, two team members had issues uploading the software to the server. They each solved the problem using methods they found on the internet. This may cause issues going forward if team members are fixing issues by themselves. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Have both members work with each other going forward in a one-on-one setting","Remove both members from the team and inform the other not to do this again.","Have both members attend a meeting with you and inform them this is not to be done again","Have the entire team meet regularly to discuss issues and solutions they might have"],"answer":"Have the entire team meet regularly to discuss issues and solutions they might have","explanation":"The main issue here is the team members are communicating. The way to fix this would be to have the team meet regularly to resolve the issue."},
    {"question":"M4Q28 While upgrading a network component in the company finance department, a project manager realizes that the component might not be approved by the sponsor. What should the project manager do first?","options":["Have the sponsor implement a change request to fix the component","Meet with the sponsor and ask what could be removed to fix the component","Reach out to the PMO and ask for guidance","Review the project management plan, acceptance criteria and the component"],"answer":"Review the project management plan, acceptance criteria and the component","explanation":"The best actions would be to review the plans, acceptance criteria and the component to understand what has gone wrong before taking any action."},
    {"question":"M4Q29 During a hybrid project, two teams, one using traditional and the other using hybrid, are creating critical components for the project. The two teams are working in parallel and depend on each other for information. You came to realize the two teams are not communicating and this could lead to a delay in the project. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Remove both teams and replace them with new teams that work with each other","Have each team submit the issue to you, then implement a solution based on the issues","Allow them to keep working, as they will resolve it themselves","Have both teams meet to discuss the problem while you coach them to implement a solution to any issues"],"answer":"Have both teams meet to discuss the problem while you coach them to implement a solution to any issues","explanation":"It would be best to have the teams resolve the issue themselves while you coach them."},
    {"question":"M4Q30 An organization has just started its first agile project. Due to a lack of experience with agile methods, the project seems to be very chaotic, with the team not knowing what to build and the constant adding to the scope is something that the team doesn't understand. What should the manager implement to fix these issues? (Choose 2)","options":["Definition of Done","Acceptance criteria","Business Case","Change control board","Agile project charter","Project management plan with a clear scope statement"],"answer":["Definition of Done","Agile project charter"],"explanation":"If the agile project is lacking direction and people don't know what the project is really about, a definition of done and agile charter will need to be completed.","isMultipleChoice":true},
    {"question":"M4Q31 The project manager has just been assigned a project where the customer is not sure what he wants the deliverable to look like or how it will function. What would be the best way to work with this customer?","options":["Implement an agile method with strict changes to the product backlog","Inform the customer that changes are not allowed after the project plan has been approved","Implement an agile method with a product owner and sprint review meetings","Implement a predictive method with a strict change control process"],"answer":"Implement an agile method with a product owner and sprint review meetings","explanation":"The best approach would require the customer to change the requirement as needed and lots of product reviews throughout the project. This would accomplish using an agile approach."},
    {"question":"M4Q32 A project manager working on a critical project has been told that if the project fails the company can endure extreme hardship going forward. The company has conducted a similar project many times before. What should the project manager do to ensure this project is successful?","options":["Closely manage the scope to ensure no scope creep","Work with external vendors to ensure work is done correctly","Engage the stakeholders and motivate the team","Keep a close eye on the cost and budget"],"answer":"Engage the stakeholders and motivate the team","explanation":"In this scenario, it would be best to keep the stakeholders engage and motivate the team. Since the company has conducted this project many times before, there would be no need to closely manage the cost, budget, or scope more than keeping the team motivated and engaging stakeholders."},
    {"question":"M4Q33 A project that should have been 65 percent complete by now is 72 percent complete. The total project budget is US$110,000 and the actual cost to date is US$85,000. What is the schedule performance index (SPI) and cost performance index (CPI) for this project?","options":["The SPI is 1.2, and the CPI is 0.97.","The SPI is 1.3, and the CPI of 0.93.","The SPI is 1.11, and the CPI is .93.","The SPI is 0.96, and the CPI is 1.11."],"answer":"The SPI is 1.11, and the CPI is .93.","explanation":"EV = 0.72 * $110,000 = $79,200. PV = 0.65 * $110,000 = $71,500. AC = $85,000. SPI = EV/PV = $79,200/$71,500 = 1.11. CPI = EV/AC = $79,200/$85,000 = .93."},
    {"question":"M4Q34 While working on a complex technical IT project, the team has implemented a solution to an issue that has now made the product ready for production. One functional manager has insisted that he should be the sole person to determine whether to put the product into production. What should the project manager do first in this situation?","options":["Schedule a meeting with the functional manager to discuss this issue","Inform the functional manager only the team can determine if the product can be put into production","Update the resource management plan to list the functional manager as the person to approve the product","Meet with the project sponsor and ask if this is correct"],"answer":"Schedule a meeting with the functional manager to discuss this issue","explanation":"The first course of action should be to meet with the functional manager to better understand this issue and how to resolve it."},
    {"question":"M4Q35 A new team member has joined an agile project team. Over the last two iterations, the team member has been consistently late on the delivery. How should the project manager handle this situation?","options":["Meet and coach the team member to improve their performance","Replace the team member with someone more productive","Have the team member to speak with the project team for help","Inform the project management office of the situation and seek guidance"],"answer":"Meet and coach the team member to improve their performance","explanation":"A project manager should be coaching and mentoring the project team in order to increase their productivity or provide adequate training."},
    {"question":"M4Q36 A project manager manages a diversified global team for a mission-critical project. The project is about building safety devices for construction projects. What should the project manager focus on to ensure project success?","options":["Ensure the project schedule and budget is monitored closely","Ensure the project scope never changes throughout the project","Ensure regulatory and safety guidelines are documented in meeting throughout the project","Remove team members that may cause communication issues"],"answer":"Ensure regulatory and safety guidelines are documented in meeting throughout the project","explanation":"Since this project is about safety, it is best to ensure that all regulatory and safety guidelines are met throughout the project."},
    {"question":"M4Q37 An organization has informed the project manager that the new product development project needs to be pushed out to the customers within eight months. The project manager alerts the sponsor that the estimated time is 36 months for completion. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Hire additional resources and conduct fast tracking and crashing to complete it sooner","Change the project to agile methods and utilize a minimum viable product approach","Change the project to an agile method ensure the product backlog does not change","Change the project to a hybrid method and ensure the team understand the deadline"],"answer":"Change the project to agile methods and utilize a minimum viable product approach","explanation":"The best solution here would be to use agile methods with a minimum viable product. This will allow the project to output a product quicker."},
    {"question":"M4Q38 A project plan was approved and the project has been executed. Halfway through the project, the team has met the project manager for a project update. The project manager notices that the issue log the team has is different than the issue log he has. What can the project manager do to resolve this problem?","options":["Inform the team that the issue log is incorrect","Have the team explain why their issue log is different","Update the communications management plan","Add this to the risk register"],"answer":"Update the communications management plan","explanation":"This is a communications issue between the team and the project manager, so the project manager should update the communication management plan to fix the communication issues."},
    {"question":"M4Q39 While working on a hybrid product development project, a senior stakeholder has informed the project manager that he would like the project terminated instantly. If not, he will work with senior management to ensure everyone is terminated from the organization if the project does not stop right away. What should the project manager do first in this situation?","options":["Schedule a one-on-one meeting with this senior stakeholder to learn more about this issue","Ask for a meeting with the organization's senior management to report this stakeholder","Inform the team and tell them to be prepared to stop the project","Immediately schedule a meeting with the project sponsor to update him on the situation"],"answer":"Schedule a one-on-one meeting with this senior stakeholder to learn more about this issue","explanation":"The best course of action would be to meet with this stakeholder to better understand the issues and then come up with a resolution for them."},
    {"question":"M4Q40 A project manager has just been assigned to a large development project. To complete the initiation, the project manager will need to come up with the budget and schedule for the project. What should the project manager use to prepare this information?","options":["The PMO estimated time and schedule","Reviews of the resource management plan","Historical Data from previous projects that are similar to this project","Meetings with the team members to estimate the budget and schedule"],"answer":"Historical Data from previous projects that are similar to this project","explanation":"Since this project is in the initiating phase, they will not be in project plans to refer to. The best option would be to use historical data from previous projects."},
    {"question":"M4Q41 The final deliverable of the project is almost complete. What should the project manager do to completely finish the execution of the project?","options":["Have the project sponsor accept the final deliverable","Update the scope management plan","Review the stakeholder engagement plan","Release the project team"],"answer":"Have the project sponsor accept the final deliverable","explanation":"Once a deliverable has been completed, the next step would be to have the deliverable formally accepted generally by the project sponsor."},
    {"question":"M4Q42 A project has been approved by two senior managers within the organization. Once the project enters into the planning phase, one manager informs the project manager that the plan is not in line with his original expectations. In contrast, the other manager says that it does. What should the project manager do next time to ensure this situation does not happen again?","options":["Ensure stakeholders write down their ideas and shared them with each other during initiating","Involve the two senior managers during the planning of the project","Review the project charter after it was approved","Ensure all stakeholders understand the main objectives of the project during initiating"],"answer":"Ensure all stakeholders understand the main objectives of the project during initiating","explanation":"The best option here would be to ensure all the stakeholders understand the main objectives during initiation."},
    {"question":"M4Q43 During the course of an agile project, a senior stakeholder has informed the project manager that the minimum viable product (MVP) is not meeting their expectations and the project needs to be stopped and fixed right away. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Review the MVP to understand what has been completed","Meet with the team to discuss risk management","Review the product backlog to see what features were not done yet","Perform a stakeholder analysis to understand their expectations"],"answer":"Perform a stakeholder analysis to understand their expectations","explanation":"Since there is a mismatch between their expectations and what is getting done from the project, it would be best to him analyze what the stakeholders are expecting from the project before producing any more work."},
    {"question":"M4Q44 An organization has just implemented an agile project to create a proof-of-concept product for its release to the market. A senior manager has informed the project manager that timing is the most critical part of this. What should the project manager emphasize the most on this project?","options":["Strict scope change process","A project management plan the team can follow","Strict cost change processes","Working with the team to implement quicker iterations"],"answer":"Working with the team to implement quicker iterations","explanation":"Agile projects are great to release products quicker to the market. The project manager should emphasize working with the team to get these implementations done quicker."},
    {"question":"M4Q45 While working on a product development project, a vendor has informed the project manager that a few of the components would be late to deliver. After doing some analysis, you realize this will extend the project significantly. What should the project manager do first?","options":["Start analyzing a replacement for the vendor","Determine if the team can make the component internally","Review the contract to see what legal actions can be taken against the vendor","Meet with the vendor to determine why it's late and what solutions can be implemented"],"answer":"Meet with the vendor to determine why it's late and what solutions can be implemented","explanation":"The best course of action would be to meet with the vendor to better understand what's causing it to be delayed if the vendor can do anything about this issue."},
    {"question":"M4Q46 An organization wants to develop a new product in a new market space. They're not too sure about what are the product's main functions and its overall looks. What should the project manager recommend to the stakeholders of this project?","options":["A predictive approach with stakeholder engagement","A hybrid approach with a set project management plan","An agile approach with frequent sprint review meetings","Hybrid approach with half being agile and the other half being predictive"],"answer":"An agile approach with frequent sprint review meetings","explanation":"When the scope is not knowing, it is best to implement an agile approach to the scope could change as the project progresses."},
    {"question":"M4Q47 While working on an agile project, the organization's compliance department has informed the project manager that an agile approach will not be suitable for the company's main industry. They have requested for the project to be implemented in a traditional approach. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Ask the product manager to speak with the compliance department","Have the project implement traditional methods to meet compliance","Meet with the compliance department and informed them of the benefits of using agile methods","Inform the compliance department you take their inputs once the project is done"],"answer":"Meet with the compliance department and informed them of the benefits of using agile methods","explanation":"The best option here would be to meet with the compliance department to outline agile practices and show them how agile could meet regulatory compliance."},
    {"question":"M4Q48 An agile team working on a software development project is complaining about communication issues with each other. A few members are not too sure what other members are working on. This has led to a delay is within the Sprint. What should the project manager recommend to resolve this issue?","options":["Inform the team to use Kanban","Inform the team to do the daily standup multiple times a day","Have the team do retrospectives before and after each sprint","Have the team work on smaller sprints"],"answer":"Inform the team to use Kanban","explanation":"The best option here would be to use Kanban since it will be able to display what work is getting done in easy to view format."},
    {"question":"M4Q49 While working on a technical IT project, a few team members informed the project manager that one task was taking 20% longer than expected. This project is very time-sensitive. What should the project manager do about the situation?","options":["Inform the team members they will need to completed faster","Implement the change request to increase the budget to crash the project","Implement the change request immediately to extend the project schedule","Meet with the team member to understand why this happened and find a way to compress the schedule if needed"],"answer":"Meet with the team member to understand why this happened and find a way to compress the schedule if needed","explanation":"The best option here would be to meet with the team to understand why this took place and then work with the team to come up with a solution to compress the schedule and get the work done quicker."},
    {"question":"M4Q50 An agile project team is having difficulty communicating and maintaining a trusting relationship. This has led to major schedule delays. You have already implemented a team charter that does not seem to be working. What should the project manager do to solve this?","options":["Inform the team that they should meet more often and work together to resolve this issue","Have the project sponsor to speak with the team","Set up a meeting with the team to discuss this issue and different solutions","Inform the team that if this issue is not fixed, members will be replaced"],"answer":"Set up a meeting with the team to discuss this issue and different solutions","explanation":"In this situation, the best choice but to schedule a meeting with the team to better understand this issue and how this issue can be resolved."},
    {"question":"M4Q51 A project manager has just been assigned to an ongoing project utilizing virtual teams. The virtual team seems to be following a chaotic process that has led to an argument between members. What should the project manager do about this situation?","options":["Inform the team they will need to improve this process","Meet with the PMO to determine the companies communication process when using a virtual team","Set up a virtual meeting to help identify what is chaotic about this process","Change the process the teams following and inform them of the new process"],"answer":"Set up a virtual meeting to help identify what is chaotic about this process","explanation":"It would be best to meet with them and identify what is causing this issue during the process."},
    {"question":"M4Q52 An organization is implementing a new accounting system. Some parts of the system have a clearly defined scope and some parts are not defined at all. What approach should the project manager use for this project?","options":["A predictive approach for the entire project is","An agile-approach using scrum and Kanban","An agile approach for the entire project","A hybrid approach"],"answer":"A hybrid approach","explanation":"Since a part of the project has well-known scope, it would be best to manage that part using a predictive approach and the other part using an agile approach, making this a hybrid project."},
    {"question":"M4Q53 During an agile project, a team member fixes a major issue utilizing a very complicated step-by-step procedure that will be hard to replicate in the future. This issue might arise again later in future projects. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Ask the team member to update the lesson learn register","Update the lesson learn register yourself","Wait until the project closes to update the lesson learn register","Have the team member document the procedures to keep in the project files"],"answer":"Update the lesson learn register yourself","explanation":"Since this needs to get added to the lesson learn register, it would be best to add it yourself to ensure it is done correctly can be passed on to other projects."},
    {"question":"M4Q54 An organization is moving projects to agile based methods. The project manager realizes that most of the internal employees in the organization do not approve of this change. They feel this may lead to projects not meeting requirements. What should the project manager do first in this situation?","options":["Tell them it's okay to be resistant at first, but after the first project they will understand the benefits","Conduct coaching and training sessions with the internal employees to showcase the value of agile methods","Hire an outside consultant to explain the benefits of agile to the internal employees","Download documents on the benefits of agile and share them with all employees of the organization"],"answer":"Conduct coaching and training sessions with the internal employees to showcase the value of agile methods","explanation":"It would be best to coach and train internal employees on the benefits of agile. This will remove any doubt are inadequate knowledge on agile base methods."},
    {"question":"M4Q55 During a hybrid project, the project manager learns that one particular team member is causing the team to delay certain project work. What should the project manager do first in this situation?","options":["Meet with the PMO to discuss how to replace the team member","Have the team member meet with other members to discuss this issue and fix the problem","Have a one-on-one meeting with this team member to understand what is the issue and what solutions can be implemented","Meet with the PMO to discuss what training should be done for this team member"],"answer":"Have a one-on-one meeting with this team member to understand what is the issue and what solutions can be implemented","explanation":"The best-case scenario would be to first meet with the team member to understand what the problem is and what potential solutions are."},
    {"question":"M4Q56 A project sponsor is concerned that the agile project will not deliver value to its customers due to constant changes throughout the project. What can the project manager do to ensure that value is delivered in each sprint?","options":["Have the product owner work with the team during the sprint","Have the customers determine what features are developed in each sprint","Ensure team members are well trained and understand the purpose of the product backlog","Ensure the user stories are written"],"answer":"Ensure the user stories are written","explanation":"An agile project should have user stories. This way, the team understands what it would take the customers to realize value was produced during the project."},
    {"question":"M4Q57 An organization has completed a hybrid project to redesign its main product and is about to hand it to operations. Due to a new regulation by the local government, the redesigned product will not be able to be sold in the market.. What should the project manager do in this situation?","options":["Release the redesigned product since it was created before the regulation","Implement an adequate response from the risk register","Remove the component that is redesigned and sell the old product","Update the risk register and determine a response"],"answer":"Implement an adequate response from the risk register","explanation":"Since this is a completed project, the project manager should have had this listed as a risk and can now implement an adequate response from the risk register."},
    {"question":"M4Q58 Recent regulation has just been passed by the local government. The organization's compliance department informs the project manager that this regulation would have a drastic impact on the overall project objectives. What should the project manager do first?","options":["Meet with the project team to understand how the regulation will impact the project objectives","Complete the project and then implement the change request to incorporate the regulatory change","Schedule a meeting with the sponsor to inform him of this development","Immediately stop the project work until the regulation can be implemented"],"answer":"Meet with the project team to understand how the regulation will impact the project objectives","explanation":"The best solution would be to meet with the team to understand how this regulation will impact the project what solutions can be implemented."},
    {"question":"M4Q59 Project Management Methods","options":["Scope is well define","Some of the scope is known","Scope is unknown"],"answer":{"Scope is well define":"Predictive","Some of the scope is known":"Hybrid","Scope is unknown":"Agile"},"explanation":"Some of the scope is known ? Hybrid, Scope is well define ? Predictive, Scope is unknown ? Agile","isMatching":true},
    {"question":"M4Q60 MBTI Match","options":["Enjoy ideas and concepts for their own sake","Value harmony, forgiveness","Value Justice, fairness"],"answer":{"Enjoy ideas and concepts for their own sake":"Intuition","Value harmony, forgiveness":"Feeling","Value Justice, fairness":"Thinking"},"explanation":"Value harmony, forgiveness ? Feeling, Value Justice, fairness ? Thinking, Enjoy ideas and concepts for their own sake ? Intuition","isMatching":true}
];
const mock5Data = [
	{ "question": "M5Q1 A project manager is being assigned to an ongoing company project. After approving the project management plan and the work has started the project manager has determined that this project will most likely fail to meet its objectives. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Review any assumptions and do more research on why the project may fail", "Meet with the organization PMO and terminate the project", "Add this to the issue log and inform the project team", "Alert project sponsor and informed him of this"], "answer": "Review any assumptions and do more research on why the project may fail", "explanation": "The best choice here would be to do more research and determine if any assumptions are actually correct since the project manager feels this project may fail." },
	{ "question": "M5Q2 A project manager has recently been informed that customers are speaking directly to the project sponsor about implementing changes to the project scope. This generally happens without the project manager's knowledge and the team only finds out about it after the changes have been approved. What should the project manager do to handle this?", "options": ["Have a meeting with the customers and project sponsor to review the stakeholder engagement plan", "Update the change management plan where the project manager will be the only one that can approve a scope change", "Inform the change control board of this issue and replace the project sponsor", "Inform the project sponsor only team members can approve changes"], "answer": "Have a meeting with the customers and project sponsor to review the stakeholder engagement plan", "explanation": "The best option here would be to review the stakeholder engagement plan with the customers and sponsor and understand how to manage changes on the project." },
	{ "question": "M5Q3 A project manager has implemented a change request to fix a schedule and budget issue with the project. Which of the following values would have caused a change request for both cost and schedule?", "options": ["The SPI is 0.89, and the CPI is 1.06.", "The SPI is 1.3, and the CPI is 1.08.", "The SPI is 0.91, and the CPI is 0.94.", "The SPI is .83, and the CPI is 1.07."], "answer": "The SPI is 0.91, and the CPI is 0.94.", "explanation": "An SPI or CPI value of 1 and over is good. Any value under 1 is bad." },
	{ "question": "M5Q4 While managing an agile project, the compliance department informed the project manager that a new requirement would be needed to complete the project successfully. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Have the team add the work to the product backlog and have then reprioritized it", "Add a new requirement to the top of the product backlog", "Add the new requirement to the bottom of the product backlog so it can be done last", "Meet with the product owner and inform him of this new requirement and have him add it to the product backlog and then reprioritize it"], "answer": "Meet with the product owner and inform him of this new requirement and have him add it to the product backlog and then reprioritize it", "explanation": "Work that needs to be added to the product backlog should be done by the product owner and should also be prioritized by the product owner." },
	{ "question": "M5Q5 A major disagreement has occurred on the project between the project manager and one of the suppliers. The supplier keeps sending the wrong materials to the project team, causing a delay in the schedule. Which type of communication should the Project Manager use first when contacting the supplier about this issue?", "options": ["Email", "Virtual Meeting", "Face-to-face", "Instant message"], "answer": "Face-to-face", "explanation": "Face-to-face interaction is usually the most effective way to resolve issues in most circumstances. Face-to-face interaction is known to be the most productive way to communicate." },
	{ "question": "M5Q6 A project manager is working on a project where the scope is at a high level and will need to hire a vendor to conduct the work. The PMO wants the project to have a signed contract. What contract should be used?", "options": ["Cost plus incentive fee (CPIF) contract.", "Firm fixed price (FFP) contract.", "Time and material (TM) contract.", "Fixed price incentive fee (FPIF) contract."], "answer": "Time and material (TM) contract.", "explanation": "A time and materials contract is where the seller bills the buyer for all work perform and all materials used. It's best used on a project where the scope is not detailed. This has the most risk to the buyer." },
	{ "question": "M5Q7 To determine which features to create first, the product owner did a feasibility study. After the feasibility study was done, the product owner prioritizes the product backlog. However, the project team disagrees with the prioritized product backlog, claiming the work is infeasible in that order. What should the project manager do first in this situation?", "options": ["Review the results of the feasibility study.", "Meet with the team to understand why the work is infeasible before meeting with the product owner.", "Inform the product owner the work will need to be reprioritized.", "Reprioritize the product backlog with the team."], "answer": "Meet with the team to understand why the work is infeasible before meeting with the product owner.", "explanation": "The best course of action would be to meet with the team to understand why they feel this way and then inform the product owner of the result." },
	{ "question": "M5Q8 A project manager is conducting scope verification on a project with a few completed deliverables. The sponsor has informed the project manager that the deliverables will not be accepted due to the way it functions, it is not what they were expecting. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Meet with the team to discuss what they did wrong", "Review the acceptance criteria", "Ask the sponsor what could have been done to ensure the deliverables where accepted", "Ask the team how the WBS was created"], "answer": "Review the acceptance criteria", "explanation": "The best course of action would be to review acceptance criteria to see what should have been done for the product to be fully accepted." },
	{ "question": "M5Q9 A new project manager was assigned to a project that had completed 50% of the work. The project manager determines the SPI is .7 and CPI is .9. The project manager wants to meet with the team the next day. What communication method should the project manager use?", "options": ["Email the team a status report", "Update the issue log with this information", "Set up a meeting with the team", "Send out a memo to all team members"], "answer": "Set up a meeting with the team", "explanation": "The best answer here would be to meet with the team for a face-to-face meeting to update the team on the status of the project." },
	{ "question": "M5Q10 A software issue has been resolved and the project is almost completed. The project manager has been advised that the same issue may probably happen on similar projects in the future. What should be done first when responding to this information?", "options": ["Update the risk register.", "Update a risk report.", "Update the lessons learned register", "Ensure that the quality management plan is updated."], "answer": "Update the lessons learned register", "explanation": "The lessons learned register will be shared with other projects when this project is done. It is usually archive with the P??." },
	{ "question": "M5Q11 An organization is about to implement a hybrid project using two different methods of agile. The product owner has specified that he would like the product to be delivered in increments but has never worked on a project like this. What should the project manager do to help the product owner?", "options": ["Have the team prioritize the product backlog and break the work down into increments", "Complete the project management plan with the help of the product owner", "Coach the product owner on how the project will be handled", "Have the team train the product owner on the new agile methods"], "answer": "Coach the product owner on how the project will be handled", "explanation": "The best solution would be to coach the product owner on how these agile methods would be used to build the product. Then review what the product owner role is and why it's important for the success of the project." },
	{ "question": "M5Q12 A project team has had difficulties reaching decisions while solving difficult issues. In the last few meetings, the team was able to reach a decision using a particular technique that was taught to them recently. Where should the project manager document this technique and have the team continuously using it?", "options": ["Stakeholder engagement plan", "Configuration management plan", "Team charter", "Communications management plan"], "answer": "Team charter", "explanation": "The team charter is a document created by the team to help manage how the team would collaborate and manage the project. This includes how to reach a consensus on the project." },
	{ "question": "M5Q13 A team member has submitted the change to the change control board and the change control board rejected the change. The team member feels this is unfair. What should the project manager do to ensure this does not happen again?", "options": ["Verify the change was cost-efficient", "Approved the change yourself since it was from a team member", "Have the change control board reassess the change", "Assess the change against all of the project objectives"], "answer": "Assess the change against all of the project objectives", "explanation": "The best solution here would be to ensure the changes are assessed against all of the project objectives. These are the changes rejected the project team member would feel and understand why it was." },
	{ "question": "M5Q14 An organization is currently using predictive approaches to design a new product. The new product has many uncertain requirements. The organization hires a new project manager for this project to implement agile methods. What should the project manager do to deliver this project?", "options": ["Inform the organization it would be best to continue using predictive methods", "Ask the project sponsor for a detailed list of requirements in order to proceed on the project", "Create the backlog and complete the work in iterations", "Create a project management plan with a set scope statement"], "answer": "Create the backlog and complete the work in iterations", "explanation": "Since the requirements are unclear. Best create this product using agile methods and building the product in increments. This way stakeholders would be able to give feedback to clarify the scope." },
	{ "question": "M5Q15 A Stakeholder on a software development project is constantly calling the project team members for status updates and reporting issues that are not related to the project. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Have the team tell the stakeholder to stop this", "Meet with the stakeholder and review the communications management plan", "Meet with the stakeholder to understand why this is happening and what solutions can be implemented", "Inform the project sponsor of this situation and have the sponsor speak with the stakeholder"], "answer": "Meet with the stakeholder to understand why this is happening and what solutions can be implemented", "explanation": "It would be best to meet with the stakeholder to understand why he is doing this and how it can be fixed to stop interrupting the project team." },
	{ "question": "M5Q16 The Project Manager learns that one team member needs to complete a personal assignment for a functional manager that is outside of the project, resulting in a scheduling risk for the project. How can the Project Manager avoid this risk?", "options": ["Meet with the team member's manager, and negotiate for another time to complete the task.", "Meet with the functional manager and let him know the team member cannot leave the project.", "Ask the team member to finish the manager's work then complete the project work.", "Release the team member and have other members complete the work."], "answer": "Meet with the team member's manager, and negotiate for another time to complete the task.", "explanation": "It would be best to meet the manager and inform them that the team member is needed and if this can be done at another time." },
	{ "question": "M5Q17 A project manager is working on a complex project that has four different teams working on four different components. One of the senior team members managing one of the teams reported to the project manager that he was having a difficult time keeping the team on track in completing the work. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Reassign this team member to the role that best suits their ability", "Have this team member meet with the team and brainstorm a solution to this issue", "Ask the PMO for a new team member", "Have a few mentoring and coaching sessions with this team member to improve his management skill"], "answer": "Have a few mentoring and coaching sessions with this team member to improve his management skill", "explanation": "Since this is a problem with the particular team member that needs improvement in skills, it would be best to have the project manager train this person to improve their skills." },
	{ "question": "M5Q18 An organization has just approved a new office renovation project. After being assigned to the project, the project manager would like to know what is his power level on the project. What document should the project manager refer to?", "options": ["Stakeholder engagement plan", "Project charter", "Issue log", "Communication management plan"], "answer": "Project charter", "explanation": "The project charter is a document that will assign the project manager and also outlined his authority level." },
	{ "question": "M5Q19 A project manager has reviewed a partially complete deliverable and found that it has a few minor defects. These defects may cause complications when it's being used by the customer. The project has a CPI of .97 and an SPI of .98. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Reinspected the deliverable to ensure of the defect", "Have the team fixed the issue since the project has an adequate budget and time left", "Initiate a change request with the change control board", "Report this issue to the project sponsor and seek guidance"], "answer": "Initiate a change request with the change control board", "explanation": "Since this will require additional time and cost to fix, it would be best to initiate a change request to add additional time and costs to complete the repairs on this defect." },
	{ "question": "M5Q20 The product owner has sequenced the product backlog and the project manager has determined the order of the task for the team. Halfway into the agile project, the PM notices the project is really behind schedule. What should the project manager do to prevent this from happening again?", "options": ["Ensure that there is a management reserve to cover these issues.", "Support self-organization for the project team and have them determine the order of the task.", "Have the team sequenced the product backlog based on their work schedule.", "Ensure that the team is trained to use the agile methods."], "answer": "Support self-organization for the project team and have them determine the order of the task.", "explanation": "For Agile projects, rather than a project manager selecting and sequencing tasks, the team members are empowered to self-organize specific tasks as a group to best meet those objectives." },
	{ "question": "M5Q21 An agile project team has been informed by the product owner that the product backlog has been prioritized. The team has reviewed the product backlog and has informed the project manager that some of the features may cause issues with the final deliverable. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Remove the issues from the product backlog yourself and have the team complete the work", "Inform the team to just complete the work in the prioritized order", "Schedule a meeting with the team to better understand what these issues are and potential solutions", "Inform the product owner to reprioritize the product backlog and remove features that may cause an issue"], "answer": "Schedule a meeting with the team to better understand what these issues are and potential solutions", "explanation": "The best solution to do next would be to meet with the team to better understand what the issues are and if there are any potential solutions to these issues." },
	{ "question": "M5Q22 A new project is about to be initiated to create a new product. After meeting with the project sponsor, the project manager realizes that the sponsor is not too sure about the functionality of the final product. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Work with the project sponsor to help define the main functionality and suggest that the product be developed in iterations", "Have the sponsor meet with the team to clarify the functionality", "Meet with the PMO to review how previous projects have dealt with this issue", "Update the risk register with this risk"], "answer": "Work with the project sponsor to help define the main functionality and suggest that the product be developed in iterations", "explanation": "The best solution would be to work with the sponsor or to help define the main functionality and suggest an iteration approach to help refine the functionality." },
	{ "question": "M5Q23 A project manager has just been informed by a vendor that due to a disaster at one of their facilities, a deliverable will be significantly delayed. The project team has informed the project manager that they can fix the deliverable and complete the project on time. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Implemented change requests to delay the project", "Request a new vendor from the PMO", "Implement a change request to implement the team's response", "Assess the project team solution against the project objectives"], "answer": "Assess the project team solution against the project objectives", "explanation": "The next step would be to assess the team solution to see how it would impact the project objectives." },
	{ "question": "M5Q24 As part of active leadership on an agile project, project managers support team member's growth and keep them driven throughout each project. What is one trait that supports this effective leadership?", "options": ["Challenge the team by giving project tasks.", "Use daily conversation sessions to solicit and respond to the team's concerns.", "Provide a team reward for each successfully completed sprint", "Stand up for the team's views."], "answer": "Stand up for the team's views.", "explanation": "It is important on an agile project to be a servant leader and that means supporting and standing for the team." },
	{ "question": "M5Q25 The PMO has assigned a new Project Manager to a project, and the sponsor asks the new Project Manager to develop the quality management plan. How should the new Project Manager proceed?", "options": ["Wait for the PMO to provide the quality management plan.", "Meet with the PMO to identify established plans and processes.", "Schedule a meeting with the sponsor to collect requirements for the plan.", "Obtain the necessary benchmarking scores from the customers."], "answer": "Meet with the PMO to identify established plans and processes.", "explanation": "The new Project Manager needs to consult with the PMO to find out what practices and processes are already in place." },
	{ "question": "M5Q26 A group of customers has complained that their expectations are not met on a hybrid project. They say the main deliverable has failed a basic performance test and it is not useable for their needs. What should the project manager do to prevent this from happening again?", "options": ["Make use of conflict management techniques.", "Collect feedback from them throughout the project.", "Have them conduct risk assessments throughout the project.", "Document their needs once the project executes."], "answer": "Collect feedback from them throughout the project.", "explanation": "One method to ensure work is accepted once completed is to have more engagement of customers throughout your project." },
	{ "question": "M5Q27 The project manager has met with the product owner to discuss an issue about the project team being unhappy with the overall project. This has been going on since the project started. What could the project manager have done to prevent this?", "options": ["Create the team ground rules have them follow it", "Ensure the team understands the product owner role on the project", "Work with the team to understand the goals of the project vision", "Have the product owner meet with the team to implement a solution"], "answer": "Work with the team to understand the goals of the project vision", "explanation": "The best solution here would be to work with the team to help them understand the main cause of the project and understand the project vision." },
	{ "question": "M5Q28 The PMO requires a project team to be made up of people that live in multiple different countries. The project sponsor believes that the distribution will provide a team with many ideas and might save costs. Where should this be documented in the project charter?", "options": ["As part of the overall project risks.", "As part of stakeholder list.", "As part of high-level scope.", "As part of the risk management plan within the charter."], "answer": "As part of the overall project risks.", "explanation": "Having a distributed project team comes with risks. These risks need to be identified in the charter as an overall risk for the project." },
	{ "question": "M5Q29 An ongoing software development project has added three new senior stakeholders. They will have a large impact on the overall development and acceptance of the final product. Which two options should the Project Manager use to ensure they are engaged in the project? (Choose 2)", "options": ["Schedule meetings with the three new senior stakeholders.", "Share the benefits management plan with the new stakeholders.", "Update the assumption log.", "Revise the stakeholder engagement plan.", "Update the risk register"], "answer": ["Schedule meetings with the three new senior stakeholders.", "Revise the stakeholder engagement plan."], "explanation": "Meetings are used to develop an understanding of the three new senior stakeholders. The stakeholder engagement plan should be reviewed and revised to include them.", "isMultipleChoice": true },
	{ "question": "M5Q30 A new team member will be joining a hybrid project team. This team member has a few physical disabilities that make communicating difficult. What should the project manager and team do next?", "options": ["Redesign the communications management plan", "Have the team meet with the new team member and have them implement a communications solution.", "Have a meeting with the team to understand the issue and what communications will need to be changed", "Update the team charter for the project team and inform them of the changes"], "answer": "Have a meeting with the team to understand the issue and what communications will need to be changed", "explanation": "The next step here would be to meet with the team and to understand what the main issue would be and then implement solutions to fix this." },
	{ "question": "M5Q31 A project manager is starting a project using an agile approach and notices most team members only have knowledge of the traditional approach. What does the project manager need to do first?", "options": ["Remove team members without the correct knowledge and replace them with team members that know agile", "Have the team go through e-learning courses to learn more about agile methods", "Have the team start the project and learn as they go", "Meet with the team to determine what the training requirements would be and then implement a solution to get the training done"], "answer": "Meet with the team to determine what the training requirements would be and then implement a solution to get the training done", "explanation": "The best choice would be to meet with the team and determine what training requirements they will need and then implement those training requirements." },
	{ "question": "M5Q32 While working on a traditional project, a few team members have informed the project manager that another member is doing the job incorrectly and without guidance. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Have the team member review the stakeholder engagement plan", "Review the resource management plan and meet with the team member to understand the main issue", "Have the team meet with the member and provide guidance to him", "Have the entire project team review the resource management plan"], "answer": "Review the resource management plan and meet with the team member to understand the main issue", "explanation": "The best solution here would be to first review the resource management plan to understand how to manage conflicts with resources and then meet with this new member to understand the main issue." },
	{ "question": "M5Q33 A hybrid team has met with the project manager to seek advice on the best ways to estimate the amount of time it can take to complete the work. What are two techniques the team can use? (Choose 2)?", "options": ["Story points", "Bottom-up estimating", "Prototyping", "Decision making", "Cause and effect diagram"], "answer": ["Story points", "Bottom-up estimating"], "explanation": "The predictive portion of the project can use bottom-up estimating the agile portion of new story points.", "isMultipleChoice": true },
	{ "question": "M5Q34 A project manager has just been assigned to an ongoing agile project. After speaking with the team, he finds out that the team feels that they have no power and cannot make decisions on the project. What can the project manager do to increase the productivity of this team?", "options": ["Assess the skills of each individual member and then have them make decisions based on their expertise", "Inform the team going forward you will be making all decisions for them", "Inform the team going forward they will be allowed to make decisions on their own", "Have the team meet with the product owner to discuss this issue"], "answer": "Inform the team going forward they will be allowed to make decisions on their own", "explanation": "An agile project team should be a self-directed and self-managing team. An agile project manager should encourage the team to make their own decisions while giving them the support they need." },
	{ "question": "M5Q35 Before the team starts the third sprint on an agile project, the project manager is unsure whether or how much work they can complete in the next sprint. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Replace any team member that lacks skills needed to complete the work in the next sprint", "Ask the team to work overtime to complete the work in the next sprint to ensure the project stays on schedule", "Have the team create a detailed plan of how they will complete the work in the product backlog", "Have the team compute the velocity and then choose work based on the velocity"], "answer": "Have the team compute the velocity and then choose work based on the velocity", "explanation": "The team should choose work based on their velocity. Since the team completed a few sprints, they can easily compute this velocity to determine how much work they can get done in the next sprint." },
	{ "question": "M5Q36 A project manager has just been informed by the sponsor that the project will need to be completed three months earlier than expected. This is due to an early launch date that the CEO has requested. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Update the project management plan to finish the project three months earlier by removing certain parts of the scope", "Have the team implement the change request to reduce the schedule", "Schedule a meeting with the sponsor to review the impact of this change", "Implement resource leveling to finish it sooner"], "answer": "Schedule a meeting with the sponsor to review the impact of this change", "explanation": "The best solution would be to meet with the sponsor to let him know that finishing the project earlier could result in scope and cost changes." },
	{ "question": "M5Q37 The project team has completed the project budget. The team used a combination of their expertise and previous lessons learned to complete the budget. The company's senior management has informed the project manager that the project is too expensive and will not be approved. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Review the method the team use and if it was applicable to this project", "Inform senior management that the budget is accurate", "Inform the team they will need to redo the entire budget because it was done incorrectly", "Inform senior management that you will remove all contingency from the project budget to lower the overall budget"], "answer": "Review the method the team use and if it was applicable to this project", "explanation": "The next step would be to first review the method the team created the budgeting to ensure that it is accurate and it applies to this project before taking any other action." },
	{ "question": "M5Q38 An organization has moved from predictive methods to agile methods. A new agile project manager is working with a newly formed team. What can the project manager do to ensure the team is successful on the project?", "options": ["Ensure team members are assigned tasks that best meets their skills", "Coach the team both individually and as a whole, remove the impediments and promoting agile values", "Schedule team performance assessments on a weekly basis and implement solutions to correct any weakness", "Have the product owner assign the work to the team based on their skillset"], "answer": "Coach the team both individually and as a whole, remove the impediments and promoting agile values", "explanation": "A good agile coach will ensure that he works with the team as a whole and individually to remove the impediments and promote agile values throughout the entire agile project." },
	{ "question": "M5Q39 While working on a major construction project, a team discovers a new method to acquire permits faster. The team was able to acquire permits in half the time the plan specified. This new method was not documented in any other project documents. What should the project manager do next with this new method?", "options": ["Document it in the lesson learned register", "Document it in the risk register", "Update the risk management plan with this new method", "Share this new method with other projects"], "answer": "Document it in the lesson learned register", "explanation": "One new thing are learned, it is best for the PM and team to document it in the lesson learn register." },
	{ "question": "M5Q40 The project manager has just started working in an organization that has just transitioned to agile methods. He finds that most employees of the organization have a negative view of agile practices because the last company CEO failed at using agile successfully. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Work with the organization's HR department to hire functional managers that value agile practices", "Have the HR department only hire new employees to value agile methods", "Conduct training sessions on the value of agile practices", "Convert all internal projects to agile practices and have the teams learn on the job"], "answer": "Conduct training sessions on the value of agile practices", "explanation": "A good agile project manager will coach, mentor, train employees of an organization on the values of agile practices." },
	{ "question": "M5Q41 A project manager working on a software development project following a traditional approach has been informed that the project sponsors are having a disagreement on what some of the core functionalities should be. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Review the project management plan to gain a better understanding of where the disagreements can come from", "Meet with the project team to review the disagreements", "Meet with the project sponsors better to understand what this disagreement is and what is causing it", "Review the project charter to better understand the overall objectives of the project"], "answer": "Meet with the project sponsors better to understand what this disagreement is and what is causing it", "explanation": "The best choice here would be to first meet with the sponsors to gain a better understand of what this disagreement is and then find a solution to resolve it." },
	{ "question": "M5Q42 The project requires the development of an accounting system. The Project Manager reviews historical data from the organization PMO. This data is from the last time the organization created the old accounting system. The PM is worried about the risk that may happen. What should the project manager do first in this situation?", "options": ["Update the risk register.", "Inform the sponsor of these new risks.", "Create a risk mitigation plan.", "Quantify the new project risks."], "answer": "Update the risk register.", "explanation": "Once the PM reviews the historical data and identifies new risks, he should then add it to the risk register to be analyzed." },
	{ "question": "M5Q43 A Project Manager notices stakeholders are not involved in the project. The PM held a few meetings and still, no stakeholder was active during the meeting. This can lead to deliverables not getting accepted. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Make use of political awareness techniques.", "Add this as a risk to the project.", "Use effective facilitation techniques.", "Have the team hold the meeting."], "answer": "Use effective facilitation techniques.", "explanation": "Facilitation is the ability to effectively guide a group event to a successful decision, solution, or conclusion. A facilitator ensures that there is effective participation and that participants achieve a mutual understanding." },
	{ "question": "M5Q44 A Project Manager working on a traditional project receives complaints from a project sponsor because a prototype was delayed. The Project Manager responds that the delay was due to a lack of knowledge by the project team. How should the Project Manager avoid this type of situation in the future?", "options": ["Have the team work through issues, as they will learn more this way.", "Conduct training sessions when the project start to ensure all members have adequate skills", "Have a list of required skills when the project starts, and then assign the work based on those skills.", "Have the sponsor train the team on the required skill."], "answer": "Have a list of required skills when the project starts, and then assign the work based on those skills.", "explanation": "When a project starts to project manager should be aware of all the required skills to take to complete the project, then organize the work around the skills of the team members." },
	{ "question": "M5Q45 A new member has recently joined an agile project and comes from a background following traditional methods. The new member has been trained thoroughly in agile practices. Unfortunately, there is a rumor that the new member may be a problem due to a lack of actual working agile experience. How should the Project Manager handle this rumor?", "options": ["Have the project team assess this new member's agile skills using a questionnaire.", "Disregard any concerns since it's just a rumor.", "Meet with the new member to evaluate their agile skills and see if there are any gaps.", "Ask the PMO to remove this member and replace them with someone that is more skilled and agile."], "answer": "Meet with the new member to evaluate their agile skills and see if there are any gaps.", "explanation": "Since it is just a rumor, it would be best to speak to the team member and evaluate their skills before taking any action." },
	{ "question": "M5Q46 A project manager has been assigned to an ongoing project. The project is about building a new community center. After reviewing the project management plan, the project manager realizes there is no stakeholder engagement plan. What should the project manager do to create this plan?", "options": ["Review how each stakeholder can negatively impact the project", "Review what communications will be needed for each stakeholder on the project", "Review how to negotiate with all stakeholders on the project", "Review the different types of stakeholders on the project"], "answer": "Review the different types of stakeholders on the project", "explanation": "The best action here would be to review the different types of stakeholders on the project and then analyze how to engage them on the project." },
	{ "question": "M5Q47 A project manager has noticed that two team members working on a large project have acquired knowledge from the project work that could potentially help other team members. The two team members have not shared this knowledge with anyone yet. How should the project manager proceed in this situation?", "options": ["Have the two team members document this knowledge in an email to all team members", "Have the two members send this information to the PMO", "Wait until the project is over and then update the lesson learn register", "Schedule a meeting with all team members and have the two members update the team on the new knowledge"], "answer": "Schedule a meeting with all team members and have the two members update the team on the new knowledge", "explanation": "The best solution would be to have the two team members meet with the entire team and update them on this new knowledge." },
	{ "question": "M5Q48 A project manager has had to take a few months off from the project due to health reasons. After returning, he notices that the project team has many disagreements and this is leading to the project being delayed. What should the project manager do in this scenario?", "options": ["Schedule a meeting with the team to understand what these disagreements are about", "Inform the team this is not acceptable and have them resolve their issues immediately", "Remove team members that are causing the disagreement", "Implement a schedule compression technique to bring the project back on schedule"], "answer": "Schedule a meeting with the team to understand what these disagreements are about", "explanation": "The best choice here would be to first meet with the team to understand what these disagreements are and then come up with a solution to fix them." },
	{ "question": "M5Q49 The project sponsor is dissatisfied with how a feature of a project has been developed on the hybrid project. He says the product was not ready for deployment, yet the team allowed it. What should the Project Manager do first to resolve this issue?", "options": ["Identify the reasons for issues with the feature, then address the issue.", "Have the deployment team assess if the team made a bad decision.", "Have the team explain to the sponsor why they said it was complete.", "Meet with the project team for a brainstorming session and identify a solution."], "answer": "Identify the reasons for issues with the feature, then address the issue.", "explanation": "The project manager should first identify the reasons that cause the feature to fail then address those reasons are." },
	{ "question": "M5Q50 During a hybrid project, a team member is reassigned to a new agile project. The team is disappointed since this member was one of their key mentors. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["Add a member with the same skills to replace the key team member.", "Implement a change to bring the member back.", "Use your leadership and emotional intelligence techniques to motivate the team.", "Have the team meet with the sponsor to voice their disagreement."], "answer": "Use your leadership and emotional intelligence techniques to motivate the team.", "explanation": "Since this is more of a personal issue within the team, which manager should use his leadership emotional intelligence to keep the team motivated to stay work on the project." },
	{ "question": "M5Q51 While working on an agile project, the project manager notices two team members have been complaining about the same issue for the last two weeks. The issue seems to be something about the product owner not being happy with their work. What should the project manager do?", "options": ["Review what the main cause of this issue is and help them to remove this impediment", "Inform the team members to ignore the product owner and complete the work", "Inform the product owner they're not allowed to speak to team members", "Report this issue to the PMO and ask for help"], "answer": "Review what the main cause of this issue is and help them to remove this impediment", "explanation": "The best course of action would be to find the main cause of this issue and then remove this impediment that the team can get back to work." },
	{ "question": "M5Q52 The Project Manager calculates the SPI of 4 tasks assigned to 6 team members as .75. How should the Project Manager handle this issue?", "options": ["Meet with the team members to review the tasks and determine a plan for resolving the issue.", "Instruct the team to continue at this pace to finish the project ahead of schedule.", "Ask them why this is happening and give them a solution.", "Contact the project sponsor and escalate the issue."], "answer": "Meet with the team members to review the tasks and determine a plan for resolving the issue.", "explanation": "Since the team is behind schedule, there is a possible risk to the project. The Project Manager needs to be proactive and review the activities with the team to identify resolution strategies." },
	{ "question": "M5Q53 Team members have been unable to complete the second half of a deliverable due to working with operations to help users with the finished product. The project manager wants to confirm that the deliverable was transferred to operation. Which three documents should the project manager use for this decision?", "options": ["Final report, project document updates, and organizational process assets updates.", "Final report, organizational process assets updates, and risk register.", "Procurement agreements, and organizational process assets updates, and scope statement", "Procurement agreements, scope statement, and organizational process assets."], "answer": "Final report, project document updates, and organizational process assets updates.", "explanation": "When closing the project, the Project Manager reviews the project management plan to ensure that all project work is completed and that the project has met its objectives. The project documents are updated accordingly." },
	{ "question": "M5Q54 An agile team has just executed its fourth sprint when the project manager notices that the team is working slower than expected. This may cause the sprint to be delayed. If this happens, the entire project can be delayed significantly. What should the project manager do to resolve this?", "options": ["Remove team members that are slowing down the other members", "Meet with the entire team to better understand what is causing this slowdown and brainstorm a solution", "Ask the team if they would like help from an SME", "Inform the project management office that the sprint duration will need to be increased"], "answer": "Meet with the entire team to better understand what is causing this slowdown and brainstorm a solution", "explanation": "The best solution would be to meet with the entire and brainstorm a solution to solve this issue." },
	{ "question": "M5Q55 A project team member has configured a new email system for the team to communicate. The project manager was not aware that this system existed. The new email system is being used in a way that violates project ethics. Which action should the Project Manager take?", "options": ["Update the communication management plan to include the new email system.", "Have the project team stop using the system and then review the communications management plan.", "Monitor communications on this platform.", "Report the issue to the PMO after removing the individuals involved."], "answer": "Have the project team stop using the system and then review the communications management plan.", "explanation": "Since this platform was not part of the original communications plan and it causing an ethics violation, it should not be used. The Project Manager needs to refer the team members back to the approved project communications plan." },
	{ "question": "M5Q56 A hybrid project has a change request that was approved to develop a fix to one of the original requirements. The team conducted data analysis and the change request was approved. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["Review the data analysis.", "Execute the change request.", "Have the sponsor review the data analysis.", "Deny the change request."], "answer": "Execute the change request.", "explanation": "Once a change is approved, it should be implemented." },
	{ "question": "M5Q57 A contractor demands payment for the last set of work they did one week ago. The project is still ongoing and there are other vendors that need to get paid. How should the Project Manager respond to this contractor's demand?", "options": ["Have the customer inspector sent the payment.", "Negotiate payment through a face-to-face meeting with the contractor.", "Immediately sent payment to the contractor.", "Act according to the agreement between the contractor and the project"], "answer": "Act according to the agreement between the contractor and the project", "explanation": "When managing a project, it is important to follow all terms and conditions listed in an agreement that should include all payments that will be made." },
	{ "question": "M5Q58 A project has three sponsors that will need to be active to ensure the finished product is accepted. A few weeks into the project, one sponsor informs the PM she will be out for the next three months. What should the Project Manager do?", "options": ["Update the risk management plan.", "Revise the project management plan.", "Update the stakeholder engagement plan.", "Update the stakeholder register."], "answer": "Update the stakeholder engagement plan.", "explanation": "The stakeholder engagement plan is updated to reflect any issues that might impact the engagement of a stakeholder." },
	{ "question": "M5Q59 Match the Agile roles", "options": ["Self-directed and self-managing", "Creation and maintenance of the product backlog", "Servant leader"], "answer": { "Self-directed and self-managing": "Agile project team", "Creation and maintenance of the product backlog": "Product owner", "Servant leader": "Agile Project manager" }, "explanation": "Self-directed and self-managing ? Agile project team, Creation and maintenance of the product backlog ? Product owner, Servant leader ? Agile Project manager", "isMatching": true },
	{ "question": "M5Q60 Place agile meeting in order done during a sprint.", "options": ["1st Meeting", "2nd Meeting", "3rd Meeting"], "answer": { "1st Meeting": "Sprint Planning Meeting", "2nd Meeting": "Sprint Review", "3rd Meeting": "Sprint Retrospective" }, "explanation": "The correct order of meetings during a sprint is: 1. Sprint Planning Meeting, 2. Sprint Review, 3. Sprint Retrospective", "isMatching": true }		
];
const mock6Data = [
  { "question": "M6Q1: A project manager implemented an approved change to manage a component failure. One month after the implemented change, the PM learns that the change did not work and it may cause more issues. What should the project manager do to prevent this from happening again?", "options": ["A: Revisit or change existing assumptions in the assumption log.", "B: Follow up to verify that the change is performing as expected.", "C: Update the risk matrix after assessing any new risks.", "D: Update the lessons learned register with the component failure."], "answer": "B: Follow up to verify that the change is performing as expected.", "explanation": "Once a change is implemented, it should be monitored to ensure the results of the change are as expected." },
  { "question": "M6Q2: The Project Manager hears that a possible new law will take effect in the next two weeks. This could cause a delay to the project and increase its budget. This was unexpected and PM is not sure it will really take effect. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Start implementing the necessary step to ensure the project will be in compliance.", "B: Schedule a meeting with the sponsor to discuss solutions to this.", "C: Get more information through informal methods.", "D: Update the risk in the risk register with this new information."], "answer": "D: Update the risk in the risk register with this new information.", "explanation": "The Project Manager needs to proactively approach this. Since this is something that may occur, it needs to be added to the risk register and then analyzed." },
  { "question": "M6Q3: During a sprint, the team encounters issues that may cause a delay in the completion of the sprint. Another team within the project needs the sprint to be completed on time in order to meet their schedule. The team that prioritize the iteration backlog didn't account for the other team. What can the Project Manager do to fix this problem?", "options": ["A: Hire external help to complete the work sooner.", "B: Ask team members to finish their work and then engage in a retrospective after completion of the sprint.", "C: Have the product owner reprioritize the iteration backlog for value and account for relationships between teams", "D: Have the project team work harder to complete on time."], "answer": "C: Have the product owner reprioritize the iteration backlog for value and account for relationships between teams", "explanation": "Reprioritizing the backlog may improve the probability of success since it may allow work to be in another order." },
  { "question": "M6Q4: The project manager is working on a pharmaceutical hybrid project and he is concerned that the team will fail to meet certain health regulations. What should the project manager do in order to ensure compliance is met?", "options": ["A: Inspect deliverables on a consistent basis to check for compliance", "B: Conduct retrospective sessions with the team", "C: Ensure acceptance criteria are well documented", "D: Manually review all deliverables to ensure compliance"], "answer": "A: Inspect deliverables on a consistent basis to check for compliance", "explanation": "The best choice here would be to inspect deliverables on a regular basis to ensure they are meeting the regulations." },
  { "question": "M6Q5: An organization has just implemented its first agile project. The product owner is concerned that risks will not be managed correctly and could cause issues on the project. What should the project manager do to address these concerns with the product owner?", "options": ["A: Inform the product owner since scope and time is fixed, there is less risk", "B: Implement a risk register for the entire project that will be updated throughout the project", "C: Inform the product owner that risk is managed through many agile ceremonies and meetings", "D: Ensure there is adequate contingency built into the project budget"], "answer": "C: Inform the product owner that risk is managed through many agile ceremonies and meetings", "explanation": "During agile projects, risks are continuously monitored and responded to during the daily standup meetings, sprint review meetings and retrospectives." },
  { "question": "M6Q6: A new hybrid technology project requires a highly skilled team member who lives overseas and needs 4 months to complete the international move. What should the Project Manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Find a new skilled team member.", "B: Finish all the work except that of the skilled member.", "C: Delay the project by 4 months.", "D: Request that the resource work remotely."], "answer": "D: Request that the resource work remotely.", "explanation": "Since the resource is international it would be best to have the person work remotely. This is a better answer than rescheduling the work." },
  { "question": "M6Q7: A vendor is late with a project deliverable due to internal staff changes. There is a small buffer in the budget for cost overruns. What is the first thing a Project Manager should do to mitigate this issue?", "options": ["A: Look into alternative vendors that can assist with project deliverables.", "B: Report the vendor to the organization's legal department.", "C: Update the project budget after first accepting the cost overrun.", "D: Hire a new vendor to replace the current vendor."], "answer": "A: Look into alternative vendors that can assist with project deliverables.", "explanation": "The Project Manager needs to assess alternatives. Once a practical alternative is identified, they can present their circumstance to the sponsor for a decision." },
  { "question": "M6Q8: During the daily standup meetings, team members discuss the amount of rework they have to do because the workload is too much. How should the Project Manager respond to this concern?", "options": ["A: Reduce the work in the product backlog.", "B: Request that team members implement time boxing.", "C: Request that the product owner reduces the work in the product backlog.", "D: Have the team use a Kanban board."], "answer": "B: Request that team members implement time boxing.", "explanation": "Rework can often be caused by trying to do too much in too little time. Timeboxing is a technique to choose an appropriate window of time dedicated to a single thing." },
  { "question": "M6Q9: A Project Manager has recently started to use agile methodologies in his projects. The project manager hears that some team members feel like other members are missing key skills and this might lead to a delay in work. How should the project manager handle this situation?", "options": ["A: Implement the use of Kanban.", "B: Add cross-functional resources.", "C: Hire an external vendor to complete complex work.", "D: Have the sponsor add more resources to the project with the right skills."], "answer": "B: Add cross-functional resources.", "explanation": "Agile methodologies require \"T\" shaped team members. That is, individuals who are cross-functional and can help each other overcome issues." },
  { "question": "M6Q10: The project manager is having a major issue with the customer on a project. The customer wants the deliverables to be done two months earlier. The project manager has decided this is not possible, but the customer is insistent. What should the project manager do? (Choose 2)", "options": ["A: Inform the customer how this will impact other project objectives", "B: Meet with the project team to discuss what are the possibilities of completing the deliverables two months earlier", "C: Inform the customer of your disagreement and continue as planned", "D: Continue the project as planned and finish it on time", "E: Ask the project sponsor for additional funding to complete the project two months earlier"], "answer": "A: Inform the customer how this will impact other project objectives, B: Meet with the project team to discuss what are the possibilities of completing the deliverables two months earlier", "explanation": "The best option would be to meet with the team to discuss how this can be done and then informed the customer how this would impact all the other project objectives." },
  { "question": "M6Q11: An organization has moved to agile methods. A new project has completed about 50% of the work and the customers are complaining that the project is not delivering any value to them. What should the project manager do to ensure the project delivering value?", "options": ["A: Inform the project team they will need to prioritize the product backlog based on the value then complete the most valuable work first", "B: Reprioritize the work yourself and tell the team what work to do first", "C: Coach the product owner to prioritize the product backlog based on the value", "D: Informed the customer's project will deliver value later in the project cycle"], "answer": "C: Coach the product owner to prioritize the product backlog based on the value", "explanation": "On an agile project, the product owner should be prioritizing the product backlog based on value to ensure the most valuable work is done first." },
  { "question": "M6Q12: The project manager has just been informed by a senior team member that the project cannot proceed due to a work package that the team is having difficulties with. What should the project manager do to help the team? (Choose 2)", "options": ["A: Work with the team to identify the main cause", "B: Add this to the risk register", "C: Brainstorm potential solutions with the team", "D: Implement change requests to increase the project schedule", "E: Informed the project sponsor and seek guidance"], "answer": "A: Work with the team to identify the main cause, C: Brainstorm potential solutions with the team", "explanation": "When there is a major issue on a project, the project manager should work with the team to identify the main cause and potential solutions." },
  { "question": "M6Q13: A team misinterpreted one feature functionality that was documented by the customers. During the current iteration, the functionality has not gotten done yet due to other work. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["A: Since functionality was approved, initiate a change request.", "B: Schedule a meeting to discuss and brainstorm the functionality with the project team and how to implement it soon.", "C: Escalate the issue to the project sponsor for a rapid solution.", "D: Continue with the current iteration and then add the functionality later in the project."], "answer": "B: Schedule a meeting to discuss and brainstorm the functionality with the project team and how to implement it soon.", "explanation": "Since the functionality has not been done, the Project Manager should facilitate a meeting with the project team to brainstorm ideas on how to prevent dysfunctionality." },
  { "question": "M6Q14: Some agile approaches have recently been added to an infrastructure company's predictive processes. Most of the agile processes and methods are not being followed by the team. The Project Manager is worried about the method they are using to estimate the amount of work to do. What should the Project Manager do?", "options": ["A: Instruct the team on what work needs to be done when.", "B: Have the sponsor estimate the story points for all the features.", "C: Provide training to the team, so the team can estimate using story points.", "D: Use burndown charts to evaluate team estimating."], "answer": "C: Provide training to the team, so the team can estimate using story points.", "explanation": "The project manager should be providing training when the team lacks certain skills, this includes, this includes how to use agile methods." },
  { "question": "M6Q15: There is a conflict between three team members and one member from the vendor team. The issue is escalated to the Project Manager. What is the first thing the Project Manager should do?", "options": ["A: Have the vendor meet with you in person to discuss the issue.", "B: Terminate the vendor.", "C: Call the vendor on the phone to discuss the issue.", "D: Send an email to the vendor to discuss the issue."], "answer": "A: Have the vendor meet with you in person to discuss the issue.", "explanation": "A face-to-face meeting is the best choice to resolve this conflict." },
  { "question": "M6Q16: A customer requires the configuration of a component for the project to move on to the next phase. After checking, the project manager notices that the configuration might be done late in the project. Which action should the Project Manager perform?", "options": ["A: Start configuring the component right away.", "B: Modify the project schedule to account for the delay configuration.", "C: Update the risk register to document the risk and develop a plan to complete the configuration.", "D: Revise the risk register, and discuss it at the next project status meeting."], "answer": "C: Update the risk register to document the risk and develop a plan to complete the configuration.", "explanation": "The Project Manager should document the risk and then work with the stakeholder to address this risk." },
  { "question": "M6Q17: A project manager has taken over an agile project from her previous manager. The project manager notices that most of the customers do not attend the sprint review meetings. This has led to a few issues with the value delivery of the project. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Continue the project, but inform the customer's issues may arise later", "B: Ask the team to reschedule the sprint review meetings to better match the customer schedule", "C: Inform the customers it is mandatory to attend", "D: Meet with the customers and mentored them on the values of these meetings"], "answer": "D: Meet with the customers and mentored them on the values of these meetings", "explanation": "An agile project manager should coach teams and customers on the values of agile ceremonies." },
  { "question": "M6Q18: The project manager creates the project management plan with the team. One team member is refusing to participate as he feels the project will be a burden on the company. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Inform the project sponsor of this team member and asked for a replacement", "B: Meet with the team member to understand why he feels this way and how the issue can be solved", "C: Ask other team members to resolve the issue with this particular member", "D: Remove the team member and replace him with someone that is willing to participate"], "answer": "B: Meet with the team member to understand why he feels this way and how the issue can be solved", "explanation": "This choice would be to first meet with the team member to understand why he feels the project would be a burden and seek solutions from there." },
  { "question": "M6Q19: A team member has informed the project manager that he needs to leave right away due to a family issue. In response, the project team postponed some tasks. The result is that a few activities are now happening at the same time. What is the first thing that the Project Manager should do?", "options": ["A: Identify suitable responses for the newly introduced risks.", "B: Revise the risk register and update the issue log.", "C: Evaluate the new risks with the team and update the risk register", "D: Mitigate risks by relapsing to the original schedule."], "answer": "C: Evaluate the new risks with the team and update the risk register", "explanation": "The PM and the project team should evaluate the newly discovered risk. PM should also update the risk register, analyze and prioritize the risk and plan the response." },
  { "question": "M6Q20: There are three deliverables in the project manager's IT transformation project: Deliverable 1 has a strict schedule. Deliverables 2 & 3 need quickly changing requirements during development. Which lifecycle model should be used to meet the project's requirements?", "options": ["A: Select a hybrid project model, where Deliverable 1 is positioned as a single waterfall method embedded in an overall agile project.", "B: Select a fully agile project model.", "C: Select a waterfall project model for deliverables.", "D: Select a hybrid project model, where Deliverable 1 is positioned as a single agile sprint embedded in an overall waterfall project."], "answer": "A: Select a hybrid project model, where Deliverable 1 is positioned as a single waterfall method embedded in an overall agile project.", "explanation": "In this project, deliverable should be done using a waterfall method and the rest in an agile method." },
  { "question": "M6Q21: A new Project Manager realized the project's daily standup meetings take over 3 hours on most days because the team spends time discussing only a specific set of issues every day. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Invite the product owners to the standup sessions in order to resolve the issues quickly.", "B: Explain to team members that long discussions are okay as long as they find a solution.", "C: Hire an external team member to fix this issue to keep the meeting short.", "D: Tell the team members that they should shorten the standup meetings and improve on finding solutions."], "answer": "D: Tell the team members that they should shorten the standup meetings and improve on finding solutions.", "explanation": "The PM should explain to the team that standup meetings are designed to be short and to the point; 10-15 mins. Problem solving discussions are held outside the daily standup." },
  { "question": "M6Q22: A customer is not happy with the finished deliverable. They claim it was produced wrong and didn't function as expected. The agile development team delivered the product several sprints early. What should the project manager do to prevent this from happening again?", "options": ["A: Ensure the customer attends the sprint review meetings.", "B: Required sign-off for each sprint.", "C: Conduct more testing with the team.", "D: Have the team select the features that were included in the sprints."], "answer": "A: Ensure the customer attends the sprint review meetings.", "explanation": "When a customer is not engaged in the project, it usually leads to a failed product that doesn't meet their requirements." },
  { "question": "M6Q23: The organization wants to move to an agile approach. What principles should the organization start following to accomplish this goal? (Choose 2)", "options": ["A: Design a digital communication system.", "B: Implement a change control process", "C: Have management directly communicate with the project team", "D: Allow the team to choose what order the work should get done.", "E: Start using a product backlog that is ordered by the product owner."], "answer": "C: Have management directly communicate with the project team, E: Start using a product backlog that is ordered by the product owner.", "explanation": "Agile projects is about open communications and getting the most valuable work done first, which is usually done by the product owner." },
  { "question": "M6Q24: A hybrid project team members are worried that a new member does not seem appropriate for a complex task. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Meet with the new member to assess their skills.", "B: Contact the sponsor to reassign the new resource to a different project.", "C: Ask the team members to list what skills are lacking by the new member.", "D: Contact the project sponsor to discuss these issues and ask for a solution"], "answer": "A: Meet with the new member to assess their skills.", "explanation": "The PM should talk to the new member to assess their skills and see if they meet the needs of the project." },
  { "question": "M6Q25: A project manager is working in an environment where schedule and scope are fixed. The team is skilled at a specific task. The organization is about to enter a new market that would require a whole new set of skills. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Upgrade the existing team members' skills.", "B: Add new resources with the required skills.", "C: Hire a third-party vendor with the needed skills.", "D: Stop the project until HR can provide the correct resource."], "answer": "B: Add new resources with the required skills.", "explanation": "In a situation where time is limited, the most efficient option is expanding the team to include skilled resources." },
  { "question": "M6Q26: An agile project team has realized that the customer doesn't have much trust in them in order to create a deliverable that delivers value. The sprint is almost done. The team has tried to interact with the customer but has failed. When should the team brainstorm ideas on how to get the trust of the customer?", "options": ["A: Immediately after the sprint starts.", "B: During the next retrospective meeting.", "C: During the sprint planning meeting.", "D: At the start of the first sprint"], "answer": "B: During the next retrospective meeting.", "explanation": "The retrospective allows the team to learn about, improve and adapt their processes. It's in this meeting they would find ways to gain the customer's trust." },
  { "question": "M6Q27: A project management plan has a schedule baseline of 2 years. After the project completes 8 months, a senior stakeholder requested the project to be completed by month 15. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Condense the schedule to 15 months by removing unneeded components.", "B: Request the project team to work late and faster to complete the work, then reward them.", "C: Meet with the stakeholders and project team members to discuss how the work can be completed quickly than plan to remove requirements that were not needed.", "D: Meet with project team members to discuss what sections of the project are not needed."], "answer": "C: Meet with the stakeholders and project team members to discuss how the work can be completed quickly than plan to remove requirements that were not needed.", "explanation": "The best solutions here would be to meet with the stakeholders and team to discuss how they complete the work quicker and what can be removed." },
  { "question": "M6Q28: During an agile iteration, you realize the order of the work would not be able to get done since a few tasks depend on tasks that will be done later. How should the Project Manager resolve this issue?", "options": ["A: Add a new team to complete the depended work.", "B: Meet with the product owner to reprioritize the iteration backlog and inform him of why", "C: Tell the team to continue working and you will implement a solution once the issue happens.", "D: Meet with the team and ask them to reprioritize the product backlog."], "answer": "B: Meet with the product owner to reprioritize the iteration backlog and inform him of why", "explanation": "The Product Owner and the team should prioritize the tasks they know will or might impact other teams." },
  { "question": "M6Q29: A project has completed a phase that was done using a traditional approach. Now the next phase will use agile. Unfortunately, there are team members who have not had suitable agile training. How should the Project Manager handle the lack of agile training?", "options": ["A: Create an e-learning video course for key team members.", "B: Identify and implement cost-effective, agile training for the team members.", "C: Check if the project's contingency reserve can cover agile training for all team members.", "D: Include agile training for these team members in the project scope statement."], "answer": "B: Identify and implement cost-effective, agile training for the team members.", "explanation": "The Project Manager should identify and implement Agile training for team members." },
  { "question": "M6Q30: An agile project manager believes that a delay in developing the feature was due to a lack of a specific skill that was needed by the agile team. How could the Project Manager prevent this situation in the future?", "options": ["A: Have specialized training for the team throughout the project.", "B: Have the project sponsor work with the team members to assign training for specific skills.", "C: Have team members train each other on skills other may be lacking.", "D: Identify required strengths, and then train the team based on those strengths."], "answer": "D: Identify required strengths, and then train the team based on those strengths.", "explanation": "The Project Manager should know the required strengths and skill sets needed for a project. Then they can build the team around those strengths." },
  { "question": "M6Q31: A project's team is small and has worked together before on other projects. A team member informs the project manager that a newly added member is not behaving well and is insulting other members. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Schedule a team meeting and create the team charter.", "B: Review stakeholder engagement plan.", "C: Have the team meet and discuss this issue.", "D: Remove the new member."], "answer": "A: Schedule a team meeting and create the team charter.", "explanation": "The best solution would be to create a team charter to document what is acceptable behavior on the project." },
  { "question": "M6Q32: During a highly regulated project, a customer has requested a change that appears to not meet the legal requirements. What should be the first step in the Project Manager's response?", "options": ["A: Reject the change.", "B: Send the change to the change control board for approval.", "C: Inform the customer the change is outside the scope of the project.", "D: Meet with the organization's legal department to gain more of an understanding of the law."], "answer": "D: Meet with the organization's legal department to gain more of an understanding of the law.", "explanation": "The first step would be to investigate the change and understand if it is something that can legally be done before asking the change control board about the change." },
  { "question": "M6Q33: At a status meeting, a team member says the method of development will only lead to the failure of the deliverable. The other team members don't feel this way. What steps should the Project Manager take?", "options": ["A: Update the risk register to document this risk, then continue the meeting.", "B: Acknowledge the team member's concern, then after the meeting, meet privately meet with the team member to fully understand more about this potential issue.", "C: Inform the team member this potential issue should be raised outside of the meeting.", "D: Ask if the team wants to use the time to discuss this potential issue."], "answer": "B: Acknowledge the team member's concern, then after the meeting, meet privately meet with the team member to fully understand more about this potential issue.", "explanation": "Conflict should be addressed in private and the project should have a better understanding what this potential issue why the team member feels this way." },
  { "question": "M6Q34: During a meeting, a Project Manager learns that the project must be done 4 months earlier than planned. The project will need at least 2 more members to finish this quickly. What is the first thing the Project Manager should do?", "options": ["A: Notify the project sponsor that this may not be possible.", "B: Check with the functional manager to see if there are any available resources to hire.", "C: Inform the PMO of this and ask for resources.", "D: Contact a vendor to hire outside resources to complete the work."], "answer": "B: Check with the functional manager to see if there are any available resources to hire.", "explanation": "The Project Manager should first confirm with the functional manager whether a resource is available." },
  { "question": "M6Q35: A project manager has been assigned a new agile project. After the assignments, he found out that he would need to leave the project for six weeks. He would only spend two weeks with the team at the beginning. How can the Project Manager develop the new project team over the next two weeks?", "options": ["A: Managed team using frequent emails.", "B: Assign one member to serve as the project manager while gone.", "C: Have the team determine the best way to communicate by themselves.", "D: Help the team create a team charter that will encourage team unity."], "answer": "D: Help the team create a team charter that will encourage team unity.", "explanation": "This will allow the team to normalize themselves and be self-servicing when the project manager is away." },
  { "question": "M6Q36: A project team was informed of a new privacy requirement from the company's legal department. This privacy requirement could impact all major baselines of the project. They learn this right after the project charter is authorized. How should the Project Manager handle this situation?", "options": ["A: Add the privacy requirement to the project scope statement.", "B: Wait until the project executes and then approach the sponsor for scope change to include the privacy requirement.", "C: Add the privacy requirement to the risk register and have the sponsor come up with a response.", "D: Research the privacy requirements for the project, then give the sponsor/customers a recommendation."], "answer": "D: Research the privacy requirements for the project, then give the sponsor/customers a recommendation.", "explanation": "The best course of action here would be to research how this privacy requirement can affect the project then give the sponsor recommendations on how to implement it." },
  { "question": "M6Q37: The Project Manager schedules a sprint review and learns that a few customers do not approve of how a feature has been made. What should the Project Manager do first in order to address this issue?", "options": ["A: Ask the stakeholders what about the feature is made incorrect.", "B: Have the team members fix it right away.", "C: Determine the impact of this failed feature on the product backlog.", "D: Ask the project sponsor to approve of the feature so the project can continue."], "answer": "A: Ask the stakeholders what about the feature is made incorrect.", "explanation": "The project manager should first understand why the feature is a failure before taking any action to fix it." },
  { "question": "M6Q38: A junior team member on an agile project is asked to move to another project during the middle of a sprint. The team believes this may cause an issue, but the project manager thinks it may not since the team member was not doing any critical work. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Discuss the conflict with the project sponsor.", "B: Replace the junior member with a member who has the same skills.", "C: Acknowledge the teams' concerns and also analyze the impact on the project.", "D: Use coaching tools to make the project team understand your decision"], "answer": "C: Acknowledge the teams' concerns and also analyze the impact on the project.", "explanation": "PM should acknowledge the team's worries and then see how this may impact the project." },
  { "question": "M6Q39: The project manager has recently been assigned a project that is almost completed. The project manager notices that most of the customers don't feel that the project has delivered any value to them. What should the previous project manager do to prevent this?", "options": ["A: Perform risk assessment early and continuous throughout the project", "B: Conduct more thorough testing with the customers", "C: Have the customer accept each deliverable upon completion", "D: Have more stakeholder engagement throughout the project"], "answer": "D: Have more stakeholder engagement throughout the project", "explanation": "The best way to ensure projects meet the customer's expectations is to have the customer involved in the creation of the deliverables. This is usually done through stakeholder engagement." },
  { "question": "M6Q40: A project has completed 30% of the work when the project manager notices that the team is having issues communicating and finishing the rest of the work. What should the project manager do to ensure the team is functioning well?", "options": ["A: Have a meeting with the team and the sponsor to discuss the root cause of this issue", "B: Coach and mentor the team on effective communication and problem solving methods", "C: Review the project management plan with the team to ensure they fully understand the objectives of the project", "D: Individually assess team members and remove members that are causing issues"], "answer": "B: Coach and mentor the team on effective communication and problem solving methods", "explanation": "The best choice here would be to coach and mentor them on how to effectively communicate and resolve their issues." },
  { "question": "M6Q41: A Project Manager is managing an agile project that is on a strict timeline. The Project Manager is informed by a few stakeholders that they are worried the project will deliver the features too late. What can the project manager do to speed up the delivery of the features?", "options": ["A: Remove features from the product backlog.", "B: Explain to stakeholders the schedule will need to be readjusted.", "C: Meet with the product owner to identify the minimum viable product.", "D: Informed the stakeholders, you will consistently monitor the project using a variety of agile tools."], "answer": "C: Meet with the product owner to identify the minimum viable product.", "explanation": "Defining the minimum viable product would allow the team to focus only on the must-have items that the business stakeholders need." },
  { "question": "M6Q42: The project sponsor informs the project manager during the planning stage that the available resources are insufficient to meet the objectives of the project. The Project Manager believes that the sponsor is correct. How should the Project Manager handle this situation?", "options": ["A: Have the sponsor provide more resources.", "B: Participate in negotiations for more resources.", "C: Have the sponsor speak with the PMO for more resources.", "D: Review the project charter to determine if this is actually true."], "answer": "B: Participate in negotiations for more resources.", "explanation": "The Project Manager should be using negotiation skills to acquire the right resources for the project by following the steps in the project management plan." },
  { "question": "M6Q43: A Project Manager is informed by another team member that one team member seems unhappy while working. The member is very slow to complete the work. The team member feels that he is not in the correct position. What should the Project Manager do?", "options": ["A: Meet with the team member to discuss where they can contribute, based on their strong points.", "B: Meet this member on a daily basis to assess the member's skills.", "C: Research and enroll the member into classes on skills they lack.", "D: Meet with the team member to ensure the member is in the correct position."], "answer": "A: Meet with the team member to discuss where they can contribute, based on their strong points.", "explanation": "A good project manager should work with members to find where the date best fits the project and how they can contribute." },
  { "question": "M6Q44: A product owner complains that a function developed by the agile team does not seem to work as per the original design. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Ask the quality assurance department to inspect the work.", "B: Invite the product owner to the next sprint review meeting to discuss their concerns.", "C: Ask the product owner to sit in on the next retrospectives.", "D: Ask the team to include the product owner in the daily standups."], "answer": "B: Invite the product owner to the next sprint review meeting to discuss their concerns.", "explanation": "The next sprint review meeting is where customers will be able to voice their feedback on the products that are made by the team." },
  { "question": "M6Q45: A customer would like to add functionality to an ongoing project. The Project Manager finds that the cost for the addition would not impact the budget. The functionality would increase the overall quality of the product. What should the Project Manager do next?", "options": ["A: Move forward, using the project's management reserve to add the requested functionality.", "B: Add the functionality to the project plan.", "C: Inform the customer to get approval from the sponsor before moving forward.", "D: Submit a change request and then evaluate the impact on the project."], "answer": "D: Submit a change request and then evaluate the impact on the project.", "explanation": "All changes must be assessed for impact on all project objectives. Changes should go through the perform integrated change control process before being approved." },
  { "question": "M6Q46: A customer requests a technical change on a major deliverable. The Project Manager researched and finds this change is extremely complex. What should the Project Manager do with the customer's request?", "options": ["A: Have the team research how to implement the change and what its effects would be on the project.", "B: Work with team members to implement the new change.", "C: Research the methods of implementation and have the customer approved the change.", "D: Determine why this customer wants this change."], "answer": "A: Have the team research how to implement the change and what its effects would be on the project.", "explanation": "As a technical issue, the team should be in charge of assessing this change due to its complex nature. After the assessment then the change can be implemented." },
  { "question": "M6Q47: A company is having a hard time defining the scope of a new project due to the technical complexity of the deliverable. The stakeholders are not sure what the final output should look like. How should the project manager accomplish the scope?", "options": ["A: Hire an external vendor to create the scope.", "B: Implement a traditional approach in a large contingency reserve.", "C: Implement an agile approach to build the product in iterations.", "D: Inform the customers to take all time needed to create the scope."], "answer": "C: Implement an agile approach to build the product in iterations.", "explanation": "Since the scope is difficult to determine, it would be best to build this product in iterations. This will allow the stakeholders to give more feedback as the product is being built." },
  { "question": "M6Q48: After five sprints, variations have occurred to the project schedule. This has occurred because the features being made by the project team are not aligning with the customer's expectations. The Project Manager wants to suggest a new method in the next sprint to avoid possible delays. What should the Project Manager do first?", "options": ["A: Meet with the product owner to discuss a potential fix.", "B: Have the product owner prioritize the product backlog, then implement solutions identified during the last retrospective.", "C: Have the customers send in a detailed explanation of what they're want in each feature.", "D: Meet with the team and have them explain why the features are not aligning."], "answer": "B: Have the product owner prioritize the product backlog, then implement solutions identified during the last retrospective.", "explanation": "The best step here would be to first prioritize the work and then implement any recommendations from the retrospective in order to fix the schedule." },
  { "question": "M6Q49: The project sponsor has informed the project manager that risk assessment is not necessary for the current project since the organization has completed this project many times before. The sponsor claims this can help the complete project sooner. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Ask the PMO if the risk is truly needed on the project", "B: Ask the sponsor to share the risk register of the previous project", "C: Skip the risks assessment and continue the planning process", "D: Complete the risk assessment as planned and inform the sponsor risk changes per project"], "answer": "D: Complete the risk assessment as planned and inform the sponsor risk changes per project", "explanation": "Risk assessment should be done on every project since risk changes per project." },
  { "question": "M6Q50: The project manager has been assigned to an ongoing project to create a new medical device. Due to compliance with the countries laws, the team doesn't feel safe building the product. They feel the product will not pass the required audits. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Research and budget for the correct training for the team to understand this compliance", "B: Recruit team members that are familiar with this particular compliance", "C: Meet with the team to gather their inputs on how to meet the compliance", "D: Contract a SME to guide the project"], "answer": "A: Research and budget for the correct training for the team to understand this compliance", "explanation": "The best solution here would be for the project manager to ensure the team is trained correctly on how to manage this compliance." },
  { "question": "M6Q51: A Project Manager needs to ensure that all security requirements are covered during a software mitigation project being executed. The project will be moving a large amount of private data from one system to another. Due to government regulations, a breach of this data could lead to severe consequences. How should the project manager ensure compliance?", "options": ["A: Hire an outside security consultant to develop a security plan.", "B: Inform the project team of the security requirements and have them implement a method to ensure compliance.", "C: Have the quality assurance team check for security breaches.", "D: Work with the project team to implement the security requirements and regularly check to ensure the implementation."], "answer": "D: Work with the project team to implement the security requirements and regularly check to ensure the implementation.", "explanation": "It would be best to work with the team to implement these requirements and check periodically that they are being implemented." },
  { "question": "M6Q52: Several activities are behind schedule because a project team member has fallen sick and has been out for the past week. This impacts the critical path. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Allow the project to continue and, when the member return, have him work overtime to complete the missed work.", "B: Work with the PMO to replace this resource.", "C: Meet with the team to discuss this situation and work with them to identify a solution.", "D: Ask the team if they can work overtime to complete the work."], "answer": "C: Meet with the team to discuss this situation and work with them to identify a solution.", "explanation": "The project team would have the most practical solutions to most issues on a project. Therefore it's best to meet with them for those solutions." },
  { "question": "M6Q53: The contractor has completed a portion of a major deliverable for the project. The procurement department has informed the project manager the vendor was paid for this work. The contractor has informed the project manager the payment made was not for the completed work and needs more money. What should the project manager do next?", "options": ["A: Conduct a procurement audit", "B: Inform the contractor to settle this dispute with the procurement department", "C: Have the contractor send you his invoices for payment", "D: Review the deliverable to ensure it was completed correctly"], "answer": "A: Conduct a procurement audit", "explanation": "The best choice here would be to conduct the procurement audit to see what was done, what wasn't done and what was paid or not." },
  { "question": "M6Q54: A Project Manager realizes during the 2nd sprint of the project that the project management plan software is not showing updates due to a potential software error. Which action should the Project Manager do?", "options": ["A: Update the issue log on the project to get the team involved.", "B: Assign one team member to fix the software.", "C: Stop using the software and alert the PMO.", "D: Fix this error independently by meeting with the IT department."], "answer": "D: Fix this error independently by meeting with the IT department.", "explanation": "In an Agile approach, the Project Manager should work to protect the team against impediments around building the product. This question addresses administrative work that doesn't require technical knowledge and should be handled by the PM." },
  { "question": "M6Q55: During a meeting with the organization's management, they indicate that they will reject an iteration's deliverable. What should the Project Manager do?", "options": ["A: Send a request to the project sponsors, asking them to update the project charter.", "B: Work with the organization's management to create a shared approach that will address the issues of concern.", "C: Meet with the project team to add new and improved features to replace the features that were rejected.", "D: File a change request with the change control board (CCB) in order to add budget and scope to the baseline."], "answer": "B: Work with the organization's management to create a shared approach that will address the issues of concern.", "explanation": "Taking any other step, first work with the organization management to create a shared approach to what the product should be and then addressing issues." },
  { "question": "M6Q56: A new member has been assigned to replace a key member who had to leave the project. After this, a stakeholder claims that the person who assigned the new member sent someone with little to no skills. What should the project manager do in this situation?", "options": ["A: Assess the new member's ability to communicate with the current project team.", "B: File a request with the project management office (PMO) to replace the new member.", "C: Evaluate the skills of the new member to understand how the resource can provide value to the project.", "D: Have the team trained the new member."], "answer": "C: Evaluate the skills of the new member to understand how the resource can provide value to the project.", "explanation": "The project manager should first evaluate the skills of the resource to better understand what value this member can add to the project." },
  { "question": "M6Q57: Match agile terms. 1. Inspection by the customers 2. Work the team selects to get done in the next sprint 3. The project team, work to complete the task", "options": ["A: Sprint review meeting", "B: Sprint Backlog", "C: Sprint"], "answer": "N/A", "explanation": "The correct answer is: Inspection by the customers → Sprint review meeting, Work the team selects to get done in the next sprint → Sprint Backlog, The project team, work to complete the task → Sprint" },
  { "question": "M6Q58: Match the formulas to their output. 1. Negative values indicate over budget 2. This value should be 1 and over for a project to be ahead of the schedule. 3. This value should be 1 and over for projects under budget 4. Negative values indicate behind schedule", "options": ["A: CV", "B: SPI", "C: CPI", "D: SV"], "answer": "N/A", "explanation": "The correct answer is: Negative values indicate over budget → CV, This value should be 1 and over for a project to be ahead of the schedule. → SPI, This value should be 1 and over for projects under budget → CPI, Negative values indicate behind schedule → SV" },
  { "question": "M6Q59: Match the quality terms. 1. Shows you the root causes of potential defects 2. Distribution of numerical data. 3. Graphical representation of the process", "options": ["A: Cause-and-effect diagram", "B: Histograms", "C: Flowcharts"], "answer": "N/A", "explanation": "The correct answer is: Shows you the root causes of potential defects → Cause-and-effect diagram, Distribution of numerical data. → Histograms, Graphical representation of the process → Flowcharts" },
  { "question": "M6Q60: Match agile terms. 1. Show you the amount of work that remains to be done 2. Show you what work has been done on 3. Shows how many points a team can get done in each iteration", "options": ["A: Burndown chart", "B: Burnup chart", "C: Velocity Chart"], "answer": "N/A", "explanation": "The correct answer is: Show you the amount of work that remains to be done → Burndown chart, Show you what work has been done on → Burnup chart, Shows how many points a team can get done in each iteration → Velocity Chart" }
];
const pmpData = [
			{ "question": "M7Q1: There has been a sharp increase in user complaints about the agile product development methods of a smartphone company. [cite: 1] The smartphone manufacturer re-assessed the methods. An analysis of the complaints revealed that the users are trying to use some features in ways that the designers did not anticipate. [cite: 2] How can this problem be prevented? [cite: 3]", "options": ["A: Ask some of the users to test the product before it is launched. [cite: 8]", "B: Create a detailed lessons-learned document so that these issues don't happen in future. [cite: 9]", "C: Survey the users on how they will use the product. [cite: 10]", "D: Ask your Dev team to keep end-users in mind. [cite: 11]"], "answer": "A: Ask some of the users to test the product before it is launched. [cite: 8]", "explanation": "Let's use the elimination technique. Option D is out because this is something that would already be taken care of. [cite: 12] Option B is not about prevention. Options A and C are both good choices, so you need to determine which is better. [cite: 13] The survey can be good, but a better choice would be to ask the end-users to test the product. [cite: 14]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q2: We are 7 months into a strategic agile project. The Company Executives are closely monitoring its progress. [cite: 15] The Project Director is frustrated about the last weekly burn-down charts depicting the project completion dates changing significantly several times. [cite: 16] How can the project manager forecast the project completion date with more accuracy and stability? [cite: 17]", "options": ["A: Lower the Frequency of Progress Reports shared with Senior Stakeholders. [cite: 21]", "B: Inform the Executive Committee about the flexible nature of agile planning. [cite: 22]", "C: Come up with planning variable-size iterations based on story complexity and load. [cite: 23]", "D: Explain or elaborate on the upcoming backlog items in more detail with the team. [cite: 24]"], "answer": "D: Explain or elaborate on the upcoming backlog items in more detail with the team. [cite: 24]", "explanation": "Inconsistent progress curve variations could result in inconsistent or uninformed story point estimates. [cite: 25] Breaking down complex user stories is a must from time to time. [cite: 26] Option B can be helpful but does not resolve the problem in the question. Similarly, option A is completely irrelevant. [cite: 27] Variable size iterations are typically not done in agile. So option C is out as well. [cite: 28]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q3: Mark is a project manager who is experienced in predictive methods. [cite: 29] He is taking on an Agile Project for the first time. [cite: 30] In order to seamlessly adjust to the shift from Predictive to Agile, Mark makes a Watchlist of situations that arise from insufficient actions as a servant leader. [cite: 31] SELECT THREE situations that would result from a lack of Servant Leadership? [cite: 32]", "options": ["A: Team Members don't communicate directly with other departments. [cite: 34]", "B: Team members come up with impediments that they are unable to neutralize. [cite: 35]", "C: Team Members don't take on challenging tasks. [cite: 36]", "D: Project Stakeholders express skepticism over Agile Methods. [cite: 38]", "E: Team's High Performers move to more senior positions. [cite: 39]"], "answer": ["A: Team Members don't communicate directly with other departments. [cite: 34]", "C: Team Members don't take on challenging tasks. [cite: 36]", "D: Project Stakeholders express skepticism over Agile Methods. [cite: 38]"], "explanation": "A, C, and D are correct because Servant Leaders help promote professional development through challenges, help teams build bridges with external groups, andeducate stakeholders on Agile Business Value, B and E are incorrect because Servant Leaders support Personal Growth and Remove Impediments beyond the interests of the project. [cite: 40]", "isMultipleChoice": true },
			{ "question": "M7Q4: Jason is a new team member who is unaccustomed to Agile practices. [cite: 41] An Operations Engineer often criticized Jason's work. Jason becomes nervous when the Operations Engineer appears in the morning standup meeting. [cite: 42] Which of the following could justify the Project Manager's invitation to the Operations Engineer? [cite: 43]", "options": ["A: All team members are important and we should not ignore anyone. [cite: 48]", "B: Team Members' performance will become better. [cite: 49]", "C: The Project Manager will be able to learn more about the Operations Engineer. [cite: 50]", "D: It will help the project to get back on track. [cite: 51]"], "answer": "A: All team members are important and we should not ignore anyone. [cite: 48]", "explanation": "It is a good Agile Practice to proactively seek inputs from different stakeholders ensuring transparency in project communications. [cite: 52] The wrong options do not promote direct communication or the promotion of trust. [cite: 53]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q5: There have been several incomplete stories at the end of an iteration. [cite: 54] Multiple Team Members worked on these stories and there were no blockers identified. [cite: 55] Which of the following options can the Agile Team use to resolve the situation? [cite: 56]", "options": ["A: Make use of the next Iteration to come out with a team spike that would help determine the feasibility of completing the planned user stories. [cite: 59]", "B: Place the stories in the blocked column and work with the Product Owner to remove the impediments. [cite: 60]", "C: Proceed with breaking down the stories further in the backlog by working with the Product Owner. [cite: 61]", "D: Insert the stories back into the product backlog and wait for a less intensive iteration to work on them. [cite: 63]"], "answer": "C: Proceed with breaking down the stories further in the backlog by working with the Product Owner. [cite: 61]", "explanation": "The chief reason behind not being able to complete a story within one iteration is that the story cannot be broken down into small enough goals. [cite: 64] The incorrect options don't address the root cause by waiting or placing them in the blocked column. [cite: 65] Also, reserving the full team for a Spike is inefficient and bypasses the normal backlog refinernent process. [cite: 67]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q6: You are in charge of an Agile Team that has shown impressive progress in the first four iterations. [cite: 68] However, in the fifth iteration the progress has slowed without any apparent reason. [cite: 69] What will you do as a next step? [cite: 70]", "options": ["A: Work with the team to find the root cause of the issue. [cite: 72]", "B: Remove the underperforming team member who is slowing things down. [cite: 76]", "C: No action is needed as the team has moved onto norming stage from storming, [cite: 77]", "D: No action is needed as the team happened to work low-complexity user stories in the first four iterations. [cite: 78]"], "answer": "A: Work with the team to find the root cause of the issue. [cite: 72]", "explanation": "The first logical step would be to find the root cause of the problem. [cite: 80] Also, if there happened to be a low performer, he/she would have had become apparent in earlier iterations. [cite: 81]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q7: Despite your Team's best efforts to address several blocked items on the Kanban Board, the items remain as is. [cite: 83] The Sprint Retrospective reveals that all the impediments can be traced back to a particular Department Head. [cite: 84] Tom, the Project Manager had tried to educate the Department Head previously, but the Head is still resistant. [cite: 85] Which of the following options should Tom do next? [cite: 86]", "options": ["A: Ask the Department Head for Budgetary Compensation that's proportional to the delays due to the lack of their cooperation. [cite: 89]", "B: Release an Information Radiator that ranks the Stakeholders according to their Active Support of the Project Goal. [cite: 90]", "C: Find other Stakeholders who can help work around the Department Head's barriers [cite: 91]", "D: Make use of a Stakeholder Analysis to identify an aligned Senior Stakeholder who could influence the Department Head. [cite: 92]"], "answer": "D: Make use of a Stakeholder Analysis to identify an aligned Senior Stakeholder who could influence the Department Head. [cite: 92]", "explanation": "In this scenario where stakeholders remain resistant despite the Project Manager's best efforts, escalation may be necessary. [cite: 93] Bypassing the stakeholder does not address the root cause. [cite: 94] Furthermore, public shaming by rank does not promote trust and cooperation. [cite: 95]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q8: Despite your Team's best efforts to address several blocked items on the Kanban Board, the Items remain as is. [cite: 96] The sprint retrospective reveals that all the impediments can be traced back to mandatory corporate business processes that introduce wait times. [cite: 97] Which of the following options should the Project Manager do next? [cite: 98]", "options": ["A: Increase the story point estimates for the stories in the product backlog to factor in the business process delays. [cite: 101]", "B: Work with the Process Owners to streamline procedures. Secure the team that is coaching on the processes. [cite: 102]", "C: Train the team on the business processes in the upcoming iteration. This would help them work more autonomously. [cite: 106]", "D: As a Servant Leader, resolve the pending issues while the team attends a team-building event. [cite: 107]"], "answer": "B: Work with the Process Owners to streamline procedures. Secure the team that is coaching on the processes. [cite: 102]", "explanation": "A Servant Leader should work within the organization to simplify processes affecting the team as much as possible. [cite: 108] Training is part of the solution, but not at the price of an iteration. [cite: 111] There should be a streamlining effort as well. [cite: 112]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q9: According to the annual report, your Products' prices are being driven down by your Competitors. [cite: 114] This is causing your company to lose market share. Also, midway into a product development project, it appears the sponsoring unit is unlikely to get a return on its investment. [cite: 115] Which of the following options should the Project Manager do to adapt to these new conditions? [cite: 116] (choose 2)", "options": ["A: Come out with a Cost-Benefit Analysis of Deliverables to help optimize speed and delivery cost. [cite: 122]", "B: Deliver the same feature as the competitors by re-scoping the project to match the pricing of the competitors. [cite: 123]", "C: Replace local staff by outside staff incrementally who can work at much less hourly rates. [cite: 124]", "D: Split out an agile track to incrementally maximize value within a fixed budget. [cite: 125]", "E: In order to help deliver the intended scope with less overhead costs, fast-track the remainder of the project. [cite: 126]"], "answer": ["A: Come out with a Cost-Benefit Analysis of Deliverables to help optimize speed and delivery cost. [cite: 122]", "D: Split out an agile track to incrementally maximize value within a fixed budget. [cite: 125]"], "explanation": "The answer option should help address the loss of profitability without disruption to the business. [cite: 127] Cost/Benefit Analysis and Fixed-Budget Incremental Development are the best options in this regard. [cite: 128]", "isMultipleChoice": true },
			{ "question": "M7Q10: An agile software project is security-classified. The project requires external expertise and delivery to add a module based on machine learning. [cite: 129] An approved supplier asks you to join the daily meeting with the supplier's Agile Team. [cite: 130] However, your day is filled with internal meetings. Which of the following options should be used for the two teams to synchronize interactively but less frequently? [cite: 131]", "options": ["A: Come out with a Common Electronic Kanban. [cite: 136]", "B: Have iterations aligned with Common Retrospectives. [cite: 137]", "C: Add a Scrum of Scrum Layer and execute it. [cite: 138]", "D: Come up with a fishbowl window for each site. [cite: 139]"], "answer": "C: Add a Scrum of Scrum Layer and execute it. [cite: 138]", "explanation": "The best option is Scrum of Scrums which allows both Teams to have their own Daily Meetings and have less frequent targeted meetings between them. [cite: 140] The incorrect options are inappropriate because of low pertinence & frequency (retrospectives), security reasons (fishbowl) or lack of live interaction (Kanban). [cite: 141]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q11: You are the Project Manager of XYZ firm. [cite: 142] Your firm's Marketing Director is unhappy that the Agile Innovation Team is developing too many novelty products with very little business value. [cite: 143] Which of the following actions should the Project Manager do to rectify the team's approach? (choose 2). [cite: 144]", "options": ["A: Increase the story sizes to incorporate more valuable features. [cite: 147]", "B: Survey end-users and rank the items in the Product Backlog according to the survey results (user value ranking). [cite: 148]", "C: Instruct the team to undertake a training course in direct response marketing. [cite: 151]", "D: Let the Marketing Director approve each story by adding a process. [cite: 152]", "E: Tighten the value criteria in the Definition of Ready by working with the Product Owners. [cite: 153]"], "answer": ["B: Survey end-users and rank the items in the Product Backlog according to the survey results (user value ranking). [cite: 148]", "E: Tighten the value criteria in the Definition of Ready by working with the Product Owners. [cite: 153]"], "explanation": "Out of all the options, Definition of Ready and User Value Ranking are the best options. [cite: 154] The incorrect options are wrong because marketing comes after value, coming out with large stories is a bad practice, and approval of all stories is not agile. [cite: 155]", "isMultipleChoice": true },
			{ "question": "M7Q12: You are the Head of Operations of a highly productive Agile Innovation Team. [cite: 156] You have informed the Product Owner that the company is not getting a solid Return on Investment from the Team's work. [cite: 157] How should the Product Owner address the problem? [cite: 158]", "options": ["A: Run a Retrospective with the Project Manager and go ahead with Project Cancellation. [cite: 159]", "B: Come out with Minimum Marketable Features and prioritize relevant backlog items. [cite: 162]", "C: Lessen the number of team members as necessary to guarantee a positive ROI. [cite: 164]", "D: Review the User Stories and prioritize relevant backlog items. [cite: 165]"], "answer": "B: Come out with Minimum Marketable Features and prioritize relevant backlog items. [cite: 162]", "explanation": "The fastest way to get a return on investment is the frequent release of smaller incremental products. [cite: 166] Minimum Marketable Features are ready for public launch and prioritizing them will help resolve the problem described in the question. [cite: 167]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q13: You are managing a virtual team. Your team came up with the below burn-down chart. [cite: 169] In the chart below, select the point where the project is behind schedule. [cite: 170]", "options": ["A: A [cite: 195]", "B: B [cite: 196]", "C: C [cite: 197]", "D: D [cite: 198]"], "answer": "B: B [cite: 196]", "explanation": "Clearly as per the diagram, the work remaining (Green Line) is more than the ideal work (Red Line) in option B. [cite: 201]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q14: You are part of an efficient, empowered Agile Innovation Team. [cite: 202] You and your team don't understand why the required approvals from the legal department are allowed to delay your team's progress. [cite: 203] You approach your Product Owner in this regard who replies that the approvals are needed to check for existing patents that can block the team's product from going to market. [cite: 204] Which of the following options reveal how such conflicts could be prevented? [cite: 205]", "options": ["A: Work with Senior Management to make sure the Product Owner explains to the team the rationale behind the requirement workflow. [cite: 210]", "B: Require the team to move a story to the Blocked Items in the Kanban Board based on their concerns about progress. [cite: 211, 212]", "C: Mandate that supporting department stakeholders are present in the daily progress to report progress from time to time. [cite: 213]", "D: Make sure that the Product Owner can easily be approached to help answer the team's concerns and queries. [cite: 214]"], "answer": "D: Make sure that the Product Owner can easily be approached to help answer the team's concerns and queries. [cite: 214]", "explanation": "Lack of Communication, as well as Inaction to prevent delay, is causing the conflict. [cite: 215] Ensuring constant communication between the team and Product Owner is the most comprehensive response. [cite: 216]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q15: Mary is in-charge of an Apparel Brand. There has been an increase of complaints on social networks about her brand's drop in quality. [cite: 218] Mary is determined to place product quality above all considerations and with this mission in mind, she helps set up a new Agile Innovation Team. [cite: 219] Which of the following methods would be most effective to help achieve the team's goals? [cite: 220]", "options": ["A: Eliminate human error by creating an automated testing bench. [cite: 225]", "B: Introduce User Focus group inputs in the development life cycle of the product. [cite: 226]", "C: Come up with features that help benchmark against competitor products. [cite: 227]", "D: Fund the use of better quality materials by raising the product price. [cite: 228]"], "answer": "B: Introduce User Focus group inputs in the development life cycle of the product. [cite: 226]", "explanation": "The most important aspect to determine the target is receiving continuous user input. [cite: 229] The incorrect options don't include user inputs as a valid means to address gaps. [cite: 230]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q16: You are the Project Manager of an Agile Development Team. [cite: 231] To remove a significant blocker your Team comes out with a workaround. [cite: 232] The Team's output dramatically increases over the next two iterations. [cite: 233] However, at the third iteration, the Product Owner strongly disagrees with the workaround and asks your team to come up with a better solution and redo the work. [cite: 234] Which of the following is the best solution to prevent such situations? [cite: 235]", "options": ["A: Regularly engage with the Product Owner and run Catch-up meetings when necessary. [cite: 239]", "B: Help the team focus by offloading all work on Improving Team Impediments. [cite: 240]", "C: Ask the Product Owner for additional funding for the re-work due to the lack of collaboration with your team. [cite: 241]", "D: Update the team charter with the revised ground rules and correct deviations as early as possible. [cite: 243]"], "answer": "A: Regularly engage with the Product Owner and run Catch-up meetings when necessary. [cite: 239]", "explanation": "The ultimate authority of product scope rests with the Product Owner. [cite: 244] Hence the Product Owner's engagement is critical when considering any scope changes. [cite: 245] Updating the team charter may help, but a better choice is to make sure the Product Owner is regularly engaged. [cite: 247]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q17: You are part of an Agile Team which is composed of highly skilled Product Design Engineers. [cite: 248] The Design Engineers have earned new duties based on their reputation for quality and speed. [cite: 249] However, in this role, the team's output has dropped steeply compared to their design work. [cite: 250] Which of the following measures are most effective to improve the team's productivity in the present scenario? (choose 2) [cite: 251]", "options": ["A: Come out with a Creativity Spike in the next iteration. [cite: 254]", "B: Increase the team's motivation with a team building event. [cite: 255]", "C: Get help from the creative thinkers on your team. [cite: 256]", "D: Recruit more T-shaped profiles into the team. [cite: 259]", "E: Extend the iterations to adjust for the new tasks. [cite: 260]"], "answer": ["A: Come out with a Creativity Spike in the next iteration. [cite: 254]", "D: Recruit more T-shaped profiles into the team. [cite: 259]"], "explanation": "Having diverse skills in play is the best option as Specialists keep getting thrown out of their comfort zones. [cite: 261] The incorrect options do not address the problem of specialization. [cite: 262]", "isMultipleChoice": true },
			{ "question": "M7Q18: Your company is transitioning from a waterfall/predictive model to a hybrid model and you are in charge of leading this effort. [cite: 263] Multiple projects will continue in predictive model, few will be following pure agile, and a few will be following hybrid methodology [cite: 264] Match each of the following terminologies/scenarios with the correct scenarios/definitions. [cite: 265]", "options": ["Requirements are predefined [cite: 266]", "Changes follow change control process [cite: 268, 269]", "Requirements are not necessarily pre-defined [cite: 270]", "Embrace change [cite: 273]"], "answer": { "Requirements are predefined [cite: 266]": "Scope in predictive. [cite: 267]", "Changes follow change control process [cite: 268, 269]": "Changes in predictive. [cite: 271]", "Requirements are not necessarily pre-defined [cite: 270]": "Scope in agile. [cite: 272]", "Embrace change [cite: 273]": "Changes in agile. [cite: 274]" }, "explanation": "The question is asking about how scope/changes are managed in predictive and agile projects. [cite: 275] Clearly scope is well defined in predictive, and in agile it is not necessary for requirements to be fixed. [cite: 276] On the same lines, agile methodology embrace changes and in predictive, it follows the integrated change control process. [cite: 277]", "isMatching": true },
			{ "question": "M7Q19: It's been almost 1 year since your organization transitioned to a hybrid model. [cite: 278] The Program Manager complains to you (the Project Manager) that your project is not doing well as compared to other projects in the PMO. [cite: 279] What can you do to improve the performance before the next couple of sprints? [cite: 280]", "options": ["A: Discuss with the Product Owner in the sprint review meeting. [cite: 281]", "B: Initiate the conversation in the daily stand up meeting. [cite: 283]", "C: Find out the root cause in the sprint retrospective session. [cite: 285]", "D: Use team building activities to motivate the team. [cite: 286]"], "answer": "C: Find out the root cause in the sprint retrospective session. [cite: 285]", "explanation": "Having diverse skills in play is the best option as Specialists keep getting thrown out of their comfort zones. [cite: 287] The incorrect options do not address the problem of specialization. [cite: 288]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q20: As an Agile Project Manager, you are ensuring that all User Stories are completed on schedule and all tests are passed. [cite: 289] However, the Customer does not consider the product a success. [cite: 290] Which of the following is the most effective way to prevent this outcome in the projects to follow? [cite: 291]", "options": ["A: Obtain customer feedback on incremental release demos and user tests. [cite: 292]", "B: Make sure that the test plan incorporates non-functional requirements in the backlog. [cite: 296]", "C: Before developing the Product Backlog, ensure that the product vision is approved by the customer. [cite: 297]", "D: Come up with an agreement with the customer on the success criteria of the product. [cite: 298]"], "answer": "A: Obtain customer feedback on incremental release demos and user tests. [cite: 292]", "explanation": "The best way to ensure that the product addresses identified and non-identified needs throughout the product development is by getting continuous and incremental feedback from the Customer. [cite: 299] The incorrect options are wrong because the product vision and success criteria do not address the non-expressed requirements. [cite: 300]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q21: Competitors with new Business Models are causing a Company to lose its market share. [cite: 302] To recommend ways to recover market share, a cross-functional Agile Team has been constituted. [cite: 303] Which of the following ways talk about how the Team can increase their chance of coming up with successful recommendations? [cite: 304]", "options": ["A: Understand and focus on the value consumers seek and the value competitors offer. [cite: 307]", "B: Come out with an understanding of how competitors' business models can reach more consumers at a lower cost. [cite: 308]", "C: Make sure a representative from the legal team is involved in these discussions. [cite: 311]", "D: Come up with a deeper understanding of why consumers are disappointed by the Company's Product. [cite: 312]"], "answer": "A: Understand and focus on the value consumers seek and the value competitors offer. [cite: 307]", "explanation": "As per the first principle of Agile Manifesto, the highest priority should be \"to satisfy the customer through early and continuous delivery of valuable software.\" [cite: 313] The value that consumers attribute to the offerings help drive the markets. [cite: 314]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q22: You are managing a hybrid project that is facing a product design issue. [cite: 316] The team collaboratively comes up with a solution but it would require significant change to product features. [cite: 317] Which of the following would you recommend your team to do before going further with developing the solution at hand? [cite: 318]", "options": ["A: Verify if the product vision is still valid. [cite: 319]", "B: Come out with a prototype and demo it to the end-user. [cite: 322]", "C: Execute a Cost/Benefit Analysis to determine its value. [cite: 323]", "D: Tell the Product Owner to review the change and provide recommendations. [cite: 325]"], "answer": "D: Tell the Product Owner to review the change and provide recommendations. [cite: 325]", "explanation": "This is a classic example where change affects the basic product characteristics. [cite: 326] In collaboration with stakeholders, the Product Owner is responsible for shaping the product. [cite: 328]" },
			{ "question": "M7Q23: Carefully examine the following steps below: [cite: 329]\n1. ABC project has been successfully delivered. [cite: 330]", "options": ["A: You should ask for permission to formally close the project from the Project Sponsor [cite: 332]", "B: Get the formal acceptance of deliverables from the stakeholders. [cite: 333]", "C: Now you should work towards releasing the project team. [cite: 335]", "D: Now you should work towards completing the final project report. [cite: 337]"], "answer": "B: Get the formal acceptance of deliverables from the stakeholders. [cite: 333]", "explanation": "The logical next step after the delivery of a successful project is getting the formal acceptance of deliverables from the stakeholders. [cite: 338] This is the most appropriate option out of the given four options. [cite: 339]" }
];

export const pmpExam: Quiz = {
  id: 'pmp-exam-1',
  title: 'PMP® Practice Exam 1',
  description: '60 questions to test your project management knowledge.',
  questions: processQuestions(mock1Data),
  isImportant: true,
};

export const pmpExam2: Quiz = {
  id: 'pmp-exam-2',
  title: 'PMP® Practice Exam 2',
  description: '60 questions on core PMP concepts and agile practices.',
  questions: processQuestions(mock2Data),
};

export const pmpExam3: Quiz = {
  id: 'pmp-exam-3',
  title: 'PMP® Practice Exam 3',
  description: '60 scenario-based questions to sharpen your decision-making.',
  questions: processQuestions(mock3Data),
};

export const pmpExam4: Quiz = {
  id: 'pmp-exam-4',
  title: 'PMP® Practice Exam 4',
  description: '60 questions to test your agile and hybrid project management knowledge.',
  questions: processQuestions(mock4Data)
};

export const pmpExam5: Quiz = {
  id: 'pmp-exam-5',
  title: 'PMP® Practice Exam 5',
  description: '60 questions to test your project management knowledge.',
  questions: processQuestions(mock5Data)
};

export const pmpExam6: Quiz = {
  id: 'pmp-exam-6',
  title: 'PMP® Practice Exam 6',
  description: '60 questions to test your agile and hybrid project management knowledge.',
  questions: processQuestions(mock6Data)
};

export const pmpExam7: Quiz = {
  id: 'pmp-exam-7',
  title: 'PMP® Agile Focused Exam',
  description: '23 questions focused on agile practices and principles.',
  questions: processQuestions(pmpData)
};

export const mockExams: Quiz[] = [
  pmpExam,
  pmpExam2,
  pmpExam3,
  pmpExam4,
  pmpExam5,
  pmpExam6,
  pmpExam7,
];
